Transcript and translation
from Dream Heroes http://youtu.be/XWa3_S-i-3Y
Sung by Taryn Szpilman
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
A neve branca brilhando no chão
The white snow shining on the ground
not a footprint to be seen
Sem pegadas pra seguir
There's no footprint to follow
A kingdom of isolation,
Um reino de isolamento
A kingdom of isolation
and it looks like I'm the queen
E a Rainha está aqui
And the Queen is here
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
A tempestade vem chegando e já não sei
The storm is coming and I don't know anymore
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Não consegui contar, bem que eu tentei
I couldn't contain it, as much as I tried
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Não podem vir, não podem ver
They cannot come, they cannot see
Be the good girl you always had to be
Sempre a boa menina deve ser
Always the good girl, you must be
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Encobrir, não sentir, nunca saberão
Cover up, do not feel, they will never know
Well, now they know!
Mas agora vão!
But now they will!
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free, I am free!
Can't hold it back any more!
Não posso mais segurar
Can't hold it back any more
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free! I am free!
Turn away and slam the door!
Eu saí pra não voltar
I left not to go back
I don't care what they're going to say
Não me importa o que vão falar
What they're going to say doesn't matter to me
Let the storm rage on
Tempestade vem
Come the storm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio não vai mesmo me incomodar.
The cold won't bother me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
De longe tudo muda,
From far everything changes,
Makes everything seem small
parace ser bem menor
it seems to be much smaller
And the fears that once controlled me
Os medos que me controlavam,
I do not see around me
Can't get to me at all!
não vejo ao meu redor
the fears that controlled me
It's time to see what I can do
É hora de experimentar
It's time to experiment
To test the limits and break through
Os meus limites vou testar
My limits I will test
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
A liberdade veio enfim
Freedom has come at last
I'm free!
Pra mim
For me
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free, I am free!
I am one with the wind and sky
Com o céu e o vento andar
To walk with the sky and the wind
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free, I am free!
You'll never see me cry
Não vão me ver chorar
They won't see me cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Aqui estou eu, e vou ficar
Here am I, and I will stay
Let the storm rage on...
Tempestade vem...
Come the storm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
O meu poder envolve o ar e vai ao chão
My power envelops the air and goes to the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Da minha alma fluem fractais de gelo em profusão
Ice fractals flow in profusion from my soul
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Um pensamento se transforma em cristais
A thought turns into crystals
I'm never going back
Não vou me arrepender...
I will not regret...
The past is in the past!
... do que ficou pra trás!
... what has been left behind!
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free, I am free!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Como o sol vou me levantar
Like the sun, I will rise
Let it go, let it go!
Livre estou, livre estou!
I am free, I am free!
That perfect girl is gone
É tempo de mudar
It's time to change
Here I stand in the light of day
Aqui estou eu, vendo a luz brilhar
Here am I, seeing the light shine
Let the storm rage on!
Tempestade vem!
Come the storm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio não vai mesmo me incomodar.
The cold won't bother me anyway.