Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/hXdUECDWKmA
Sung by Nadezhda Panayotova
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Блести цнега, озарява ношта,
Blesti cnega, ozarâva nošta,
The snow shines, brightening the night,
not a footprint to be seen
недокоснат от света.
nedokosnat ot sveta.
untouched by the world.
A kingdom of isolation,
В самотно и бяло кралство,
V samotno i bâlo kralstvo,
In lonely and white kingdom,
and it looks like I'm the queen
аз кралица сьм сега.
az kralica s’m sega.
I am queen now.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Приглася вятърът на моята душа.
Priglasâ vât’r’t na moâta duša.
The wind chime of my soul.
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Бурята е в мен. Не мога да я спра.
Burâta e v men. Ne moga da â spra.
The storm is inside me. I can't stop it.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Бомеи сега, бьди добра.
Bomei sega, b’di dobra.
Remember now, be good.
Be the good girl you always had to be
Всичко друго остава след това
Vsičko drugo ostava sled tova
Everything else remains thereafter.
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
На чувствата не ставай роб
Na čuvstvata ne stavaj rob
Don't become a slave to your feelings
Well, now they know!
И знам защо!
I znam zaŝo!
And I know why!
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
Can't hold it back any more!
Не мога да продъжа.
Ne moga da prod″ža.
I can't go on like that.
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
Turn away and slam the door!
И затварям тази врата.
I zatvarâm tazi vrata.
And I'm closing that door.
I don't care what they're going to say
Късно е. Няма как да спра.
K″sno e. Nâma kak da spra.
It's too late. I can't stop.
Let the storm rage on
Викам бурята
Vikam burâta
I call the storm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Владея студа и не се боя.
Vladeâ studa i ne se boâ.
I wield the cold and I'm not afraid.
It's funny how some distance
Отгоре вече виждам
Otgore veče viždam
I can see from up here
Makes everything seem small
възможности безброй
v″zmožnosti bezbroj
countless possibilities.
And the fears that once controlled me
А страхът не ме погубва
A strah″t ne me pogubva
But the fear is not destroying me.
Can't get to me at all!
Знам, изборът е мой!
Znam, izbor″t e moj!
I know the choice is mine!
It's time to see what I can do
Приключвам миналото тук.
Priklûčvam minaloto tuk.
I quit with the past right here.
To test the limits and break through
Със нова сила, с мощен дух.
S″s nova sila, s moŝen duh.
With new strength, with mighty spirit.
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
За тази волна свобода
Za tazi volna svoboda
For this freedom...
I'm free!
мечтах!
mečtah!
I've dreamed!
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
I am one with the wind and sky
Към небето сега летя.
K″m nebeto sega letâ.
I'm flying towards the sky now.
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
You'll never see me cry
В очите без сълза
V očite bez s″lza
Without a tear in my eyes.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Тук стоя, не ще се слра.
Tuk stoâ, ne ŝe se slra.
Here I stand, I won't stop.
Let the storm rage on...
Викам бурята...
Vikam burâta...
I call the storm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Мощта ми с въздуха лети и няма край.
Moŝta mi s v″zduha leti i nâma kraj.
My might flies with the air and has no end.
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Душата ми се влива в лъскавия, леден рай.
Dušata mi se vliva v l″skaviâ, leden raj.
My soul is infused within the shiny, icy paradise.
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Кристална мисъл в миг пронизва моя ден
Kristalna mis″l v mig pronizva moâ den
Crystal thought in a moment pierces my day
I'm never going back
Ще спра да бъда аз
Ŝe spra da b″da az
I'll stop being...
The past is in the past!
на миналото в плен!
na minaloto v plen!
... a captive of the past!
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ново утро изгрява в мен.
Novo utro izgrâva v men.
New dawn rises in me.
Let it go, let it go!
Слагам край, слагам край!
Slagam kraj, slagam kraj!
I'm putting an end to it, I'm putting an end to it!
That perfect girl is gone
И чувствам се добре.
I čuvstvam se dobre.
And I feel good.
Here I stand in the light of day
Тук стоя, няма как да спра!
Tuk stoâ, nâma kak da spra!
Here I stand, there's no way to stop!
Let the storm rage on!
Викам бурята!
Vikam burâta!
I call the storm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Владея студа и не се боя.
Vladeâ studa i ne se boâ.
I wield the cold and I'm not afraid.