Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/_V1f1gpHSnI
Sung by Gisela
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
La nieve brilla esta noche aquí,
The snow is shining tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
mas ni una huella queda allá;
but not a footprint remains there;
A kingdom of isolation,
Soy la reina en un reino
I am the queen in a kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
de aislamiento y soledad
of isolation and loneliness
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
El viento aulla y se cuela en mi interior;
The wind is howling and is passing inside of me;
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
¡Lo quisé contener, pero se escapó!
I wanted to hold, but it escaped!
Don't let them in, don't let them see
No dejes que sepan de tí;
Don't let them know about you;
Be the good girl you always had to be
"Que no entren" siempre mi dijo a mí;
"Do not enter" I always said to me;
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
No has de sentir, no han de saber
You don't have to feel, they don't have to know
Well, now they know!
¡Ya que más da!
Who cares now!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
Can't hold it back any more!
¡No lo puedo ya retener!
I can't hold it back now!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
Turn away and slam the door!
Que no hay nada que perder!
There is nothing to lose!
I don't care what they're going to say
¿Qué más da? ¡Ya se descubrió!
Who cares now? It has been discovered now!
Let the storm rage on
¡Déjalo escapar!
Let it escape!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
¡El frío a mí nunca me molestó!
The cold never bothered me!
It's funny how some distance
Desde la distancia
From the distance
Makes everything seem small
que pequeño todo es;
how small everything is;
And the fears that once controlled me
El temor que me aferraba
The fear that gripped me
Can't get to me at all!
no me va a hacer volver!
is not going to make me return!
It's time to see what I can do
¡Soy libre y ahora ententaré
I am free and in this moment
To test the limits and break through
sobrepasar los límites!
I will try to exceed the limits!
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Ya no hay más reglas para mí...
Now there are no rules for me...
I'm free!
¡Por fin!
Finally!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
I am one with the wind and sky
¡Que el frío reine ya!
The cold is reigning now!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
You'll never see me cry
¡No volveré a llorar!
I am not going to cry!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
¡Aquí estoy y aquí estaré!
Here I am and I will be here!
Let the storm rage on...
Déjalo escapar...
Let it escape...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
En las entrañas de la tierra puedo entrar;
I can enter into the bowels of the ground;
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mi alma crece y hace espirales sin parar;
My soul is growing up and making spirals endlessly;
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Y un pensamiento en mí surgió y cristalizó:
And one thought appeared inside of me and crystallized:
I'm never going back
¡Ya no regresaré,
I will not come back,
The past is in the past!
el pasado ya pasó!
the past has passed now!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
¡Subiré con el amanecer!
I will rise with the dawn!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Suéltalo! ¡Suéltalo!
Let it go! Let it go!
That perfect girl is gone
¡La farsa se acabó!
The farce is finished!
Here I stand in the light of day
¡Que la luz salga otra vez!
That light comes again!
Let the storm rage on!
¡Déjalo escapar!
Let it escape!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
El frío a mí nunca me molestó.
The cold never bothered me.