Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/-ZjGTpmrdR-I
Sung by Gisela
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
La neu de nit té un to més bonic
The snow at night has more beautiful tone
not a footprint to be seen
no hi ha traces, tot és blanc
there are no traces, all is white
A kingdom of isolation,
d'un regne aïllat del món
from a kingdom isolated from the world
and it looks like I'm the queen
en sóc reina en aquest instant
I am the queen at this time
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
El vent fereix la nit per dins la tempestat
The wind wounds the night, inside the tempest
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
He acabat fugint tot i que he lluitat.
I ended up running away, although I have fought.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
No els vulla dins, no els vull aquí
I don't want them inside, I don't want them here
Be the good girl you always had to be
"Porta't molt bé" sempre em deia a mi
"Behave very well" he always said to me
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Desat no ho pot saber ningú
Hidden, no one can know
Well, now they know!
Ja ho sap algú!
Now someone knows!
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
Can't hold it back any more!
Ni puc ni el vull amagar
Neither can I, nor do I, want to hide it
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
Turn away and slam the door!
Ja tant és, ja tant me fa!
Now it doesn't matter, now I don't care!
I don't care what they're going to say
És igual el que puguin dir
It doesn't matter what they could say
Let the storm rage on
Deixa el vent cridar
Let the wind cry
The cold never bothered me anyway.
El fred no m'ha fet mai cap mal a mi.
The cold has never hurt me.
It's funny how some distance
És curiós com la distància
It's curious how the distance
Makes everything seem small
ho fa tot molt petit
makes everything very small
And the fears that once controlled me
i les pors que em dominaven
and the fears that dominated me
Can't get to me at all!
per sempre han fugit!
are gone forever!
It's time to see what I can do
Ara veuré el que puc fer
Now I will see what I can do
To test the limits and break through
Quins límits jo superaré
what limits I will reach
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Ni el bé ni el mal no són per mi
Neither good nor bad, they're not for me
I'm free!
Per fi!
At last!
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
I am one with the wind and sky
Sóc part de la neu i el vent
I'm part of the snow and wind
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
You'll never see me cry
Ja he fet fora aquest torment
I've taken out this torment
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Sóc aquí, i no em mouran
I'm here, and they won't move me
Let the storm rage on...
Deixa el vent cridar...
Let the wind cry...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Tinc un poder que va dels cims fins els averns
I have a power which goes from the summits to the underworld
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
De la meva ànima en surten gels que ni en comprenc
Ice leaves my soul, that I don't even understand
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
I un pensament sorgeix com un gran dard gelat
And a thought emerges like a great ice dart
I'm never going back
No penso tornar mai
The past is in the past!
això ja és el passat!
That's already the past!
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
I com l'alba jo creixeré
And I'll rise up like the break of dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Vol volar, el deixo anar!
It wants to fly, I let it go!
That perfect girl is gone
Ja no em portaré bé
I won't behave well any more
Here I stand in the light of day
Sóc aquí, s'alça un nou matí
Here I am, a new morning is rising up
Let the storm rage on!
Deixa el vent cridar!
Let the wind cry!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
El fred no m'ha fet mai cap mal a mi.
The cold has never hurt me.