Transcript and translation
from Aria Sky http://youtu.be/I0DrWFblrhs
Sung by Hu Wei Na (胡维纳)
Note: Needs a transcription - currently, the
transliteration is all I have.
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
bái xuě fā liàng jīn yè pū mǎn shān shàng
The glowing snow covers the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
méi yǒu jiǎo yìn de dì fāng
there are no footprints in this place
A kingdom of isolation,
gū lì de wāng guó hěn huāng liáng
This lone kingdom is so desolate
and it looks like I'm the queen
wǒ shì zhè lǐ de nǚ huáng
I'm the queen in this place
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
fēng zài hū xiào xiàng xīn lǐ de fēng bào yī yàng
The wind is howling like the storm inside of me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
zhǐ yǒu tiān zhī dào wǒ shòu guò de shāng
Only heaven knows what I've been through
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Bié ràng tā men jìn lái kàn jiàn
Be the good girl you always had to be
zuò hǎo nǚ hái jiù xiàng nǐ de cóng qián﻿
Be the good girl as you did before
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
duǒ cáng bū ràng tā mén kàn jiàn
Hide and don't let them see
Well, now they know!
yǐ beì fā xiàn
But now they know!
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Can't hold it back any more!
huí tóu yǐ méi yǒu bàn fǎ
Now there's no way back
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Turn away and slam the door!
yī zhuǎn shēn bū zài qiān guà
Turn back and don't worry any more!
I don't care what they're going to say
wǒ bū guǎn tā mén xiǎng shuō de huà
I don't care about what they have to say
Let the storm rage on
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
Let the wind howl and rain fall
The cold never bothered me anyway.
fǎn zhèng bing tiān xuě dì wǒ yě bū pà
I don't fear the ice and snow anyway.
It's funny how some distance
zhè yī diǎn diǎn de jǜ lí
This very little distance
Makes everything seem small
ràng yī qiè biàn jīn zhì
Makes everything so fine
And the fears that once controlled me
céng jing kùn ráo wǒ de kǒng jǚ
The fear that once bothered me
Can't get to me at all!
huì yuǎn lí wǒ huí yì
Will go away from my memory
It's time to see what I can do
xiàn zài kāi shǐ ràng wǒ kàn jiàn
Starting now, what makes me see
To test the limits and break through
shì wǒ de tū pò hé jǐ xiàn
are my break through and limits
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
bū fen duì cuò méi yǒu jǐ xiàn
No right, no wrong, without limits
I'm free!
xiàng qián
I'm going on
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
I am one with the wind and sky
gēn fēng hé tiān kōng duì huà
Speak out with the wind and the sky
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
You'll never see me cry
yǎn lèi bū zài diào xià
My tears won't ever drop
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
zhè ge jiā ràng wǒ liú xià
This is the home which let me stay
Let the storm rage on...
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
Let the wind howl, and the rain fall...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
wǒ lì liàng chón kōng qì zhōng kuò sàn dào dì shàng
My power spreads from the air into the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
wǒ líng hún pán xuán zài bing kuài gè zhǒng bū tóng xíng zhuàng
My soul is spiraling as ice in different shapes and forms
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
wǒ sī xiǎng jié jīng biàn chéng fēng lì de shǎn guāng
My thought crystallizes into sharp flashes
I'm never going back
wǒ yǒng bū huí tóu kàn
I will never look back
The past is in the past!
yǐ wǎng huì beì mái zàng
I'll bury all the past!
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
ràng wǒ zài shǔ guāng zhōng shēng huá
Let me rise at the break of dawn
Let it go, let it go!
suí tā ba suí tā ba
That perfect girl is gone
ràng wán měi beì zhēng fā
Let the perfection evaporate
Here I stand in the light of day
zhè gè jiā zài yáng guāng zhī xià
This home under the beams of the sun
Let the storm rage on!
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
The cold never bothered me anyway.
fǎn zhèng bing tiān xuě dì wǒ yě bū pà
I don't fear the ice and snow anyway.