Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/hPFfKWOINgY
Sung by Nataša Mirković
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Tu svud je snijeg i sav bijeli je brijeg
There is snow everywhere and the whole mountain is white
not a footprint to be seen
Samo moj je vidljiv trag
Only my [foot]print is visible
A kingdom of isolation,
Tih, osamljen, hladan prostor
Quiet, lonely, cold space
and it looks like I'm the queen
nikome baš nije drag
nobody likes
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
A vjetar vije ko u meni mećava
The wind is howling like the blizzard inside me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Obuzdati je ne znam ja
I don't know how to keep it in
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Ne vjeruj im, sve taji ti
Don't trust them, hide everything
Be the good girl you always had to be
Radi to što od tebe traže svi
Do whatever they want from you
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Ne osjećaj, ne otkrivaj
Don't feel, don't reveal
Well, now they know!
Tom sad je kraj!
Now it's the end!
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
Can't hold it back any more!
jer sad je već krajnji čas
It's high time already
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
Turn away and slam the door!
Nek se čuje i moj glas!
Let them hear my voice!
I don't care what they're going to say
Nevažni su zli jezici
Evil people aren't important any more
Let the storm rage on
Nek se bijeli sve
Let's make everything white
The cold never bothered me anyway.
jer snijeg meni nikad ne dosadi.
because I never get bored of the snow.
It's funny how some distance
Čim gledaš izdaleka
When you watch from a distance
Makes everything seem small
već su brige manje tad
every worry is less then
And the fears that once controlled me
I sav strah što me je stez'o
And all the fear that gripped me
Can't get to me at all!
više ne dira me sad!
doesn't touch me any more!
It's time to see what I can do
A saznat ću još ovu noć
And I'll find out this night
To test the limits and break through
do kuda seže moja moć
where my power goes on
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Bez zabrana jer slobodna...
Without limits because...
I'm free!
... sam ja!
... I'm free!
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
I am one with the wind and sky
i postajem vjetra dah
and I become the breath of the wind
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
You'll never see me cry
jer napušta me strah
because all the fear is leaving me
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Došla sam da ostanem
I'm here to stay
Let the storm rage on...
Nek se bijeli sve...
Let's make everything white...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Tu moja moć je našla put kroz leden zrak
Here my power found its way through the icy air
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
I lako podiže se snježni dvorac na moj znak
And the snow castle easily rises on my mark
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
A zakletva se rađa sad u srcu mom
And the oath is now born in my heart
I'm never going back
da neću vratit se
I'm not going back
The past is in the past!
jer ovo je moj dom!
because this is my home!
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
ko da lebdim već iznad tla
like I'm already above the ground
Let it go, let it go!
Puštam sve, puštam sve!
Letting all go, letting all go!
That perfect girl is gone
jer svoja sad sam ja
because now I'm myself again
Here I stand in the light of day
Sviće dan, svud su snjegovi
Day dawns, there is snow everywhere
Let the storm rage on!
Nek se bijeli sve!
Let's make everything white!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Snijeg meni nikad ne dosadi.
I never get bored of the snow.