Transcript and translation
from MarkiyC http://youtu.be/YjvNFzyRzO4
Sung by Monika Absolonová
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Na vrcholchích v noci panuje sníh,
The snow rules on the hilltops at night,
not a footprint to be seen
ani stopa po lidech
A kingdom of isolation,
Ta samota království vňmž,
The loneliness of the kingdom in which
and it looks like I'm the queen
královnou jsem vloček všech
I am the queen of all the snowflakes
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Už kvílí vítr a hřmí bouře v srdci mém
The wind is howling and the storm is thundering in my heart
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Zlobu vyšeptám v tichu mrazivém
I'll whisper out my anger in the chilling silence
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Já byla v zámku vězněná
I was trapped in a castle
Be the good girl you always had to be
skrývej city, bud' skříňka zamčená
hide your feelings, be a locked box
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
To táta chtěl, ty dny pryč jsou
That's what my dad wanted, those days are gone
Well, now they know!
Svět zná tvář mou!
The world knows my face!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
Can't hold it back any more!
chci skončit s tou hloupou hrou
I want to end the stupid game
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
Turn away and slam the door!
dveřmi prásknu za sebou
I'll slam the door behind myself
I don't care what they're going to say
Já jsem svá, to chci dokázat všem
I'm myself, I want to prove that to everyone
Let the storm rage on
V bouři rozkvétám
I'm blooming in the storm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
A mráz v duši víězí nad sluncem.
And the cold in my soul wins over the sun.
It's funny how some distance
Je zvláštní jak z té dálky,
It's funny how from the distance,
Makes everything seem small
se všechno menší zdá
everything seems smaller
And the fears that once controlled me
I ten strach co ve mně vládnul
Even the fear that once controlled me
Can't get to me at all!
je loutka bezmocná!
is a helpless puppet!
It's time to see what I can do
Jen vyzkouším, jak mocná jsem
I'll just try how powerful I am
To test the limits and break through
A k výšinám mě zvedne zem
And the ground will raise me to heights
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
V své říši bez konce chci žít
I want to live forever in my kingdom
I'm free!
klid mít!
in peace!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
I am one with the wind and sky
volná jsem, kráčím oblohou
I am free, I'm walking through the sky
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
You'll never see me cry
mé slzy šperkem jsou
my tears are my jewelry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Já jsem svá, jsem hráč i rváč
I'm myself, I'm both the player and the fighter
Let the storm rage on...
V bouři rozkvétám...
I'm blooming in the storm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Moc má se vzduchem vznáší v proudu neznámém
My power is floating through the air in an unknown flow
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A chladná duše září v krystalcích jak diadém
And the cold soul is shining in the crystals like a tiara
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Mé myšlenky se tříští, jedna smysl má
My thoughts are fragmented, only one makes sense
I'm never going back
Je pasé minulost,
The past is passé,
The past is in the past!
když svítat začíná!
when it begins to dawn!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
úsvit dává mi sílu svou
the dawn is giving me its power
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
That perfect girl is gone
už nejsem dívenkou
I'm not a little girl any more
Here I stand in the light of day
Já jsem svá, křídla má hlas můj
I'm myself, my voice has wings
Let the storm rage on!
V bouři rozkvétám!
I'm blooming in the storm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Chci žít zimě bez konce život svůj.
I want to live my life in the endless winter.