Transcript and translation
from Mie Michella http://youtu.be/xThb7kbjVIE
Sung by Maria Lucia Heiberg Rosenberg
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Den glitrende sne dækker bjerget i nat,
The sparkling snow covers the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
ingen fodspor viser vej
no footprints show the way
A kingdom of isolation,
Et helt isoleret rige,
An entirely isolated kingdom,
and it looks like I'm the queen
og dets dronning, det er mig
and its Queen, that's me
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Og vindens tuden spejler stormen indeni
And the cry of the wind reflects the storm inside
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Jag har mistet alt til en ond magi
I have lost everything to an evil magic
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Luk ingen ind, lad ingen se
Let nobody in, let nobody see
Be the good girl you always had to be
Hold facaden, det' du forpligtet til
Keep up the facade, that's what you're obligated to do
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Luk af hver dag, lig låget på
Shut off every day, put on the lid
Well, now they know!
Nu skal de få!
I'll show them now!
Let it go, let it go!
Lad det ske, lad dem se!
Let it happen, let them see!
Can't hold it back any more!
Jeg viser mig som jeg er
I show myself as I am
Let it go, let it go!
Lad det ske, lad dem se!
Let it happen, let them see!
Turn away and slam the door!
Jeg vil aldrig gemme mig mere
I will never hide any more
I don't care what they're going to say
Aldrig mere vil jeg lytte til dem
Never again will I listen to them
Let the storm rage on
Ja, det stormer, men -
Yes, it's storming, but -
The cold never bothered me anyway.
det iskolde fjeld er mit sande hjem.
the ice cold mountain is my true home.
It's funny how some distance
Når man er lid på afstand,
When you have some distance,
Makes everything seem small
bli'r alle ting så små
everything gets so small
And the fears that once controlled me
Og mit liv i frygtens lænker
And my life in the chains of fear
Can't get to me at all!
er slut, må de forstå
is over, must they understand
It's time to see what I can do
Det bli'r mit store gennembrud
It'll be my big breakthrough
To test the limits and break through
Nu gi'r jeg los, går linen ud
I'll give everything I have now, walk out the line
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Farvel til pligtens tyrrani
Goodby to duty's tyranny
I'm free!
jeg' fri!
Let it go, let it go!
Lad det ske, lad dem se!
Let it happen, let them see!
I am one with the wind and sky
De kræfter som jeg har fået
Those powers that I have been giving
Let it go, let it go!
Lad det ske, det' forbi!
Let it happen, it's over!
You'll never see me cry
Med skam og bitter gråd
With shame and bitter crying
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Når jeg bli'r til den jeg er
When I become the one I am
Let the storm rage on...
bryder stormen løs
the storm will break loose
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Jeg ryster jord og himmel let som ingenting
I shake the ground and sky as easily as nothing
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Isblomster springer ud og samles i en sluttet ring
Ice flowers bloom and assemble in a connected circle
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Og som krystaller står en tanke ganske klar
And just like crystals, a thought appears so clear
I'm never going back
Kan aldrig vende hjem,
Can never return back home,
The past is in the past!
farvel til det der var!
goodbye to all that was!
Let it go, let it go!
Lad det ske, lad dem se!
Let it happen, let them see!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Nu er handskerne taget af
Now the gloves have been taken off
Let it go, let it go!
Is og sne vil I see
Ice and snow you will see
That perfect girl is gone
Jeg er klar til en helt ny dag
I'm ready for a whole new day
Here I stand in the light of day
Og med ét bryder lyset frem
And suddenly the light breaks out
Let the storm rage on!
Vinterstorm, kom an!
Winterstorm, bring it!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Det iskolde fjeld er mit sande hjem.
The ice cold mountain is my true home.