Transcript and translation
from ShizukaKuroi http://youtu.be/oQPiGqzZRGA
Sung by Willemijn Verkaik
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
De sneeuw glanst zacht in het maanlicht vannacht,
The snow glows softly in the moonlight tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
van een voetstap geen blijk
no sign of any footprints
A kingdom of isolation,
Dit lege verlaten land is
This empty abandoned land will
and it looks like I'm the queen
vanaf nu mijn koninkrijk
from now on be my kingdom
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Van de storm die in mij woedt had tot nu toe niemand weet
Until now no one knew about the storm inside of me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Het werd mij te veel, hoe 'k mijn best ook deed
It became too much for me, no matter how hard I tried
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Laat niemand toe, spreek niemand aan
Don't let anyone in, don't talk to anyone
Be the good girl you always had to be
Wees gehoorzaam en ga hier niet vandaan
Be obedient and don't leave this place
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Voel niets, doe niets, dat iets verradt
Feel nothing, do nothing, that could reveal something
Well, now they know!
Da's nu te laat!
That's too late now!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
Can't hold it back any more!
Het roer moet om, ja dat moet!
It has to change, yes it must!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
Turn away and slam the door!
Sluit de deuren nu voorgoed!
Now close the doors permanently!
I don't care what they're going to say
Wat men daar over mij beweert
What people back there state about me
Let the storm rage on
raakt mij hier niet meer
won't reach me here any more
The cold never bothered me anyway.
En kou heeft me sowieso nooit gedeerd.
And cold never harmed me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
't Is grappig dat wat afstand
It's funny that some distance
Makes everything seem small
Zo snel meer inzicht gaf
So quickly gave me a better understanding
And the fears that once controlled me
Want de vrees die mij steeds voortjoeg
Because the fear that kept chasing me
Can't get to me at all!
Glijdt nu al van mij af!
Is already sliding off me!
It's time to see what I can do
Ik ga opzoek naar wie ik ben
I'm going to search for who I am
To test the limits and break through
Verleg de grenzen die ik ken
Pushing the boundaries that I know
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Geen goed of fout geldt hier voor mij
No right or wrong applies to me here
I'm free!
'k Ben vrij!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
I am one with the wind and sky
Voorbij is de storm in mij
The storm inside me is over
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
You'll never see me cry
Geen tranen meer, vorbij
No more tears, it's over
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Hier begint mijn nieuw bestaan
Here begins my new existence
Let the storm rage on...
Onbevreesd en vrij...
Fearless and free...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
M'n kracht neemt toe en schept een zuilenrij van steen
My powers are increasing and create a colonnade made of stone
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
M'n ziel bouwt een kasteel van ijskristallen om me heen
My soul is building a castle made of ice crystals all around me
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
In elk kristal weerklinkt de echo van mijn geest
In each crystal resounds the echo of my mind
I'm never going back
'k Ga nooit, nee noit terug,
I'm never, no never going back,
The past is in the past!
't verleden is geweest!
the past has passed!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ja, ik rijs uit de kilte op
Yes, I'll rise out of the coldness
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het gaan!
That perfect girl is gone
Op deze hoge top
On top of this high peak
Here I stand in the light of day
Hier begint nu m'n leven weer
Here my life begins again
Let the storm rage on!
Vrij en onbevreesd!
Free and fearless!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
De kou is voor mij nooit een punt geweest.
The cold has never been an issue for me.