Transcript and translation
from
Sung by Idina Menzel
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
A kingdom of isolation,
and it looks like I'm the queen
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Be the good girl you always had to be
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Well, now they know!
Let it go, let it go!
Can't hold it back any more!
Turn away and slam the door!
I don't care what they're going to say
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
Makes everything seem small
And the fears that once controlled me
Can't get to me at all!
It's time to see what I can do
To test the limits and break through
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
I'm free!
Let it go, let it go!
I am one with the wind and sky
You'll never see me cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Let the storm rage on...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
I'm never going back
The past is in the past!
Let it go, let it go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
That perfect girl is gone
Here I stand in the light of day
Let the storm rage on!
The cold never bothered me anyway.