Transcript and translation
from FireAngel http://youtu.be/ccA_zLkFrqY
Sung by Hanna-Liina Võsa
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
On öine tund, sajab valget lund,
It's late night, white snow is falling
not a footprint to be seen
pole jalajälgegi.
There's not even one footstep
A kingdom of isolation,
Ei kedagi lumeriigis,
No one in the kingdom of snow
and it looks like I'm the queen
kuninganna olen siin.
Here I am, the queen
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Ka tuul ei jääta mind, vaid ihus ringi käib
The wind will not freeze me, it just howls in my body
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Külma salajõud minust jagu sai.
The mysterious force of cold defeated me.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Sind nende jaoks ei ole siin,
For them you are not here,
Be the good girl you always had to be
hoia meeles hea tüdruk käitub nii!
Remember, good girl behaves like this!
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Ja peida end see on hei nõu,
And hide yourself, that's good advice
Well, now they know!
teada mu jõud!
Now they know my powers!
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! Olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
Can't hold it back any more!
Mind haaranud tormituul
The storm wind has taken over me
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! Olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
Turn away and slam the door!
Mingu kõik kui läinud ma!
I'm gone and I care about nothing!
I don't care what they're going to say
Mul ükskõik, mida arvad sa!
I don't care what you will think!
Let the storm rage on
Ja kui see on torm,
And if this is the storm,
The cold never bothered me anyway.
siis just selles tahangi elada!
then that's right where I want to live!
It's funny how some distance
Aeg vahel vempe viskab,
Time sometimes plays tricks,
Makes everything seem small
jääb varju minust pool
Half of me stays hidden
And the fears that once controlled me
Ja ei hirm mind enam suuna,
And the fear will not control me any more
Can't get to me at all!
see saanud ajalooks!
That's now history!
It's time to see what I can do
Nüüd teada saan, mis jõud on see.
I will find out about this power.
To test the limits and break through
Ma katsun, piire murran veel
I'll test it out, break the limits
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Ei halb, ei hea, sest olen nüüd...
No wrong, no right, because now...
I'm free!
... ma prii!
... I'm free!
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! Olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
I am one with the wind and sky
Sõbraks tuule ja taeva sain.
The wind and sky are now my friends.
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! Olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
You'll never see me cry
Ei mingeid pisaraid!
No more tears!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Siin ma nüüd! Ja sii jään!
Here I am now! And here I'll stay!
Let the storm rage on...
Lase huilgab torm!
Let the storm howl!
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mu vägi tabab maad erk valge välguna.
My power strikes the ground as a bright white lightning.
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mu tunded kargeks lumesajuks taaskord muutuvad.
My feelings turn into a crisp falling snow once again.
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Kui külm kristall on mõte mida ees ma näen
My thoughts are like ice cold crystal that I see in front of me
I'm never going back
Et sinna tagasi
I will never return
The past is in the past!
ma kunagi ei läe!
to that place again!
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! Olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Koidukiirtest nüüd on mu kroon
My crown is now made out of the rays of dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Olgu nii! olgu nii!
So be it! So be it!
That perfect girl is gone
Hea tudruk lamud on!
The good girl is gone!
Here I stand in the light of day
Siin ma nüüd päevavalguses
Now I'm here in the light of day
Let the storm rage on!
Torm las kestma jääb!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Sest külmus just sobibki minule.
For the cold suits me perfectly.