Transcript and translation
from DisneyFINNISHsongs http://youtu.be/gwteRrW-Y7k
Sung by Katja Sirkiä
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
On hyiset vuoret ne lumiset niin,
The hoar mountains are so snowy,
not a footprint to be seen
hanki hohtaa hehkuen
the drift glows shimmering
A kingdom of isolation,
On linna niin yksinäinen,
The castle is so lonely,
and it looks like I'm the queen
sitä yksin hallitsen
I reign it by myself
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Ja tuuli ulvoo niin kuin myrsky sisälläin
The wind is howling like the storm inside me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Siellä pysy ei, vaikka tahtoisin
Doesn't stay there, even if I'd want
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Ei tulla saa, ei nähdä saa
Can't come in, can't see
Be the good girl you always had to be
Kiltti tyttö sä ole aina vaan
Be a good girl ever more
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Ei paljastaa saa tunteitaan
Can't reveal the feelings
Well, now they know!
Se jäädä saa
It can be left behind
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
Can't hold it back any more!
En tätä voi pidättää
I can't hold this back
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
Turn away and slam the door!
Ovi vanha taakse jää
The old door can be left behind
I don't care what they're going to say
Unhoittaa sanat julmat saan
I can forget the mean words
Let the storm rage on
Myrsky raivotkoon
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Saa nyt kylmä viima tää puhaltaa
Let this cold draught blow on
It's funny how some distance
Kun joskus kaukaa katsoo,
And when you look from afar sometimes,
Makes everything seem small
on kaikki pientä niin
everything's so small
And the fears that once controlled me
Ja nuo pelon vanhat kahleet
And those old chains of fear
Can't get to me at all!
mä loihdin kadoksiin
I will conjure away!
It's time to see what I can do
On aika nähdä voimat mun
It's time to see my powers
To test the limits and break through
Ne koetella, vapauttaa
To test [and] release them
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Pois vanhat säännöt, nyt mä oon...
Away the old rules now I am...
I'm free!
vapaa!
...free!
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
I am one with the wind and sky
Tuuleen jäiseen mä nostan pään
I'll raise my head to the icy wind
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
You'll never see me cry
On menneet päivät nää
Those days are gone
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Tänne jään ja nostan pään
Here I'll stay, and raise my head
Let the storm rage on...
Myrsky raivotkoon...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mun voima halki ilman käy, se iskee kii
My power goes through the air, it strikes on
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mun sieluun piirtyy jäiset huurreruusut kylmät niin
The roses of frost are being delineated into my soul
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Ja kirkas kristalli on ajatuksein tää
And this thought of mine is like a clear crystal
I'm never going back
Ei palaa entinen,
The past won't be back,
The past is in the past!
se kaikki taakse jää
it'll all be left behind
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Enää tyydy en vähempään
I won't settle for lesser anymore
Let it go, let it go!
Taakse jää, taakse jää
Left behind, left behind
That perfect girl is gone
Myös kiltti tyttö tää
will be this good girl as well
Here I stand in the light of day
Jääköön taa, uutta voimaa saan
Let it be left behind, I'll get new strength
Let the storm rage on!
Myrsky raivotkoon
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Saa nyt kylmä viima tää puhaltaa
Let this cold draught blow on