Transcript and translation
from ElkeChan http://youtu.be/NvHx6FR1zYg
Sung by Elke Buyle
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
De sneeuw glanst zacht op de bergen vannacht,
The snow glows softly on the mountains tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
en geen voetafdruk te zien
and not a footprint to be seen
A kingdom of isolation,
Een koninkrijk stil en eenzaam
A kingdom quiet and lonely
and it looks like I'm the queen
en ik ben de koningin
and I'm the queen
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
De wind jaagd huilend als de wervelstorm in mij
The wind is crying like the hurricane in me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
'k Hou het niet meer uit, nu laat ik hem vrij
I can't hold it back, now I let it free
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Laat niemand toe, kijk niemand aan
Let no one in, don't look at anyone
Be the good girl you always had to be
Je moet altijd het brave meisje zijn
You always have to be the good girl
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Geen blik, geen snik, het masker op
No look, no sob, put on the mask
Well, now they know!
Hier houdt het op!
It stops right here!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
Can't hold it back any more!
Ik hou het echt niet meer uit!
I can't hold it back any more!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
Turn away and slam the door!
'k Gooi de deur dicht, keer niet terug!
I slam the door shut, and don't turn back!
I don't care what they're going to say
'k Geef niet om al hun commentaar
I don't care about their commentary
Let the storm rage on
En de storm raast door
And the storm rages on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
De vrieskou daar zat ik toch al niet mee.
The freezing cold doesn't bother me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
't Is vreemd maar op een afstand
It's weird, but at a distance
Makes everything seem small
Lijkt alles heel erg klein
Everything seems very small
And the fears that once controlled me
En de angsten die ik voelde
And the fears which I have felt
Can't get to me at all!
Die blijken weg te zijn!
Those seem to be away!
It's time to see what I can do
Ik will nu zien wat ik kan doen
I want to see now what I can do
To test the limits and break through
'k Bepaalde de grenzen, waar en hoe
To try the limits, where and how
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Geen kwaad, geen goed, geen wet voor mij
No wrong, no right, no law for me
I'm free!
'k Ben vrij!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
I am one with the wind and sky
Met de wind and de hemel één
With the wind and the heaven one
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
You'll never see me cry
Mijn laatste traan verdween
My last tear disappeared
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Ik sta hier, en ik blijf hier,
I'll stand here, and I'll stay here,
Let the storm rage on...
En de storm raast door...
And the storm rages on...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mijn krachten schieten door de lucht terug naar de grond
My powers are shooting through the air back to the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mijn ziel versplinterd zich als ijskristallen in het rond
My soul shattered in ice crystals all around
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
En één gedachte vormt zich ijzig koud in mij
And one thought forms in icy cold in me
I'm never going back
Nee, ik ga nooit meer terug
No, I'm never going back
The past is in the past!
Voorbij is nu voorbij!
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ik herrijs als de ochtend gloort
I'll rise as the morning dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Laat het los, laat het los!
That perfect girl is gone
Die brave meid is er vandoor
That good girl is gone
Here I stand in the light of day
In het licht maak ik mijn entree
In the light I'll make my entrance
Let the storm rage on!
En de storm raast door!
And the storm rages on!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
De vrieskou daar zat ik toch al niet mee.
The freezing cold doesn't bother me anyway.