Transcript and translation
from FlamSparks http://youtu.be/Kl7MiuXiHDA
Sung by Anaïs Delva
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
L'hiver s'installe doucement dans la nuit
Winter is settling in gently in the night
not a footprint to be seen
La neige est reine à son tour
Snow is queen itself
A kingdom of isolation,
Un royaume de solitude
A kingdom of loneliness
and it looks like I'm the queen
Ma place est là, pour toujours.
My place is there, forever.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Le vent qui hurle en moi "ne pense plus à demain"
The wind is screaming inside me, "don't think about tomorrow any more"
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Il est bien trop fort, j'ai lutté en vain.
It's really too strong, I've struggled in vain.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Cache tes pouvoirs, n'en parle pas
Hide your powers, don't talk about them
Be the good girl you always had to be
Fais attention, le secret survivra
Be careful, the secret will survive
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Pas d'états d'âme, pas de tourments
No emotions, no torments
Well, now they know!
De sentiments!
(or) feelings!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
Can't hold it back any more!
Je ne mentirai plus jamais
I won't lie ever again
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
Turn away and slam the door!
C'est décidée, je m'en vais!
It's decided, I'm going away!
I don't care what they're going to say
J'ai laissé mon enfance en été
I left my childhood in summer
Let the storm rage on
Perdue dans l'hiver
Lost in the winter
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Le froid est pour moi le prix de la liberté.
Cold for me is the price of freedom.
It's funny how some distance
Quand on prend de la hauteur
When we raise,
Makes everything seem small
Tout semble insignifiant
Everything looks insignificant
And the fears that once controlled me
La tristesse, l'angoisse et la peur
Sadness, anxiety and fear
Can't get to me at all!
M'ont quittée depuis longtemps!
Left me long ago!
It's time to see what I can do
Je veux voir ce que je peux faire
I want to see what I can do
To test the limits and break through
De cette magie pleine de mystère
With this magic full of mystery
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Le bien, le mal, je dis tant pis
Good, evil, I say let it be
I'm free!
Tant pis!
Let it be!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
I am one with the wind and sky
Les étoiles me tendent les bras
Stars are reaching out to me
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
You'll never see me cry
Non, je ne pleure pas
No, I don't cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Me voilà, oui, je suis là
Here I am, yes I'm here
Let the storm rage on...
Perdue dans l'hiver...
Lost in the winter...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mon pouvoir vient de ciel et envahit l'espace
My power comes from the sky and invades the space
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mon âme s'exprime en dessinant et sculptant dans la glace
My soul expresses itself drawing and carving ice
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Et mes pensées sont des fleurs de cristal gelées
And my thoughts are frozen crystal flowers
I'm never going back
Je ne reviendrai pas
I won't come back
The past is in the past!
Le passé est passé!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Désormais plus rien ne m'arrête
Nothing can stop me any more
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
That perfect girl is gone
Plus de princesse parfaite
No more the perfect princess
Here I stand in the light of day
Je suis là, comme je l'ai rêvé
I am here, as I dreamt of
Let the storm rage on!
Perdue dans l'hiver
Lost in the winter
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Le froid est pour moi le prix de la liberté.
Cold for me is the price of freedom.