Transcript and translation
from xPrzygody http://youtu.be/1PCWtnBNo_o
Sung by Furedi Nikolett
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
A hótenger ma a hegyeken áll
The pile of snow stands on the mountain today
not a footprint to be seen
Ugye vakít ez a fény?
The light blinds you, doesn't it?
A kingdom of isolation,
A szíved is jégbe zárva
And your heart is locked in ice
and it looks like I'm the queen
Itt a világ peremén
Here at the edge of the world
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Tudom, hogy elrontottam rémes tettem fáj.
I know that I've ruined it, my awful deed hurts.
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Vajon, hogy is volt, lehet mindegy már.
How was it? Maybe it doesn't matter any more.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
A lelkem rég csak ettől félt
Before, my soul was afraid of this
Be the good girl you always had to be
Nagyon nehéz, hogy ma ez megtörtént
It's very hard, because it happened
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Hát jöjjön szél, és tél és hó
Let the wind, the winter, and the snow come
Well, now they know!
Tán így is jó!
Perhaps this will be the right way!
Let it go, let it go!
Legyen hó, legyen hó!
Let it snow, let it snow!
Can't hold it back any more!
Még sose volt hasonló.
There was never something like this before.
Let it go, let it go!
Legyen hó, legyen hó!
Let it snow, let it snow!
Turn away and slam the door!
Olyan lelket mozdító.
To move my soul that much
I don't care what they're going to say
Bár tudnám azt, hogy mi lesz itt még
I wish I knew what would happen here
Let the storm rage on
Jöjjön száz orkán!
Let hundreds of storms come!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
És közben a szívemen ül a jég.
And meanwhile my heart is covered in ice.
It's funny how some distance
Ma fura erők jönnek
Today, misty powers
Makes everything seem small
a messzi távolból
are coming from a distance
And the fears that once controlled me
Ez az el nem múló érzés
This endless feeling
Can't get to me at all!
a szenvedélyről szól
is all about passion
It's time to see what I can do
Ez itt és most sorsfordító
Now this is changing my fate
To test the limits and break through
Legyen hát minden jég és hó.
Let it all be ice and snow.
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Varázsos hangon szól a szív
My heart sings with a magical voice
I'm free!
Úgy hív...
It calls me...
Let it go, let it go!
Ugye jó, ugye jó?
Isn't it good, isn't it good?
I am one with the wind and sky
Hogy a gondom a széllel száll
How my problems are gone with the wind
Let it go, let it go!
Ugye jó, ugye jó?
Isn't it good, isn't it good?
You'll never see me cry
Nem sírok többé már.
I'm not crying any more.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Nagy lépés, itt otthon vár
A big step, a home for me is here
Let the storm rage on...
Ami volt nem fáj
What it was doesn't hurt me any more
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
A szívem hózáporként fúj majd mindent át,
My heart is flurrying snow all around,
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A lelkem hadd vágtasson, Hadd tomboljon, szóljon hát!
Let my soul gallop, let it rage on, and let it be heard!
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
S ha végül minden percet jégkristály vált
And if finally every minute turns in icy crystals
I'm never going back
A holnap rámtalál
Tomrrow will find me
The past is in the past!
És a múlt lehull majd rám!
And my past will fall behind!
Let it go, let it go!
Ugye jó, ugye jó?
Isn't it good, isn't it good?
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ahogy elvisz a fénylő hó
How the glittering snow takes me away
Let it go, let it go!
Ugye jó, ugye jó?
Isn't it good, isn't it good?
That perfect girl is gone
Az erő bennem jár
The power is inside me
Here I stand in the light of day
Nézz most rám minden más volt rég
Look at me now, everything used to be different
Let the storm rage on!
De ma új nap vár?
But is a new day waiting for me?
The cold never bothered me anyway.
És közben a szívemen ül a jég.
And meanwhile my heart is covered in ice.