Transcript and translation
from FlamSparks http://youtu.be/P9HPQVrBLx4
Sung by Serena Autieri
Note: The title "All'alba sorgerò" is not, unusually,
the lyrics for the line "Let it go", in this translation.
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
La neve che cade sopra di me
The snow is falling on me
not a footprint to be seen
copre tutto... col suo oblio
covering everything... with its oblivion
A kingdom of isolation,
In questo remoto regno
In this distant kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
La regina... sono io
The queen... is me
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Ormai la tempesta nel mio cuore irrompe già
The storm is already breaking into my heart
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Non la fermerà la mia volontà
My will won't hold it
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Ho conservato ogni bugia
I kept every lie
Be the good girl you always had to be
Per il mondo la colpa è solo mia
To the world the fault is only mine
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Così non va, non sentirò
It can't go on like this, I'm not going to listen to
Well, now they know!
... un altro "no"!
... another "no"!
Let it go, let it go!
D'ora in poi lascerò
From now on I'll let
Can't hold it back any more!
che il cuore mi guidi un po'
my heart lead me a little
Let it go, let it go!
Scorderò quel che so
I'll forget what I know
Turn away and slam the door!
E da oggi cambierò
And starting from today I'll change
I don't care what they're going to say
Resto qui, non andrò più via
I'm staying here, I will never leave
Let the storm rage on
Sono sola ormai
Now I'm alone
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Da oggi il freddo è casa mia.
Starting from today the cold is my home.
It's funny how some distance
A volte è un bene
Sometimes it's good
Makes everything seem small
poter scappare un po'
to run away for a while
And the fears that once controlled me
Può sembrare un salto enorme
It may seem like a huge jump
Can't get to me at all!
Ma io l'affronterò!
But I will face it!
It's time to see what I can do
Non è un difetto, è una virtù
It isn't a fault, it's a virtue
To test the limits and break through
E non la fermerò mai più
And I won't hold it ever again
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Nessun ostacolo per me
No obstacle for me
I'm free!
Perché...
Because...
Let it go, let it go!
... d'ora in poi troverò
... from now on I'll find
I am one with the wind and sky
... la mia vera identità
... my true identity
Let it go, let it go!
E vivrò, sì vivrò
And I'll live, yes I'll live
You'll never see me cry
per sempre in libertà!
forever free!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Se è qui il posto mio
If my place is here
Let the storm rage on...
Io lo scoprirò.
I will find it out.
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Il mio potere si diffonde intorno a me
My power is spreading around me
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Il ghiaccio aumenta e copre ogni cosa accanto a sé
Ice is gathering and covering everything by
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Un mio pensiero cristallizza la realtà
A thought from me crystallizes reality
I'm never going back
Il resto è storia ormai
What's left is history by now
The past is in the past!
Che passa e se ne va!
Passing by and going away!
Let it go, let it go!
Io lo so, sì, lo so
I know, yes, I know
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Come il sole tramonterà
I'll set like the sun
Let it go, let it go!
Perché poi, perché poi,
Because then, because then,
That perfect girl is gone
All'alba sorgerò
I'll rise at dawn
Here I stand in the light of day
Ecco qua la tempesta che
Here is the storm that
Let the storm rage on!
non si fermerà!
wont stop!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Da oggi il destino appartiene a me.
Starting from today fate belongs to me.