Transcript and translation
from http://papercoleena.tumblr.com/
Sung by Takako Matsu (松たか子)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
降り始めた雪は
furihajimeta yuki ha
The snow has started to fall,
not a footprint to be seen
足跡消して
ashiato keshite
and erases all footsteps
A kingdom of isolation,
真っ白な世界に
masshiro na sekai ni
In this pure-white world
and it looks like I'm the queen
一人の私
hitori no watashi
I'm all alone
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
風が心にささやくの
kaze ga kokoro ni sasayaku no
The wind whispers to my heart,
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
このままじゃダメなんだと
kono mama ja dame nan da to
I can't stay like this.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
戸惑い、傷つき
tomadoi kizutsuki
Confusion, hurt
Be the good girl you always had to be
誰にも打ち明けずに
dare nimo uchiakezu ni
Unable to open up to anyone,
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
悩んでたそれももう
nayandeta sore mo mou
I'd troubled and worried
Well, now they know!
止めよう
yameyou
Let's stop that already
Let it go, let it go!
ありのままの
ari no mama no
I'll show you how I truly am
Can't hold it back any more!
姿見せるのよ
sugata miseru no yo
I'll show you how I truly am
Let it go, let it go!
ありのままの
ari no mama no
I'll become my true self
Turn away and slam the door!
自分になるの
jibun ni naru no
I'll become my true self
I don't care what they're going to say
何も怖くない
nanimo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything
Let the storm rage on
風よ吹け
kaze yo fuke
Let the wind blow
The cold never bothered me anyway.
少しも寒くないわ
sukoshi mo samukunai wa
I'm not the least bit cold
It's funny how some distance
悩んでたことは
nayandeta koto ga
All of the worries I had
Makes everything seem small
嘘みたいで
uso mitai ne
seems like a lie
And the fears that once controlled me
だってもう自由よ
datte mou jiyuu yo
After all, I'm now free,
Can't get to me at all!
何でも出来る
nandemo dekiru
I can do anything
It's time to see what I can do
どこまでやれるか
dokomade yareru ka
How far can I go?
To test the limits and break through
自分を試したいの
jibun wo tameshitai no
I want to test myself
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
そうよ、変わるのよ
sou yo kawaru no yo
That's right, I'm going to change!
I'm free!
私
watashi
That's right, I'm going to change!
Let it go, let it go!
ありのままで
ari no mama de
As I truly am,
I am one with the wind and sky
空へ風に乗って
sora he kaze ni notte
I'll ride the wind into the sky,
Let it go, let it go!
ありのままで
ari no mama de
As I truly am,
You'll never see me cry
飛び出してみるの
tobidashitemiru no
I'll try taking flight
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
二度と涙は
nidoto namida ha
From now on tears
Let the storm rage on...
流さないわ
nagasanai wa
will not flow.
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
冷たく大地を包み込み
tsumetaku daichi wo tsutsumikomi
I envelop the earth in cold
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
高く舞い上がる想い描いて
takaku maiagaru omoi egaite
and draw my feelings soaring high up into the sky
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
花咲く氷の結晶のように
hanasaku koori no kesshou no youni
Like the crystallization of icy flowers blooming,
I'm never going back
輝いていたい
kagayaiteitai
I want to shine;
The past is in the past!
もう決めたの
mou kimeta no
I've already decided
Let it go, let it go!
これでいいの
kore de ii no
I'm fine as I am
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
自分を好きになって
jibun wo suki ni natte
I'll come to like myself
Let it go, let it go!
これでいいの
kore de ii no
I'm fine as I am
That perfect girl is gone
自分信じて
jibun shinjite
I believe so myself
Here I stand in the light of day
光浴びながら
hikari abinagara
As I bask in the light,
Let the storm rage on!
歩きだそう
arukidasou
I'll begin walking
The cold never bothered me anyway.
少しも寒くないわ
sukoshi mo samukunai wa
I'm not the least bit cold