Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/OZAEgmpXdaU
Sung by Carmen Sarahí
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
La nieve pinta la montaña hoy,
Today the snow paints the mountain
not a footprint to be seen
no hay huellas que seguir
leaving no traces to follow
A kingdom of isolation,
En la soledad un reino
A kingdom in solitude
and it looks like I'm the queen
Y la reina vive en mì
And the queen lives within me
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
El viento ruge y hay tormenta en mí interior
The wind howls and there's storm inside me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Una tempestad que de mi salió...
A turmoil that went away from me...
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Lo que hay en ti no dejes ver
Don't let this thing that dwells within you be seen
Be the good girl you always had to be
Buena chica tu siempre debes ser
Good girl, like you're always supposed to be
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
No has de abrir tu corazón...
You shouldn't open your heart...
Well, now they know!
¡Pues ya se abrió!
So the heart opened itself!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
Can't hold it back any more!
No puedo ocultarlo más
I'm not able to conceal it any more
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
Turn away and slam the door!
¡Libertad sin vuelta atrás!
Freedom without going back!
I don't care what they're going to say
¡Que más da! ¡No me importa ya!
What does it matter! I couldn't care less!
Let the storm rage on
Gran tormenta habrá...
A great storm is impending...
The cold never bothered me anyway.
El frío es parte tambíen de mí.
The cold is a part of me as well.
It's funny how some distance
Mirando a la distancia,
Looking to the distance,
Makes everything seem small
Pequeño todo es
Everything is small
And the fears that once controlled me
Y los miedos que me ataban,
And the fears that bound me,
Can't get to me at all!
¡Muy lejos los lejé!
I've driven them away with ease!
It's time to see what I can do
Voy a probar que puedo hacer
I'm going to try what I can do
To test the limits and break through
Sin limitar mi proceder
Without holding back my actions
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Ni mal ni bien obedecer
Without obeying either good or bad
I'm free!
¡Jamás!
Never again!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
I am one with the wind and sky
El viento me abrazará
The wind will embrace me
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
You'll never see me cry
¡No me verán llorar!
They won't see me crying!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
¡Firme así, me quedo aquí!
Standing firm, I'll stay here!
Let the storm rage on...
Gran tormenta habrá...
A great storm is impending...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Por viento y tierra mi poder florecerá
My power will flourish through wind and earth
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mi alma congelada en fragmentos romperá
My frozen soul will shatter in shards
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Ideas nuevas pronto cristalizaré
I'll swiftly crystalize new ideas
I'm never going back
No volveré jamás
I'll never return
The past is in the past!
¡No queda nada atrás!
Nothing is left behind!
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Surgiré como el despertar
I'll rise as if awakened
Let it go, let it go!
¡Libre soy! ¡Libre soy!
I'm free! I'm free!
That perfect girl is gone
¡Se fue la chica ideal!
The perfect little girl is gone!
Here I stand in the light of day
¡Firme así a la luz del sol!
Standing firm to the light of the sun!
Let the storm rage on!
¡Gran tormenta habrá!
A great storm is impending!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
El frío es parte tambíen de mí.
The cold is a part of me as well.