Transcript and translation
from DarkSailor7 http://darksailor7.deviantart.com/art/Ledus-sirds-Lai-nu-snieg-lyrics-465054666
Sung by Jolanta Strikaite
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Te kalnus ieskauj baltais sniegs
Mountains are covered in white snow
not a footprint to be seen
Un tas pārklāj nogāzes
And it covers slopes
A kingdom of isolation,
Šī karaļvalsts visa ledū
This kingdom is covered in ice
and it looks like I'm the queen
Kurā diemžēl - valdu es
In which, unfortunately, I rule
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Pūš spēcīgs vējš un mani augstas bēdas māc
Wind is blowing and high feelings of grief are mocking me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Nevar noslēp to, Man tas nesanāk
I can't hide it, I can't do it
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Tik nebaidies un savaldies
Don't be afraid and restrain
Be the good girl you always had to be
Smaidi vienmēr, tu vari priecāties
Always smile, you can rejoice
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Slēpies, centies, tev jāslēpj to
Hide, try it, you have to hide it
Well, now they know!
Kas tev ir dots
What you are given
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
Can't hold it back any more!
Vairs nespēju noslēpt to
I can't hide it anymore
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
Turn away and slam the door!
Man nav vairs jātēlo
I don't have to pretend
I don't care what they're going to say
Prieks ir man, Bēdām pienāks gals
Happiness is in me, Sadness has to end
Let the storm rage on
Sniega vētra nāk
Snow storm is coming
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Man sals ir paticis tik un tā
I liked cold better
It's funny how some distance
Es atradīšos citur
I will be somewhere else
Makes everything seem small
Mans sapnis mani sauc
My dream is calling me
And the fears that once controlled me
Un bailes kuras manī
And the fear that I had
Can't get to me at all!
Nemaz vairs neuztrauc
Don't bother anymore
It's time to see what I can do
Laiks pārbaudīt, Kas spēju kļūt
Time to test what I can become
To test the limits and break through
Šai vietā varu pati būt
In this place I can be myself
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Lai valda miers, kas manī mīt
Let the peace rule, which lives in me
I'm free!
Sniegs krīt
Snow is falling
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
I am one with the wind and sky
Man ir vējš šajās debesīs
I have wind in the sky
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
You'll never see me cry
Vējš bēdas aizpūtīs
Wind will blow away all sadness
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Rīts ir klāt, Tas pieder man
Morning is here, it belongs to me
Let the storm rage on...
Sniega vētra nāk...
Snow storm is coming...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mans spēks skar debesis un arī zemi skauž
My power is touching sky and the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Jau dvēsele gaisā virmo, Vējš tai augstu lidot ļauj
My soul dances in the air, Wind lets it fly high above
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Tik doma viena sagriež sirdi vērpetē
Only one thought swirls my heart
I'm never going back
Nav ceļa atpakaļ,
There is no way back
The past is in the past!
Viss paliek pagātnē!
Everything is left in the past!
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Varu visam pāri celties
I can rise above all
Let it go, let it go!
Lai nu snieg, Lai nu snieg!
Let it snow, Let it snow!
That perfect girl is gone
Man nav kur atgriezties
I do not have a place to return
Here I stand in the light of day
Rīts ir klāt, Ledus elpot sāk
The morning is here, Ice starts breathing now
Let the storm rage on!
Sniega vētra nāk
Snow storm is coming
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Man sals ir paticis tik un tā.
I liked cold better.