Transcript and translation
from FireAngel http://youtu.be/e4FzcNbS_Uw
Sung by Girmantė Vaitkutė
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Ant kalno šiąnakt spindi sniegas baltai,
Tonight on the mountain the snow shines white,
not a footprint to be seen
Pėdsako nėr, nematyt
Not a footprint to be seen
A kingdom of isolation,
Vieniša karalystė,
The desolated kingdom,
and it looks like I'm the queen
Ir turiu aš ja valdyt
And I have to rule it
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Ledinis vėjas kaukia, siaučia viduje
Frosty wind is howling, storming inside
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Kaip man išlaikyt siunkią naštą šią
How should I live through this heavy burden?
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Daugiau neleisk jiems pamatyt
Don't let them see any more
Be the good girl you always had to be
Būk gerutė, tik visada mergyt
Be good, like always, girl
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Neleisk suprast, paslėpk, nejausk
Don't let them know, conceal, don't feel
Well, now they know!
Bet jau vėlu!
But now it's too late!
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
Can't hold it back any more!
Laikytis neprivalau
I don't have to follow
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
Turn away and slam the door!
Nusigręžti man lengviau!
Turning away is easier for me!
I don't care what they're going to say
Man vis vien, Ką galvoja jie
What they think, doesn't matter to me
Let the storm rage on
Laikas siaust pūga
It's time to lark around like a snowstorm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Mano širdy vis šalta žiema.
And the cold winter is still in my heart.
It's funny how some distance
Kaip keista iš aukštybių,
It's strange, from above,
Makes everything seem small
Visus mažus matau
I see everyone small
And the fears that once controlled me
Ir kadais užvaldę baimės,
And the fears that once overtook me
Can't get to me at all!
Manes nebepagaus!
Won't grip me!
It's time to see what I can do
Suprasti metas, kągaliu,
It's time to know what I can do,
To test the limits and break through
Surast ribas, nepaisyt jų
To find the limits, (and) defy them
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Jokių taisyklių šiam kely
In this path there are no rules
I'm free!
Aš laisva!
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
I am one with the wind and sky
Su dangum ir vėju, aš viena
I'm one with the wind and sky
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
You'll never see me cry
Neverksiu niekada
I won't ever cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
ši dieną - manu sukurta
This day is created by me
Let the storm rage on...
Lai te siaus pūga...
It's time to lark around like a snowstorm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Lai šaltis valdo visą žemę šiam kalne
Let the frost rule the ground on this mountain
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Sušalus mano siela šalto ledo kristale
Frozen soul of mine in a cold crystal of ice
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Didžiai pas tave yra mintis labai aiški
Great is your bright idea
I'm never going back
Negrįšiu aš atgal,
I won't go back,
The past is in the past!
Kas liko - praeity!
What's left is in the past!
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ir aš kylu su ryškia aušra
And I'm arising with a bright dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Tebūnie, tebūnie!
Let it be, let it be!
That perfect girl is gone
Nebūsiu aš gera
I won't be good as gold
Here I stand in the light of day
Pagaliau, aš viršūnėje
At least, I'm at the top
Let the storm rage on!
Lai te siaus pūga!
It's time to lark around like a snowstorm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O mano širdy vis šalta žiema.
And the cold winter is still in my heart.