Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/TYvdjaeghcs
Sung by Marsha Milan Londoh
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Salju putih menutupi malam
The white snow covers through the night
not a footprint to be seen
Tiada jejak terlihat
No more footsteps to be seen
A kingdom of isolation,
Kerajaan yang terasing
An isolated kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
Dan akulah ratunya
And I am the queen
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Hembusan bayu bak gelora jiwaku
The blowing breeze reflects the turbulence of my soul
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Puas ku cuba untuk memendamnya
I'm tired of trying to hide it away
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Jangan sampai mereka tahu
Don't let everybody know
Be the good girl you always had to be
Harus jadi yang diharapkan
Have to be what they expect of me
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Lindungilah yang sebenar
Shelter the truth
Well, now they know!
Kini aku
So now I will!
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
Can't hold it back any more!
Tak mampu bertahan lagi
Can't hold it in any more
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
Turn away and slam the door!
Ku cuba sedayaku
I am trying with all I can
I don't care what they're going to say
Peduli apa yang dikata
Just ignore whatever they would say
Let the storm rage on
Jiwa ku beku
My soul is ice cold
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Kedinginan tak pernah menggangguku
It's funny how some distance
Kini dapat ku lihat
Now I can see
Makes everything seem small
Jelas dari kejauhan
clearly from across the distance
And the fears that once controlled me
Ketakutan terpendam
The fear I once kept inside me
Can't get to me at all!
Telah dapat ku lepaskan
I was able to set it free
It's time to see what I can do
Sedayanya aku cuba
With all my might I will try
To test the limits and break through
Mengguna segala kuasa
To convey my whole power
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Bebas mengecap nikmatnya
Free to grasp its joyous splendor
I'm free!
Ku bebas
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
I am one with the wind and sky
Terbanglah susuri awan
Fly and trace along the clouds
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
You'll never see me cry
Takkan aku berduka
I will no longer live sadness
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Disini berdiri megah
Here I stand with pride
Let the storm rage on...
Mula yang baru
Time to start anew
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Kuasaku buat hidup bercelaru
My powers have made my life so mystified
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Jiwaku bak salju yang sejuk juga membeku
My soul is like the cold and freezing icy snow
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Membentuk permata menjadi mahkota
Shaping crystals into tiaras
I'm never going back
Sejarahku kekal
My history remains
The past is in the past!
Menjadi sejarah
as history!
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ku bangkit di dunia baru
I will rise in a brand new world
Let it go, let it go!
Bebaskan, bebaskan
Let it go, let it go
That perfect girl is gone
Tidak seperti dulu
Never like before
Here I stand in the light of day
Disini berdiri megah
Here I stand with pride
Let the storm rage on!
Mula yang baru
Time to start anew
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Kedinginan tak pernah meggangguku.