Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/n8QX037nhPU
Sung by Lisa Stokke
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Det glitrer hvitt over fjellet i natt,
It's gleaming white over the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
det er vakkert vintervær.
it's beautiful winter weather.
A kingdom of isolation,
I riket jeg bor alene,
In the realm I live alone,
and it looks like I'm the queen
og som dronning står jeg her.
and as queen I'm standing here.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Og vinden hyler lik som stormen i mitt bryst.
And the wind is howling like the storm that's in my chest.
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Holdt det ikke ut, himlen så min dyst.
Couldn't stand it, heaven saw my struggle.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Slipp ingen inn, la ingen se,
Let no one in, let no one see,
Be the good girl you always had to be
slik er plikten, jeg er jo født til det.
Such is duty, I am born to that.
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Jeg dekket til. Det ingen så,
I covered up. What no one saw,
Well, now they know!
det vet de nå!
they now know!
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
Can't hold it back any more!
Den kraften jeg skjulte før.
The power I hid before.
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
Turn away and slam the door!
Jeg har snudd og stengt en dør!
I have turned and closed a door!
I don't care what they're going to say
Jeg er lei, alt de tror de har sett.
I'm tired, of all they think they have seen.
Let the storm rage on
La det storme nå,
Let the storm rage on,
The cold never bothered me anyway.
litt frost gjør meg ingenting uansett.
some frost doesn't bother me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
Litt avstand gjør det meste
Some distance makes everything
Makes everything seem small
så lite som det er.
seem as small as it is.
And the fears that once controlled me
Og den frykt som en gang holdt meg,
And the fear that once held me,
Can't get to me at all!
kan ikke nå meg her!
cannot reach me here!
It's time to see what I can do
Nå skal jeg se, hva jeg få til.
Now I will see, what I can do.
To test the limits and break through
Å teste grenser, når jeg vil.
To test the limits, when I want to.
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
For alle reglar er forbi.
For all the rules are in the past.
I'm free!
Er fri!
Am free!
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
I am one with the wind and sky
La min kraft fylle alt jeg ser.
Let my power fill all I see.
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
You'll never see me cry
Jeg gråter ikke mer.
I cry no more.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Jeg blir her, der gleden er,
I stay here, where joy is,
Let the storm rage on...
La det storme nå...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Min kraft den jager gjennom luften ned mot jord.
My power chases through the air towards the ground.
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Og sjelen er som frostne iskrystaller ifra nord
And the soul is like frozen ice crystals from the north
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
En tanke har tatt form som rim med nåler i
A thought has taken shape as rime with needles inside
I'm never going back
Jeg vender aldri hjem,
I'll never turn back home,
The past is in the past!
all fortid er forbi!
the past is in the past!
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Jeg skal stige lik solen nå.
I will now rise like the sun.
Let it go, let it go!
La den gå, la den gå!
That perfect girl is gone
Perfekt er fortid så
The past is perfect like that
Here I stand in the light of day
Jeg er klar, og jeg smiler bredt
I'm ready, and I'm smiling broadly
Let the storm rage on!
La det storme her!
Let the storm rage here!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Litt frost gjør meg ingenting uansett.
Some frost doesn't bother me anyway.