Transcript and translation
from slayra http://youtu.be/hA5x_L5JNAw
Sung by Ana Encarnação
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
A neve cobre a montanha esta noite,
The snow covers the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
Mas os passos são só meus.
But the only footsteps are mine.
A kingdom of isolation,
Comigo só há solidão,
There is only the loneliness with me,
and it looks like I'm the queen
Sou rainha destes céus.
I'm the queen of these heavens.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Cá dentro a tempestade que estou a sentir
This storm that I am feeling inside
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Não a controlei, deixei-a sair.
I didn't control it, I let it out.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Não vão entrar, não podem ver!
They won't come in, they cannot see!
Be the good girl you always had to be
Sê a menina que tu tens de ser!
Be the girl you have to be!
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Esconder, conter, ou saberão.
Conceal, contain, or they will know.
Well, now they know!
Mas foi em vão!
But it was in vain!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
Can't hold it back any more!
Não vivo mais com temor.
I don't live in fear any more.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
Turn away and slam the door!
Fecha a porta, por favor!
Please close the door!
I don't care what they're going to say
Tanto faz o que vão dizer
Let the storm rage on
Venha a tempestade...
A storm comes...
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio nunca me fará estremecer.
The cold will never make me shiver.
It's funny how some distance
Eu vejo que a distância
I can see some distance
Makes everything seem small
vai tudo suavizar.
will make everything seem softer.
And the fears that once controlled me
E os medos de outros tempos
And that my old fears
Can't get to me at all!
não me vão apanhar!
won't be able to get to me!
It's time to see what I can do
Ser livre assim é mesmo bom!
Being free like this is really good!
To test the limits and break through
Ver os limites deste dom.
To test the limits of this gift.
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Sem regras sou feliz enfim!
Without rules I'm happy at last!
I'm free!
Sou sim!
Yes I am!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
I am one with the wind and sky
Este é mesmo o meu lugar.
This is where I belong.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
You'll never see me cry
Não irei mais chorar.
I won't cry any more.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Estou aqui e vou ficar,
Here I am, and here I'll stay,
Let the storm rage on...
Venha a tempestade...
A storm comes...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
O meu poder agita o ar que entra no chão
My power stirs the air that enters the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A minha alma brilha em espirais até mais não
My soul shines in infinite spirals
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Um pensamento tudo irá cristalizar
A thought will crystallize everything
I'm never going back
O que passou, passou.
What has passed, has passed.
The past is in the past!
Para trás não vou olhar!
I'm not looking back!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Com o amanhã me vou erguer.
I will rise with tomorrow.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
That perfect girl is gone
Menina não vou ser.
I won't be a little girl any more.
Here I stand in the light of day
Este dia está a nascer
The dawn is coming
Let the storm rage on!
Venha a tempestade!
A storm comes!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio nunca me fará estremecer.
The cold will never make me shiver.