Transcript and translation
from SailorWVA http://youtu.be/uXB5dNqyqfE
Sung by Dalma Kovacs
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Zăpada strălucește-n amurg,
The snow glows in the twilight,
not a footprint to be seen
Nici-o urmă nu-i pe ea
Not a footprint is on it
A kingdom of isolation,
Tărâmul ascuns de lume,
The land hidden from the world,
and it looks like I'm the queen
Este-mpărăția mea
Is my kingdom
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Aici e totul ca furtuna ce-o trăiesc
Here everything is like the storm that I live in
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Știu c-am încercat, nu pot s-o opresc
I know I've tried, I can't stop it
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Nu te-arăta, nu îi primi,
Don't show yourself, don't let them in,
Be the good girl you always had to be
Fata bună tu trebuie să fii!
A good girl you need to be!
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Zăvorul tras și încuiat
A pulled and locked latch
Well, now they know!
Dar au aflat!
But now they know!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
Can't hold it back any more!
Eu nu am mai rezistat!
I couldn't resist any more!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
Turn away and slam the door!
Pe un alt drum am plecat!
On another way I went!
I don't care what they're going to say
Ce spun toți, nu e treaba mea!
What they all say, isn't my business!
Let the storm rage on
Fie ger mereu!
It can always be frost!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
De azi gerul e prietenul meu!
From today the frost is my friend!
It's funny how some distance
Ciudat cum total pare
Strange how everything seems
Makes everything seem small
Departe și uitat
Far away and forgotten
And the fears that once controlled me
Și cum temerile mele
And how my fears
Can't get to me at all!
De-odată au încetat!
Suddenly ceased!
It's time to see what I can do
E timpul meu să mă pornesc
It's my time to start myself (?)
To test the limits and break through
Să văd ce pot, ce reușesc
To see what I can do, what I can accomplish
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Să fie numai cum vreau eu,
To only be how I want it,
I'm free!
Mereu!
Always!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
I am one with the wind and sky
Sunt vântul stârnit din cer!
I'm the wind arisen from the sky!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
You'll never see me cry
Și lacrimile-mi pier!
And my tears fade away!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Liberă, aici în ger!
Free, here in the frost!
Let the storm rage on...
Vântul să-l pornesc...
I'll start the frost...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Puterea mea domnește în cer și pe Pământ!
My power reigns in the sky and on Earth!
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Și sufletul-mi roiește peste crestele de-argint
And my soul swarms over the silver crests
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Un jurământ puternic azi am de făcut:
A strong oath I have to make today:
I'm never going back
Eu nu mă mai întorc,
I won't go back,
The past is in the past!
Trecutul e trecut!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ca din somn eu m-am deșteptat!
Like from sleep I've woken up!
Let it go, let it go!
S-a-ntâmplat, s-a-ntâmplat!
It happened, it happened!
That perfect girl is gone
Și-n viață am plecat!
And in life I go!
Here I stand in the light of day
Stau aici, liberă mereu!
Here I stay, always free!
Let the storm rage on!
Vântul să-l pornesc!
I'll start the frost!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
De azi gerul e prietenul meu.
From today the frost is my friend.