Transcript and translation
from SlavicDubs http://youtu.be/Acy-EVLZxpM
Sung by Jelena Gavrilovic
NOTE: Cyrillic transliteration by Rosuav and likely
to be in error. Please, can someone check it for me?
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Снег се блиста на планини
Sneg se blista na planini
The snow glitters on the mountain
not a footprint to be seen
Нигде стопе па шта сь тим?
Nigde stope pa šta s' tim?
There's no footstep anywhere, so what?
A kingdom of isolation,
Кралјевство бело, пусто
Kraljevstvo belo, pusto
A white and deserted kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
А я сад владам нјим
A ja sad vladam njim
And I rule over it now
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
У мени ветар дивля, опирем се том
U meni vetar divlja, opirem se tom
Inside of me the wind is raging and I'm resisting it
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Само небо зна, целом душом свом
Samo nebo zna, celom dušom svom
Only heaven knows, with all my soul
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Затвори се, напусти све
Zatvori se, napusti sve
Lock yourself up, leave everyone
Be the good girl you always had to be
Буди добра да то не сазна се
Budi dobra da to ne sazna se
Be a good girl so no one finds out
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Твој страх је крах, обуздај га
Tvoj strah je krah, obuzdaj ga
Your fear is havoc, control it
Well, now they know!
Е сад се зна
E sad se zna
Well, now they know
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај, Сад је крај
Sad je kraj, Sad je kraj
It's over now, It's over now
Can't hold it back any more!
Јер доста сам патила
Jer dosta sam patila
Cause I've suffered enough
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај, Сад је крај!
Sad je kraj, Sad je kraj!
It's over now, It's over now!
Turn away and slam the door!
Муке сам прекратила
Muke sam prekratila
I've put an end to my torments
I don't care what they're going to say
Брига ме откуд потиче
Briga me otkud potiče
I don't care where it comes from
Let the storm rage on
Нека буде мраз
Neka bude mraz
Let the frost come
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Јер зима мене барем не дотиче
Jer zima mene barem ne dotiče
Cause at least the winter doesn't get to me
It's funny how some distance
Баш чудно што далјина
Baš čudno što daljina
It's really funny how distance
Makes everything seem small
Све бриге развеје
Sve brige razveje
Unfurls all worries
And the fears that once controlled me
Мога страха више нема
Moga straha više nema
My fear is gone
Can't get to me at all!
Све ме сада насмеје
Sve me sada nasmeje
Everything makes me laugh now
It's time to see what I can do
Показаćу шта могу я
Pokazaću šta mogu ja
I'll show what I can do
To test the limits and break through
И границу ćу преćи, да!
I granicu ću preći, da!
And I'll cross the limit, yes!
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Сад одлазим и нек се зна
Sad odlazim i nek se zna
Now I'm leaving and you should know
I'm free!
Слободна!
Slobodna!
I'm free!
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај, Сад је крај
Sad je kraj, Sad je kraj
It's over now, It's over now
I am one with the wind and sky
На крилима ветра сам
Na krilima vetra sam
I'm on the wings of the wind
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај, Сад је крај
Sad je kraj, Sad je kraj
It's over now, It's over now
You'll never see me cry
Без суза идем, знам
Bez suza idem, znam
I know that I'm leaving without tears
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Овде сам и остаćу
Ovde sam i ostaću
I'm here and I'm gonna stay
Let the storm rage on...
Нека буде мраз
Neka bude mraz
Let the frost come
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Сва моя моć се шири ваздухом и тлом
Sva moja moć se širi vazduhom i tlom
My power is spreading through the air and through the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Кристале стварам сад у новом свету леденом
Kristale stvaram sad u novom svetu ledenom
I'm forming crystals in the new icy world now
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
А додир доволян је да донесе мраз
A dodir dovoljan je da donese mraz
And a touch is enough to bring the frost
I'm never going back
И нема повратка
I nema povratka
And there's no return
The past is in the past!
Ту прошлост дели яз
Tu prošlost deli jaz
The past is separated by a gulf
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај! Сад је крај
Sad je kraj! Sad je kraj
It's over now! It's over now
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Я стојим као зоре знак
Ja stojim kao zore znak
I stand as the sign of dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Сад је крај, Сад је крај
Sad je kraj, Sad je kraj
It's over now, It's over now
That perfect girl is gone
Мој изазов је як
Moj izazov je jak
My challenge is hard
Here I stand in the light of day
Сва сам ту док дан протиче
Sva sam tu dok dan protiče
I'm all here as the day takes its course
Let the storm rage on!
Нека буде мраз
Neka bude mraz
Let the frost come
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Јер зима мене барем не дотиче
Jer zima mene barem ne dotiče
Cause at least the winter doesn't get to me