Transcript and translation
from credocommgo http://vimeo.com/95553678
Sung by Andrea Somorovská
(Note that the language name should probably be "Slovak"
rather than "Slovakian". I've followed the Disney-published
track titles, but if anyone is offended by my misnaming of
the language, I'll change it to Slovak.)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Sneh na horách v noci biely až starch
The snwo on the mountains tonight is white and frightening
not a footprint to be seen
život skryl tvár predo mnou
Life has hidden its face from me
A kingdom of isolation,
V tom král'ovstve bielych tieňov
In this kingdom of white shadows,
and it looks like I'm the queen
asi budem král'ovnou
I will probably be queen
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
No vo mne vnútri búrka zúri a ja viem
But a storm rages inside of me and I know
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
V sebe to skrývat' viac nedokážem
I can't hide it in me any more
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Nechaj to tak čo v tebe vrie
Leave alone what boils in you
Be the good girl you always had to be
A bud' len tou čo sa vždy správat' vie
And just be the one who knows how to behave
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Skry každý cit l'ud'om sa vzdial'
Hide every emotion, stay far away from people
Well, now they know!
A lumlám sa vzdaj!
And give in to the mists!
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
Can't hold it back any more!
Viac to v sebe neskrývam
I'm not going to hide in me any more
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
Turn away and slam the door!
A už pokoj v sebe mám
And now, I feel peace inside of me
I don't care what they're going to say
Tu stojím na všetko mám dost' stil
Standing here, I have enough strength to do anything
Let the storm rage on
Nech si zúri mráz
Let the frost come
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Ved' chlad mi aj tak nikdy nevadil.
Because the cold never bothered me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
Je zvláštne ako dial'ka
It's strange how distance
Makes everything seem small
Dokáže zmenšit' svet
Can make the world small
And the fears that once controlled me
Vo mne niečo krásne klíči
When something beautiful is born
Can't get to me at all!
Ked' strachu viac už niet!
When there's no more fear!
It's time to see what I can do
Nech všetci vedia vôkol že
Let everyone around know that
To test the limits and break through
čo budem chciet' to dokážem
Whatever I want, I can achieve
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Pravidlá žiadne som mnou
There are no rules for me
I'm free!
Vol'ná!
Free!
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
I am one with the wind and sky
Budem vetrom i oblohou
I'll be the wind and sky
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
You'll never see me cry
A slzy sú za mnou
And the tears are left behind me
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Tu stojím a chcem tu stát'
Standing here, and I want to stand here,
Let the storm rage on...
Nech si zúri mráz...
Let the frost come...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Na zem sa vzduchom valí sila ktorú mám
My power rolls onto the ground by the air
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A duša sa chce vyhnút' zamrznutým náladám
And my soul wants to avoid the frozen moods
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Len jedna myšlienka sa vznáša nad hlavou
Only one thought floats over my head
I'm never going back
Všetko mám pred sebou
I have everything before me
The past is in the past!
čo bolo je za mnou!
What was, I leave behind!
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Budem úsvitom nových rán
I'll be the dawn of new mornings
Let it go, let it go!
Von to dám, zvnútra dám!
I'll release it, release what's inside!
That perfect girl is gone
Ja skvelý pocit mám
I am feeling great
Here I stand in the light of day
Tu stojím v svetle krásnych dni
Standing here, in the light of beautiful days
Let the storm rage on!
Nech si zúri mráz!
Let the frost come!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Ved' chlad mi aj tak nikdy nevadil.
Because the cold never bothered me anyway.