Transcript and translation
from ElsaMH FrozenLove http://youtu.be/J8n1DZFGYgo
Sung by Nuška Drašcek Rojko
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Sneg blešči se povsod nocoj
The snow glows everywhere tonight
not a footprint to be seen
In nobenih ni sledi
There are no footprints
A kingdom of isolation,
Osamljeno je kraljestvo
The kingdom is lonely
and it looks like I'm the queen
In kraljica sama sem
And the queen is myself
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
In veter vpije, ko vrtinec v meni tli
And the wind is shouting, when a twister inside of me smolders
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Na ves glas kričim, v meni ne zdrži
I'm screaming out loud, it can't stay inside
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Skrij svoj obraz, obrni se drugam
Hide your face, turn around
Be the good girl you always had to be
Bodi takšna kot drugi so vsi
Be like everyone else
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Prijrij kar si, naj ne vedo
Hide what you are, don't let them know
Well, now they know!
A zdaj vedo!
But now they know!
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
Can't hold it back any more!
Ne morem več tja nazaj
I can't go back there
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
Turn away and slam the door!
Ne obrnem več se stran
Won't turn away any more
I don't care what they're going to say
Naj vedo, zdaj pokažem kaj znam
Let them know, now I'll show them what I can do
Let the storm rage on
Kot nevihta sem
I am like a storm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Ker mraz vedno bil je moj pravi dom.
The cold was always my home.
It's funny how some distance
Tu zares sem srečna
I'm truly happy here
Makes everything seem small
Vse nepomembno je
Everything is unimportant
And the fears that once controlled me
In strahov več ni v meni
There are no fears inside of me any more
Can't get to me at all!
Izginili so vsi!
They all disappeared!
It's time to see what I can do
Zdaj naj pokažem vse kar znem
Now I shall show everything that I can do
To test the limits and break through
Prestrežem meje grem naprej
I break the limits, I go on
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Tu ni napak in ne pravil
There's no mistakes or rules here
I'm free!
Letim!
I'm flying!
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
I am one with the wind and sky
Kot eno z vetrom do neba
I'm one with the wind to the sky
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
You'll never see me cry
Jokala več ne bom
I will never cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Tu stojim, in stala bom
Here I stand, and here I'll stand
Let the storm rage on...
Kot nevihta sem...
I am like a storm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Vsa moja moč vrti iz zraka se v tla
All my power spirals from the air into the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
In duša zlahka nosi hladne delce do neba
And my soul can easily carry cold parts to the sky
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Vse misli kot kristali z vetrom se vrte
All thoughts are spiraling like crystals in the wind
I'm never going back
Ne vrnem se nazaj
I'm not going back
The past is in the past!
Preteklost dalje gre!
The past moves on!
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Kakor sonce v zori žarim
I glow like the sun in dawn
Let it go, let it go!
Zaživim, se pustim!
I come to life, I let go!
That perfect girl is gone
Popolna se zbudim
I wake up perfect
Here I stand in the light of day
Tu stojim, bela luč sveta
I stand here, the white light of the world
Let the storm rage on!
Kot nevihta pa!
Like a storm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Ker mraz vedno bil je moj pravi dom.
The cold was always my home.