Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/70bcHn4xqcE
Sung by Annika Herlitz
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Snön har lagt sitt täcke,
The snow has made its covering,
not a footprint to be seen
över berg och glaciär
over mountains and glaciers
A kingdom of isolation,
Det gnistrar i sin enslighet,
It sparkles in its loneliness,
and it looks like I'm the queen
ingen själ passerar här
no soul passes through here
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Den storm som viner inuti mig tyckes ha vänt
The swirling storm inside me seems to have turned
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Ett isolerat land, och jag är dess regent
An isolated kingdom, and I'm its ruler
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Ingen får se djupt inom dig
Let no one see deep inside you
Be the good girl you always had to be
Låt dem inte få genomskåda dig
Don't let them see through you
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Visa ingenting, vad du än gör
Don't show anything, whatever you do
Well, now they know!
Allt är förstört!
Everything is ruined!
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
Can't hold it back any more!
Den tiden den är förbi
That time is in the past
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
Turn away and slam the door!
Vänd dig om, det får bli din sorti
Turn around, that'll be your exit
I don't care what they're going to say
Och aldrig mer ska någon säga nej
And never again will anyone say no
Let the storm rage on
Släpp den storm du bär
Let go of the storm you bear
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Lite snö har väl aldrig stört mig.
A little snow has never bothered me.
It's funny how some distance
Ja, tänkt vad lite avstånd,
Well, imagine what little distance,
Makes everything seem small
Får allt att verka smått
And the fears that once controlled me
Och de rädslor som har styrt mig
And the fears that once ruled me
Can't get to me at all!
är ett fjuttigt minne blott!
are tiny distant memories!
It's time to see what I can do
Nu ska vi se hur användbar den är
Now we'll see how useful it is
To test the limits and break through
den kraften som jag har
the power that I have
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Rätt eller fel, bestämmer jag
Right or wrong, I'll decide
I'm free!
Jag är fri!
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
I am one with the wind and sky
Nu ser jag allt och förstår
Now I see everything and understand
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
You'll never see me cry
Fäller inte en enda tår
I don't shed a single tear
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Här står jag och ska förbli,
Here I stand and will remain,
Let the storm rage on...
Släpp den storm du bär...
Let go of the storm you bear...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Min kraft den flödar genom luft och genom mark
My power flows through the air and through the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Min själ den spirar, kraften väller upp och gör mig stark
My soul is sprouting, power welling up and makes me strong
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Min tanke kristalliserar fantasi till is
My thought crystallizes fantasy into ice
I'm never going back
Jag lämnar allt som var,
I leave all that was,
The past is in the past!
förkastar direktiv!
rejecting directives!
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Bana väg, låt ske det som sker
Make way, whatever will be will be
Let it go, let it go!
Slå dig loss, slå dig fri!
Break away, break free!
That perfect girl is gone
Hon som fanns här finns inte mer
She who was here is no more
Here I stand in the light of day
Och här står jag, en förändrad själ
And here I stand, a changed soul
Let the storm rage on!
Släpp den storm du bär!
Let go of the storm you bear!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Snö har väl aldrig stört mig.
Snow has never bothered me.