Transcript from Harith Z http://youtu.be/0wZ9T4Vx03Y
Translation from Deniz Serra http://vimeo.com/101231773
Sung by Begüm Günceler
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Pırıldıyor kar taneleri
The snowflakes are shining
not a footprint to be seen
bütun izler silinmis
all the remains were wiped away
A kingdom of isolation,
Bir soyutlanma krallığı
A kingdom of isolation
and it looks like I'm the queen
bense sanki prensesi
and I'm its princess
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Rüzgar uluyor coşan fırtına gibi
The wind is howling like the gushing storm
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Durduramadım, oysa denedim
I couldn't stop it, however I tried
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Aman sakla görmesinler
Oh, hide it. Don't let them see.
Be the good girl you always had to be
Seni iyi birisi sansınlar
Make them think you're a good person
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Ört hisleri, bilmesinler
Cover the feelings, don't let them know
Well, now they know!
Biliyorlar!
They know!
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Can't hold it back any more!
Engel olamıyorum
I cannot prevent it
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Turn away and slam the door!
Uzaklaşmak istiyorum
I want to wander away
I don't care what they're going to say
Fark etmez varsın konoşsunlar
It doesn't matter, let them talk
Let the storm rage on
Sürsün fırtına
Let the storm keep on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Soğuk neyse, beni hiç üzmedi.
Whatever the cold is, didn't ever make me sad.
It's funny how some distance
Biraz uzaktan cisimler
The objects from a bit far
Makes everything seem small
Küçük görünürler
seem small
And the fears that once controlled me
Beni yöneten korkular
The fears which did control me
Can't get to me at all!
Bana erişemezler!
Cannot reach me!
It's time to see what I can do
Gücümü deneme vakti
It's time to try my power
To test the limits and break through
Sınırları, gelişmeyi
To try the limits, to thrive
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Doğru yanliş bir kural yok
There's no true-false rule
I'm free!
Özgür!
Free!
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
I am one with the wind and sky
Rüzgarın ve göğün yanında
Nearby the wind and sky
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
You'll never see me cry
Ağlamayacağım asla
I am never going to cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Burdayım, yaşam burda
I am here, the lifetime is here
Let the storm rage on...
Sürsün fırtına...
Let the storm keep on...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Gücüm toprağı sel gibi kaplamakta
My power is covering the earth like the flood
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Ruhum daireler çiziyor değişken yapıda
My soul is drawing circles in the changing structure
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Bir düşüncem bile her yeri dondurur
Even my one thought freezes everywhere
I'm never going back
Geri dönmem asla
I am never going back
The past is in the past!
Geçmiş çok uzakta!
The past is so far away!
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Ruhum yeniden doğmakta
My soul is reborn
Let it go, let it go!
Aldırma, aldırma!
Don't mind, don't mind!
That perfect girl is gone
Kusursuz kız yok burda
There is no flawless girl
Here I stand in the light of day
Burdayım ben karşınızda
I am here, I am in front of you
Let the storm rage on!
Sürsün fırtına!
Let the storm keep on!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Soğuk neyse, beni hiç üzmedi.
Whatever the cold is, didn't ever make me sad.