Transcript and translation
from http://youtu.be/hkVjUD7nm_s
Sung by Oľha Šanis (Ольга Шаніс)
Transcription very much imperfect, would
much appreciate contributions/corrections!
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Цей білий сніг дику гору обліг,
Cej bilyj snih dyku horu oblih,
The wild mountain is wrapped in snow,
not a footprint to be seen
навіть сліду тут нема.
navit’ slidu tut nema.
not even a trace of a footprint.
A kingdom of isolation,
Безлюдне неначе царство,
Bezlûdne nenače carstvo,
Like a desert kingdom,
and it looks like I'm the queen
а царюю я сама
a carûû â sama
and I'm the ruler
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
І завиває вітер, хуга в серці зла
I zavyvaye viter, khuha v serci zla
And the wind is howling, like a snowstorm in the heart of evil
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
втримати в собі силу не змогла.
vtrymaty v sobi sylu ne zmohla.
I failed to keep hiding my power.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
То скгаменись, то доведи
To skhamenys’, to dovedy
You must collect the proofs
Be the good girl you always had to be
ти хороша, і буде так завжди
ty khoroša, i bude tak zavždy
You are beautiful, you will be like that forever
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Сховаи свіи дар в душі на дно
Skhovay sviy dar v duši na dno
Keep your gift hidden in your heart
Well, now they know!
Вже все одно!
Vže vse odno!
It's already been done anyway!
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
Can't hold it back any more!
На волю шугне воно
Na volû šuhne vono
I know it will fall
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
Turn away and slam the door!
Я здалася вже давно.
Â zdalasâ vže davno.
I gave up long ago.
I don't care what they're going to say
Хаи женуть, хай цурають ся.
Khay ženut’, khaj curaût’ sâ.
Let anyone who is chasing me stay away.
Let the storm rage on
Хаи кругом зима
Khay kruhom zyma
These long winters are here,
The cold never bothered me anyway.
та холоду я не лякаюся.
ta kholodu â ne lâkaûsâ.
and I'm not afraid of the cold.
It's funny how some distance
На відстані всі речі
Na vidstani vsi reči
In distance,
Makes everything seem small
малесенькі немов.
malesen’ki nemov.
everything is small.
And the fears that once controlled me
І страхи моиі безодні
I strakhy moyi bezodni
And my endless fears
Can't get to me at all!
не вер вемуться ізнов!
ne ver vemut’sâ iznov!
won't return again!
It's time to see what I can do
Сама собі я покажу,
Sama sobi â pokažu,
I will show it,
To test the limits and break through
що вільна переити межу
ŝo vil’na pereyty mežu
which goes beyond the limit
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Добро і зло - иіх тут нема
Dobro i zlo - yikh tut nema
Good or evil - that isn't a problem any more
I'm free!
нема!
nema!
No, it's not!
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
I am one with the wind and sky
Я і вітер, і небеса.
Â i viter, i nebesa.
Me and the wind, and the sky.
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
You'll never see me cry
Умре в очах сльоза.
Umre v očakh sl’oza.
Dry the tears in my eyes.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Це міи світ, тут лишаюсь я.
Ce miy svit, tut lyšaûs’ â.
This is my world, I am left here.
Let the storm rage on...
Хаи кругом зима...
Khay kruhom zyma...
Let the winter come...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Хаи сила рине в землю - так бажаю за!
Khay syla ryne v zemlû - tak bažaû za!
Let my power sweep into the ground - as I wish to!
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Як віхола заклубочить ся хаи душа моя.
Âk vikhola zaklubočyt’ sâ khay duša moâ.
Let my soul swirl like a snowstorm
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Я починаю розуміти, це вже краи.
Â počynaû rozumity, ce vže kray.
I'm starting to realize that this is the end.
I'm never going back
Немає вороття.
Nemaye vorottâ.
I won't return.
The past is in the past!
Колишнє - прощаваи!
Kolyšnye - proŝavay!
It's the same as goodbye!
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Я заграю, немов зоря.
Â zahraû, nemov zorâ.
I have a destiny like a star.
Let it go, let it go!
Все одно, все одно!
Vse odno, vse odno!
Anyway, anyway!
That perfect girl is gone
Навік змінилась я.
Navik zminylas’ â.
I am forever changed.
Here I stand in the light of day
Ось міи світ! Ним пишаюсь я.
Os’ miy svit! Nym pyšaûs’ â.
This is my world! I'm proud of it.
Let the storm rage on!
Хаи кругом зима!
Khay kruhom zyma!
Let the winter come!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Та холоду я не лякаюста.
Ta kholodu â ne lâkaûsta.
And I'm not afraid of the cold.