Transcript and translation
from Rose Michaelis in a
comment on http://youtu.be/PjCCbmyp5vo
Sung by Dương Hoàng Yến
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Tuyết trắng xóa lấp kín đường về
The snow fills and erases away the road to home
not a footprint to be seen
Còn mình tôi đi trên con đường
Only me left walking on the road
A kingdom of isolation,
Chợt nhìn về vương quốc kia
Suddenly, (I) look back to that kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
Như bị chia cắt với màn đêm
As if it's apart from the night
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Từng đợt gió tuyết xuyên vào con tim giá băng của tôi
Each snow wind blows through my frozen heart
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Thế giới như đổi thay Bao khó khăn nhọc nhằn
As if the world changes So much difficulty and hardship
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Thận trọng tôi ơi, đừng để ai thấy
Oh my wariness, don't let anyone see
Be the good girl you always had to be
Hãy thật xinh tươi hồn nhiên như hôm nao
Be beautiful and innocent like the old days
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Đừng kể ai nghe, đừng để ai biết
Don't tell anyone, don't let anyone know
Well, now they know!
Giờ đây đã hết
It's over now
Let it go, let it go!
Giờ ra đi, một mình ta
Time to go, alone
Can't hold it back any more!
Không còn gì để mà thương đau
Nothing left to hurt me
Let it go, let it go!
Về tương lai và bước đi
To the future and go
Turn away and slam the door!
Và nơi đây ngăn cách thế gian
And this place separates the rest of the world
I don't care what they're going to say
Xóa tan đi, muộn phiền đã qua rồi
Earse away, sorrow is gone now
Let the storm rage on
Gió tuyết hãy tràn về
Snow wind, come to here
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Dù sao cơn lạnh kia đã thân quen ta rồi
Anyway, the cold is already familiar with me
It's funny how some distance
Và nơi đây cho bao diệu kì
Anh this place gives so many wonders
Makes everything seem small
Nhỏ bé trong trong không gian
Small in the space
And the fears that once controlled me
Và chẳng điều gì thay đổi tôi
And nothing can change me
Can't get to me at all!
Vì chẳng có ai nơi đây
Because no one is here
It's time to see what I can do
Dù thời gian qua một mình đơn côi
Though long time ago I was lonely
To test the limits and break through
Giờ đây là lúc vượt qua chính mình
It’s time to go beyond myself
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Còn gì trong ta giờ đây phải đây
Anything left in me must know
I'm free!
Tự do
Freedom!
Let it go, let it go!
Giờ ra đi, một mình ta
Time to go, alone
I am one with the wind and sky
Mây trời cùng hòa vào trong ta
The clouds and the sky are flowing together in me
Let it go, let it go!
Về tương lai và bước đi
To the future and go
You'll never see me cry
Giọt nước mắt đã khô rồi
My tear is already dry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Đứng nơi đây, ngày mới dâng tràn
Standing here, a new day will rise
Let the storm rage on...
Gió tuyết hãy tràn về
Snow wind, come to here
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Nơi này cho ta khám phá biết bao điều hay
This place let me explore so many interesting things
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Tâm hồn tôi đang vụt bay đem đến những cơn lạnh giá quanh đây
My soul is flying and bringing the cold to the area around here
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Bay vào không gian như ngàn băng giá kết tinh ở đây
Flying to the area like thousand of ice crystallizes here
I'm never going back
Tôi sẽ không quay trở lại
I won’t come back
The past is in the past!
Bỏ quên tuổi thơ năm tháng
Leave my childhood years in oblivion
Let it go, let it go!
Hãy bước đi, một mình ta
Step ahead, alone
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Như ngày dài chờ bình minh lên
As I wait long for dawn to come
Let it go, let it go!
Về tương lai và bước đi
To the future and go
That perfect girl is gone
Cuộc sống đã xóa tan rồi
Life has erased away
Here I stand in the light of day
Đứng nơi đây, ngày mới trào dâng
Standing here, a new day has risen
Let the storm rage on!
Hãy đến đây băng giá
Come to here, ice
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Dù sao cơn lạnh kia đã thân quen ta rồi.
Anyway, the cold is already familiar with me.﻿