Born of cold and winter air
Vzduch jak nůž a deště z hor...
[Air like a knife and rain from the mountains...]
And mountain rain combining
noc bílá zmrazí rázem,
[White night suddenly freezes,]
This icy force both foul and fair
a my to srdce ledové
[and have the heart to ice]
Has a frozen heart worth mining
v zimě tuhé dobýváme.
[Winter solid dig.]
So cut through the heart
Jen je nelituj,
[Just a pity,]
Cold and clear
stůj a řež,
[stop a bloodbath,]
Strike for love and strike for fear
strach z něj máš a necouvneš!
[fear of him and got necouvneš!]
See the beauty sharp and sheer
Krásné, zrádné, s ním se rveš.
[Beautiful, treacherous, with him scream.]
Split the ice apart
Srdce své si chraň,
[Protect your heart,]
And break the frozen heart
je pastí bílá pláň.
[it traps white plain.]
Watch your step! Let it go!
Pozor dej! Pevně drž!
[Give Attention! Hold on tight!]
Hup, ho
Hup! Hou...
[Hup! Hou...]
Watch your step! Let it go!
Pozor dej! Pevně drž!
[Give Attention! Hold on tight!]
Beautiful! Powerful!
Krasavec! Láme vaz!
[Handsome! We break a leg!]
Dangerous! Cold!
Klouže jak! had!
[Slides how! Snake!]
Ice has a magic can't be controlled
Led mocí kouzelnou
vládne snad,
Stronger than one
silnější je,
[stronger,]
Stronger than ten
opakuj to,
[repeat it,]
Stronger than a hundred men!
silnější než chlapů sto!
[stronger than a hundred guys!]
Oh!
Born of cold and winter air
Vzduch jak nůž a deště z hor...
[Air like a knife and rain from the mountains...]
And mountain rain combining
noc bílá zmrazí rázem,
[White night suddenly freezes,]
This icy force both foul and fair
a my to srdce ledové
[and have the heart to ice]
Has a frozen heart worth mining
v zimě tuhé dobýváme.
[Winter solid dig.]
Cut through the heart
Víš přece proč,
[You know why,]
Cold and clear
stůj a řež,
[stop a bloodbath,]
Strike for love and strike for fear
strach z něj máš a necouvneš!
[fear of him and got necouvneš!]
There's beauty and there's danger here
V něm krása je, v něm číhá smrt.
[The beauty of it is, there lurks death.]
Split the ice apart
Dobře chraň to své,
[Well that's forbid,]
Beware the frozen heart
zlom srdce ledové!
[Heart break the ice!]
Come on, Sven.
Poběž, Svene!
[Come on, Sven!]
Elsa. Psst!
Elso.
[Elso.]
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
Vstávej, vstávej, vstávej!
[Get up, get up, get up!]
Anna, go back to sleep.
Anno, běž spinkat.
[Anna, go beddy.]
I just can't.
Ale já nemůžu.
[But I can not.]
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
Obloha nespí, já taky nespím.
[Sky sleeps, I do not sleep well.]
So, we have to play.
Chci si hrát.
[I want to play.]
Go play by yourself.
Běž si hrát sama!
[Go play alone!]
Do you want to build a snowman?
Postavíme sněhuláka?
[We build a snowman?]
Come on, come on, come on!
Honem, honem, honem!
[Hurry, hurry, hurry!]
Do the magic! Do the magic!
Čaruj! No tak čaruj!
[Čaruj! Well čaruj!]
Oh...
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
Můžu?
[Can I?]
This is amazing!
To je paráda!
[That's great!]
Watch this!
Koukej se.
[Look down.]
Hi, I'm Olaf, and I like warm hugs.
Ahoj, já jsem Olaf. A mám rád vřelá objetí.
[Hi, I'm Olaf. And I like a warm embrace.]
I love you, Olaf!
Jsi boží, Olafe.
[You are God, Olaf.]
Olaf...
Tickle bumps!
Kopečky.
[Scoops.]
Oh!
Hang on!
Pozor!
[Beware!]
Catch me!
Chyť mě!
[Catch me!]
Gotcha!
Mám tě.
[I have you.]
Again!
Ještě!
[Yet!]
Wait!
Počkej.
[Wait.]
- Whoo-hoo! - Slow down!
Zpomal!
[Slow down!]
Whoo!
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Anna!
Anno?
[Anna?]
Mama! Papa!
Mami, tati!
[Mom, Dad!]
No, no...
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
To nic, Anno. Jsem s tebou.
[It's okay, Anna. I'm with you.]
Elsa, what have you done?
Elso, co jsi to provedla?
[Elso, what have you done?]
This is getting out of hand.
Tohle už je příliš.
[This is too much.]
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
Já za to nemůžu. Promiň mi to, Anno.
[It is not my fault. Forgive me, Annie.]
Oh. She's ice cold.
Je tak chladná.
[It is so cold.]
I know where we have to go.
Já vím, co udělat.
[I know what to do.]
Ice?
Led?
[Led?]
Faster, Sven.
Přidej, Svene!
[Add, Sven!]
Sven!
Svene.
[Sven.]
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
Prosím, pomozte! Jde o mou dcerku.
[Please help! As for my daughter.]
It's the king.
To je král.
[That is king.]
Trolls?
Trollové?
[Trolls?]
Shush! I'm trying to listen.
Chci to slyšet.
[I want to hear it.]
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Jste sladcí. Vás si nechám.
[You are sweet. I'll keep.]
Your Majesty.
Veličenstvo.
[Majesty.]
Born with the powers, or cursed?
S magií narozena, či byla prokleta?
[The magic was born, and was cursed?]
Born. And they're getting stronger.
Narozena. A stále to sílí.
[Born. And it's still growing.]
Here, here.
Mohu?
[I can?]
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
Štěstí, že to není srdce.
[Lucky it's not the heart.]
The heart is not so easily changed.
Srdce se mění velice těžko.
[Heart change very difficult.]
But the head can be persuaded.
Ale hlavu lze přesvědčit.
[But the head can be persuaded.]
Do what you must.
Udělej, co je třeba.
[Do what's necessary.]
I recommend we remove all magic.
Doporučuji odstranit veškerou magii.
[I recommend to remove all magic.]
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
Včetně vzpomínek na ni. Pro jistotu.
[Including memories of her. For sure.]
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
Ale nebojte. Vše hezké zůstane.
[But do not worry. Everything stays nice.]
She will be okay.
Bude v pořádku.
[He's going to be ok.]
But she won't remember I have powers?
A zapomene i to, že umím kouzlit?
[And forget the fact that I can do magic?]
It's for the best.
Je to tak lepší.
[It's better that way.]
Listen to me, Elsa. Your power will only grow.
Poslouchej mě, Elso. Tvoje moc bude sílit.
[Listen to me, Elso. Your power will grow.]
There is beauty in it...
Je v ní mnoho krásy,
[It contains a lot of beauty,]
But also great danger.
ale i velkého nebezpečí.
[but also of great danger.]
You must learn to control it.
Musíš se ji naučit ovládat.
[You gotta learn to control it.]
Fear will be your enemy.
Strach bude tvůj nepřítel.
[Fear is your enemy.]
No!
Ne.
[No.]
We'll protect her.
My ji ochráníme.
[We will protect her.]
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
Naučí se to krotit, určitě.
[They learn to tame it, certainly.]
Until then...
A do té doby...
[Until then...]
We'll lock the gates.
...zavřeme brány.
[... close the gates.]
We'll reduce the staff.
Propustíme služebnictvo.
[We release servants.]
We will limit her contact with people,
Přestane se stýkat s lidmi
[Stop socializing with people]
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
a o její kouzelné moci nikomu neřekneme.
[and on her magical power will not tell anyone.]
Including Anna.
Ani Anně.
[Neither Anna.]
Elsa?
Elso?
[Elso?]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Ráda sněhuláky stavíš,
[Glad you build snowmen,]
Come on, let's go and play
tak pojď si se mnou hrát!
[so come play with me!]
I never see you any more
Já už tě skoro nevídám,
[I almost never see you anymore,]
Come out the door
a proč jsi tam?
[and why are you there?]
It's like you've gone away
To se tě musím ptát!
[That I have to ask!]
We used to be best buddies, and now we're not
Jsme vůbec ještě sestry, a nebo ne?
[We did not have sisters or not?]
I wish you would tell me why
Chci být s tebou napořád!
[I want to be with you forever!]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Ráda sněhuláky stavíš
[Glad you build snowmen]
It doesn't have to be a snowman
a mě i koulování baví.
[and I even enjoy a snowball fight.]
Go away, Anna.
Běž pryč, Anno.
[Go away, Anna.]
Okay, bye
No tak ne.
[Well, do not.]
The gloves will help.
Rukavice ti pomohou.
[The gloves will help you.]
See? Conceal it.
Vidíš? Co nevidíš...
[See? What you see...]
Don't feel it.
...to necítíš.
[... feel it.]
Don't let it show.
A nikdo nic neví.
[And nobody knows anything.]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Ráda sněhuláky stavíš
[Glad you build snowmen]
Or ride our bike around the halls?
a skvěle jezdíš po schodech!
[a great ride up the stairs!]
I think some company is overdue
Mně chybí, Elso, tvoje společnost.
[I miss, Elso, your company.]
I've started talking to the pictures on the walls
Už mluvím s obrazy na zaprášených zdech.
[I am speaking with dusty pictures on the walls.]
Hang in there, Joan.
Nespadni, Johanko.
[Do not fall, Joan.]
It gets a little lonely, all these empty rooms
A je mi tady smutno, někdy mám i strach
[And here I am sad, sometimes I even fear]
Just watching the hours tick by
v těch předlouhých minutách.
[in those předlouhých minutes.]
I'm scared.
Bojím se.
[I'm afraid.]
It's getting stronger!
Je to čím dál silnější.
[It's getting stronger.]
Getting upset only makes it worse. Calm down.
Rozčilování to jen zhoršuje. Uklidni se.
[Aggravation is only getting worse. Calm down.]
No! Don't touch me!
Ne! Nesahej na mě!
[No! Do not touch me!]
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
Prosím, nechci ti ublížit.
[Please, I do not want to hurt you.]
See you in two weeks!
Nashle za dva týdny.
[See you in two weeks.]
Do you have to go?
Musíte odjet?
[You have to go?]
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Neměj strach, Elso.
[Do not worry, Elso.]
Your Highness.
Elsa?
Elso?
[Elso?]
Please, I know you're in there
Vím, že jsi tam, vím to,
[I know you're there, I know,]
People are asking where you've been
lidi se ptávají, kde jsi.
[people with ptávají where you are.]
They say "Have courage", and I'm trying to
Prý ať jsem silná, a já snažím se,
[Apparently whatever I'm strong and I'm trying to]
I'm right out here for you
když vím, jak blízko jsme.
[I know how close we are.]
Just let me in
Kdo k tobě smí?
[Who is allowed to you?]
We only have each other; it's just you and me
Vždyť máme jedna druhou, samy jsme, my dvě.
[After all, we have each other, we own two of us.]
What are we gonna do?
Čeká nás spousta dnů.
[We have a lot of days.]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Ráda sněhuláky stavíš.
[Glad you build snowmen.]
.
O tři roky později
[Three years later]
All ashore!
Všichni na břeh!
[All ashore!]
Welcome to Arendelle!
Vítejte v Arendellu.
[Welcome Arendellu.]
Ahh, merci, monsieur.
Watch your step, please.
Pozor na nohy, prosím.
[Attention feet, please.]
The gates will be opening soon.
Za chvíli otevřou brány.
[For the moment opens its gates.]
Why do I have to wear this?
Proč se musím takhle strojit?
[Why do I dress like this?]
Because the queen has come of age.
Protože královna je už plnoletá
[Because the queen is already of age]
It's Coronation Day!
a bude mít korunovaci.
[and will have a coronation.]
That's not my fault.
Ale za to já nemůžu.
[But beyond that I can not.]
What do you want, Sven?
Copak bys rád, Svene?
[Do you like Sven?]
"Give me a snack."
Něco na zoubek.
[Something on the tooth.]
What's the magic word?
A co kouzelné slůvko?
[What's the magic word?]
"Please."
Prosím.
[Please.]
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
Poděl se.
[Share it.]
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
Nemůžu uvěřit, že konečně otevírají brány.
[I can not believe they finally opened the gates.]
And for a whole day! Faster, Percy!
A na celý dlouhý den. Pospěš, Percy!
[And all day long. Hurry, Percy!]
Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
Arendelle, náš nejzáhadnější obchodní partner.
[Arendelle our most mysterious business partner.]
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets and exploit your riches.
Otevřete brány, abych odhalil vaše tajemství a obral vás o peníze.
[Open the gates to reveal your secrets and rob you of money.]
Did I say that out loud?
Že já to řekl nahlas?
[That you say that out loud?]
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait to see the queen and the princess.
Už se nemůžu dočkat, až uvidím královnu a princeznu.
[I can not wait to see the queen and princess.]
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
Určitě jsou to obě krasavice.
[Certainly they are both beautiful.]
I bet they are beautiful.
Vsaď se, že budou nádherné.
[I bet that will be wonderful.]
Princess Anna?
Princezno Anno?
[Princess Anne?]
Huh? Yeah?
Jo?
[Yeah?]
Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
Nerad vás budím, madam...
[I hate to wake you, ma'am...]
No, no, no, you didn't.
Ne, ne, nespím.
[No, no, I do not sleep.]
I've been up for hours.
Už jsem dávno vzhůru.
[I've long since up.]
Who is it?
Kdo je tam?
[Who is there?]
Still me, ma'am.
To jsem stále já, madam.
[I'm still me, ma'am.]
The gates will open soon. Time to get ready.
Otevíráme brány. Musíte se ustrojit.
[We open the gate. You have to be dressed.]
Of course.
Ovšem.
[Of course.]
Ready for what?
Ustrojit na co?
[Ustrojit for what?]
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
Na korunovaci vaší sestry, madam.
[The coronation of your sisters, ma'am.]
My sister's corneration.
Moje sestra má renovaci.
[My sister has a renovation.]
It's Coronation Day!
Dnes je korunovace.
[Today's coronation.]
It's Coronation Day!
Dnes je korunovace!
[Today's coronation!]
The window is open!
Okna a dveře...
[Windows and doors...]
So's that door!
...dokořán!
[... wide!]
I didn't know they did that any more
Kdy bylo to tak, marně vzpomínám!
[When it was so vain I remember!]
Who knew we owned 8,000 salad plates?
Kdo viděl osm tisíc talířů?
[Who saw eight thousand plates?]
For years I've roamed these empty halls
Můj křik se prázdnou chodbou nes',
[My screams empty corridor nes']
Why have a ballroom with no balls?
k čemu je sál, když není ples?
[what is the hall when no ball?]
Finally, they're opening up the gates!
Otevřem teď brány kejklířům!
[Now open the gates jugglers!]
There'll be actual, real, live people
Přijdou lidé opravdoví,
[People come true,]
It'll be totally strange
to bude nezvyklá věc!
[It will be an unusual thing!]
But wow! Am I so ready for this change!
Ty změny dnešek změní v blázinec!
[These changes tonight turns into a madhouse!]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Je to tu právě teď, tak krásné,
[It's here right now, so beautiful,]
There'll be music, there'll be light
samá hudba, světel zář!
[same music, lights glow!]
For the first time in forever
A všem právě teď jak hvězdám
[And all now how stars]
I'll be dancing through the night
budou v tanci tváře plát!
[they dance cheek plate!]
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
Jsem vzrušená a bolí mě tady,
[I'm excited and hurt me here,]
But I'm somewhere in that zone
asi shoří hlava má!
[probably burn my head!]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Vždyť svět mi právě teď jak švihák
[For the world to me right now as a dandy]
I won't be alone
ruku podává.
[hand made.]
I can't wait to meet everyone!
Už se těším, až každého poznám.
[I look forward to everyone I know.]
What if I meet The One?
Možná potkám i toho pravého.
[Maybe even I meet Mr. Right.]
Tonight, imagine me gown and all
Dnes poprvé hezky v parádě...
[Today, for the first time in the parade nicely...]
Fetchingly draped against the wall
šarmantně o zeď opřená
[charmingly leaning against the wall]
The picture of sophisticated grace
se změním v krásku se vší noblesou!
[will turn into a beauty with all the nobility!]
I suddenly see him standing there
Pak zničehonic mě osloví
[Then suddenly I appeal]
A beautiful stranger, tall and fair
ten krasavec plavý ze snů mých
[the blond beauty of my dreams]
I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face!
ať pralinky hned slepí pusu mou!
[whether pralines immediately bonded kiss me!]
But then we laugh and talk all evening
A pak se tomu zasmějeme,
[And then we would laugh,]
Which is totally bizarre
prokecáme celý bál!
[prokecáme all scared!]
Nothing like the life I've led so far
Život půjde jinak dál a dál!
[Otherwise life will go on and on!]
For the first time in forever
Vím, že právě teď a navždy
[I know that now and forever]
There'll be magic, there'll be fun
malá kouzla nadchnou nás.
[Small charms enchant us.]
For the first time in forever
Vím, že právě teď mi každý
[I know that right now my every]
I could be noticed by someone
chce šeptat: Hledám právě vás!
[I want to whisper, looking for you!]
And I know it is totally crazy
Vím, že opravdu šíleně zní to,
[I know it sounds really crazy,]
To dream I'd find romance
hned lásky dar si přát!
[just love the gift you wish!]
But for the first time in forever
Já ale právě teď jsem šťastná,
[But right now I'm happy,]
At least I've got a chance!
smím srdci šanci dát.
[I may give the heart a chance.]
Don't let them in
Kdo přijde dnes,
[Who arrives today]
Don't let them see
má uvěřit,
[He has to believe]
Be the good girl you always have to be
že jsem dívkou, jakou jsem měla být.
[I'm a girl, I'd be.]
Conceal, don't feel
Skrývej city,
[Of hiding emotions,]
Put on a show
je to jen hra!
[its only a game!]
Make one wrong move and everyone will know
Jen chybný krok a hra by propadla!
[Only misstep, and the game would fail!]
But it's only for today
Ale bude to jen dnes.
[But it will be just today.]
It's only for today
A bude to jen dnes!
[And it's just today!]
It's agony to wait
Kdo čekání má snést?
[Who should bear the wait?]
It's agony to wait
Kdo čekání má snést?
[Who should bear the wait?]
Tell the guards to open up
Stráže, brány otevřte!
[Guards, gates open!]
The gate
Ať zvou!
[Whether invite!]
The gate
Ať zvou!
[Whether invite!]
For the first time in forever
Je tu právě teď ta chvíle...
[It's now the moment...]
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Kdo přijde dnes, má uvěřit...
[Whoever comes today, has to believe...]
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of
kdy sny mé pravdou stanou se!
[where my dreams become true!]
Be the good girl you always have to be
že jsem dívkou, jakou jsem měla být.
[I'm a girl, I'd be.]
A chance to change my lonely world
Mám šanci s láskou měnit svět...
[I have the chance to change the world with love...]
Conceal
Skrývej.
[Of hiding.]
A chance to find true love
...s tou pravou láskou svou.
[... with the true love of mine.]
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Jen skrývej city, všichni lžou.
[Only of hiding emotions, everybody lies.]
I know it all ends tomorrow
A zítra už bude pozdě,
[And tomorrow will be too late,]
So it has to be today!
všechno stát se musí dnes!
[all happen to be today!]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Vždyť mně je právě teď tak sladce!
[For me right now is so sweet!]
For the first time in forever
Srdce právě teď mě k lásce
[Now my heart to love]
Nothing's in my way!
cestou svou má vést.
[on his way to lead.]
Hey!
Au!
[Ouch!]
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Omlouvám se, není vám nic?
[I'm sorry, are you all right?]
Hey.
Jéje...
[Uh oh...]
Uh... No, no, I'm okay.
Ne, jsem v pořádku.
[No, I'm fine.]
Are you sure?
Opravdu?
[Really?]
Yeah. I just wasn't looking where I was going.
Ano. Nekoukala jsem na cestu.
[Yes. I was not looking at the road.]
But I'm great, actually.
Nic mi není. Opravdu.
[It's nothing. Really.]
Oh... Thank goodness.
Díkybohu.
[Thank God.]
Oh! Uh...
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Princ Hans z Jižních ostrovů.
[Prince Hans of South Island.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Princezna Anna z Arendellu.
[Princess Anna Arendellu.]
"Princess"? My Lady.
Princezna? Má paní.
[Princess? My lady.]
Oh!
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Um... Whew.
Hi. Again.
Ahoj. Zase.
[Hey. Again.]
Oh, boy!
Propána.
[For Mr.]
This is awkward.
To je trapné.
[That is embarrassing.]
Not "You're awkward", but just because we're...
Ne že vy jste trapný.
[Not that you're lame.]
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous. Wait, what?
To já jsem trapná. Vy jste fešák. To je co?
[That I'm embarrassing. You're handsome. What is that?]
I'd like to formally apologize
Rád bych se omluvil za to, že můj kůň
[I would like to apologize for the fact that my horse]
for hitting the princess of Arendelle with my horse.
srazil princeznu z Arendellu,
[Princess knocked out Arendellu,]
And for every moment after.
a za vše, co se dělo poté.
[and for everything that happened then.]
No! No, no. It's fine.
Ne! To nic.
[No! Nothing.]
I'm not that princess.
Taková princezna nejsem.
[That I'm not a princess.]
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
Kdybyste srazil mou sestru,
[If you hit my sister,]
it would be... Yeesh!
to by bylo...
[It would be...]
Because, you know...
Poněvadž...
[Because...]
Hello.
Ahoj.
[Hey.]
But, lucky you,
Ale naštěstí...
[But fortunately...]
It's just me.
...jsem to byla jen já.
[... I was just me.]
"Just" you?
Jen vy?
[You only?]
The bells. The coronation.
Zvony. Korunovace.
[Bells. Coronation.]
I better go.
Musím jít.
[I have to go.]
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Už musím jít. Radši už půjdu.
[I have to go. I better be going.]
Bye!
Pa.
[Pa.]
Oh, no. Oh!
To ne.
[Not that.]
Your Majesty, the gloves.
Vaše Výsosti, ty rukavice.
[Your Highness, those gloves.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
...královna Elsa Arendellská.
[... Queen Elsa Arendellská.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
Královna Elsa Arendellská!
[Queen Elsa Arendellská!]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
Královna Elsa Arendellská.
[Queen Elsa Arendellská.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Princezna Anna Arendellská.
[Princess Anne Arendellská.]
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Sem? Určitě?
[Here? You sure?]
Because I don't think I'm supposed to...
Nejsem si jistá.
[I'm not sure.]
Oh. Okay.
Tak jo.
[So yeah.]
Hi.
Ahoj.
[Hey.]
"Hi" me? Oh...
To je na mě?
[This is for me?]
Um... Hi.
Ahoj.
[Hey.]
You look beautiful.
Překypuješ krásou.
[Překypuješ beauty.]
Thank you. You look beautiful-ler.
Díky. Ty taky překypuješ.
[Thanks. You too překypuješ.]
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
Tedy ne že jsi tlustá,
[Not that you're fat,]
But more beautiful.
myslím, jako že jsi moc hezká.
[I like that you're too nice.]
Thank you.
Děkuji.
[Thank you.]
So...
Aha.
[I see.]
This is what a party looks like.
Takhle vypadá královský bál.
[He looks like a royal ball.]
It's warmer than I thought.
Je tu nějak moc teplo.
[There's too much heat.]
What is that amazing smell?
Co je to za úžasnou vůni?
[What is that wonderful smell?]
Chocolate.
Čokoláda.
[Chocolate.]
Your Majesty.
Vaše Výsosti...
[Your Highness...]
The Duke of Weaseltown.
Vévoda z Kradákova.
[Duke of Kradákova.]
"Weselton"! Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
"Kravákova"! Vévoda z Kravákova, Vaše Výsosti.
[" Kravákova"! Duke of Kravákova, Your Highness.]
As your closest partner in trade it seems only fitting
Jsem váš nejbližší obchodní partner, a tak se jistě sluší,
[I'm your closest trading partner, so it certainly behooves]
that I offer you your first dance as queen.
abych vás vyzval k tanci jako první.
[I invite you to dance first.]
One-two, and jump.
Raz, dva, a hop.
[One, two, and hop.]
Uh...
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
Děkuji vám. Bohužel netančím.
[Thank you. Unfortunately dance.]
Oh...
But my sister does.
Ale má sestra ano.
[But my sister did.]
What? - Oh! Lucky you.
Cože? - Máte štěstí.
[What? - You're lucky.]
Oh, I don't think...
Já myslím, že...
[I think that...]
If you swoon, let me know. I'll catch you.
Kdybyste omdlévala, dejte vědět, chytím vás.
[If you faint, let me know, I'll catch you.]
Sorry.
Promiň.
[Sorry.]
Like an agile peacock.
Umím tančit jako páv.
[I can dance like a peacock.]
Ow! Ow.
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
Mimochodem, je skvělé, že jste otevřeli brány.
[Anyway, it's great that you've opened the gates.]
Why did they shut them in the first place?
Proč byly vůbec zavřené?
[Why were not closed?]
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
Víte, z jakého důvodu?
[Do you know why?]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
All right. Hang on!
Dobrá. Držte se.
[All right. Brace yourself.]
They don't call me the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
Neříkají mi "Splašený špunt" pro nic za nic.
[They do not call me" Crazy stopper" for nothing.]
Oh-ho!
Like a chicken with the face of a monkey, I fly.
Jsem jako kohout s tváří opice. Létám.
[I like cock -faced monkeys. I'm flying.]
Let me know when you're ready
Dejte mi vědět,
[Let me know,]
for another round, Milady.
až se budete cítit na další kolo.
[when you feel the next round.]
Well, he was sprightly.
To je ale čipera.
[But this is nimbler.]
Especially for a man in heels.
A to má ještě boty s kramfleky.
[And he has even shoes with heel.]
Are you okay?
Jsi celá?
[You all right?]
I've never been better. This is so nice.
Nikdy mi nebylo lépe. Je to nádhera.
[Never better. It's beautiful.]
I wish it could be like this all the time.
Chtěla bych, aby to tak bylo napořád.
[I want to be like that forever.]
Me, too.
Já také.
[I also.]
But it can't.
Ale nejde to.
[But I can not.]
Why not? - It just can't.
Proč ne? - Prostě to nejde.
[Why not? - I just can not.]
Excuse me for a minute.
Omluv mne na moment.
[Excuse me for a moment.]
I'd be honored.
Glad I caught you.
Tak jsem vás chytil.
[I caught you.]
Hans.
Hansi.
[Hansi.]
I often had a whole parlor to myself to slide!
Rozběhla jsem se chodbou a klouzala dál.
[I ran down the hall and slid away.]
Oops!
Sorry.
Pardon.
[Sorry.]
Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
Ještěže na to máš postavu.
[Luckily it got character.]
Ah.
What's this?
Co je tohle?
[What is this?]
Uh, I was born with it.
To mám od narození.
[I have it from birth.]
Although, I dreamed I was kissed by a troll.
I když se mi kdysi zdálo, že mě políbil troll.
[Although I once dreamed that I kissed a troll.]
I like it.
Moc hezké.
[Very nice.]
Yeah, the whole thing.
Ano, sněz to celé.
[Yes, eat it whole.]
You got it.
Dokázals to.
[You did it.]
Okay, wait, wait. So, you have how many brothers?
Takže počkej. Kolik že máš bratrů?
[So wait. How many brothers do you have that?]
Twelve older brothers.
Dvanáct, všichni jsou starší.
[Twelve, they're all older.]
Three of them pretended I was invisible, literally, for two years.
Tři z nich se dva roky tvářili, že vůbec neexistuju.
[Three of them for two years pretended not exist at all.]
That's horrible.
To je příšerné.
[This is horrible.]
It's what brothers do.
To už bratři dělávají.
[That's brothers do.]
And sisters.
I sestry.
[Even nurses.]
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
Jako malé jsme si byly s Elsou blízké,
[As a small, we were Elsa loved ones]
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
ale pak mi zavřela dveře před nosem
[but then he closed the door in his face]
and I never knew why.
a já ani nevím proč.
[and I do not know why.]
I would never shut you out.
To já bych nikdy neudělal.
[That I would never do that.]
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
Můžu říct něco bláznivého?
[Can I say something crazy?]
I love crazy.
Mám rád blázniviny.
[I like crazy.]
All my life has been a series of doors in my face
Život vždycky dveřmi před nosem práskne mi hned,
[Life always slam the door in my face me now,]
And then suddenly I bump into you
a dnes najednou dveřmi vejdeš ty.
[and now all of a sudden you walk through the door you are.]
I was thinking the same thing, because, like...
Přesně to mě napadlo, protože...
[That's exactly what I thought, because...]
I've been searching my whole life to find my own place
Chci mít taky svoje místo, hledám svůj svět!
[I want to take my place, too, seeking your world!]
And maybe it's the party talking, or the chocolate fondue
A možná oslavou jsem zmámen, a tím sladkým fondue.
[And maybe I was a celebration of stupor, and the sweet fondue.]
But with you
S tebou já...
[With you I...]
But with you I found my place
S tebou já už vím, kým jsem!
[With you I already know who I am!]
I see your face
...jen divím se!
[I wonder... just!]
And it's nothing like I've ever known before
Dveře dokořán a napořád, se zdá,
[Doors open and forever, it seems,]
Love is an open door!
otevře láska má!
[Love has opened!]
Love is an open door!
Otevře láska má!
[Love has opened!]
Love is an open door
Otevře láska má!
[Love has opened!]
With you
S tebou!
[With you!]
Love is an open door
Otevře láska má!
[Love has opened!]
I mean, it's crazy
Ty dopovíš to...
[They dopovíš it...]
What?
Co?
[What?]
We finish each other's
No to co jsem nakous'.
[Well, what I nakous'.]
Sandwiches
Sendviče!
[Sandwiches!]
That's what I was gonna say!
Přesně to chci říct!
[That's exactly what I mean!]
I've never met someone
Ne, neznám nikoho,
[No, you do not know anyone,]
Who thinks so much like me
kdo přemýšlí jak já!
[who thinks as I do!]
Jinx! Jinx again!
Trefa. A zase!
[Fluke. And again!]
Our mental synchronization
Jsme dvojčata, mozek jeden,
[We're twins, one brain,]
Can have but one explanation
a na stejné lodi jedem,
[and in the same boat poison]
You and I were just meant to be
Ty a já jsme vjednom dva.
[You and I are in one and two.]
Say goodbye
Sbohem dám
[goodbye to give]
To the pain of the past
minulým bolestem,
[past pain,]
We don't have to feel it anymore
zamčené tvé dveře, jak se zdá,
[locked your door, it seems,]
Love is an open door
otevře láska má.
[Love has opened.]
Love is an open door!
Otevře láska má.
[Love has opened.]
Life can be so much more
Otevře láska má!
[Love has opened!]
With you
S tebou!
[With you!]
Love is an open
Otevře láska
[opens love]
Door
má!
[It has!]
Can I say something crazy?
Můžu říct něco bláznivého?
[Can I say something crazy?]
Will you marry me?
Vzala by sis mě?
[Would you married me?]
Can I say something even crazier?
Můžu říct něco ještě bláznivějšího?
[I can say anything more foolish?]
Yes!
Ano.
[Yes.]
Coming through. Excuse me. Oh...
Pardon. Sorry. Oh!
Pardon.
[Sorry.]
Can we just get around you there?
Mohli bychom se protáhnout?
[We could stretch?]
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Děkuji. Tamhle je.
[Thank you. There it is.]
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
Chci říct... královno. To jsem zase já.
[I mean... queen. It's me again.]
May I present Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Smím ti představit prince Hanse z Jižních ostrovů?
[May I introduce Prince Hans of South Island?]
Your Majesty.
Vaše Výsosti.
[Your Highness.]
We would like...
Chceme požádat...
[We want to ask...]
Uh, your blessing...
...o požehnání...
[... a blessing...]
Of our marriage.
...našeho sňatku.
[... our marriage.]
Marriage? - Yes!
Sňatku? - Ano!
[Marriage? - Yes!]
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Promiňte, ale nechápu.
[Sorry, but I do not understand.]
Well, we haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
Podrobnosti jsme zatím příliš neřešili.
[Details are still too tackling.]
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
Naplánovat ceremoniál bude chvíli trvat,
[Plan the ceremony will take time]
Of course, we'll have soup, roast, and ice cream. And then...
ale určitě bude pečeně a zmrzlina a pak...
[but certainly will be roast and ice cream, and then...]
Wait. Would we live here?
Počkat. Budeme žít tady?
[Wait. We live here?]
Here? - Absolutely!
Tady? - Samo sebou.
[Here? - By itself.]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Oh! We can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us.
Pozveme všech tvých dvanáct bratrů, aby tu žili s námi.
[We invite all your twelve brothers to live here with us.]
What? No, no, no.
Ne.
[No.]
Of course we have the room......
Místa je tu všude dost.
[Place there abound.]
Wait, slow down. No one's brothers are staying here.
Počkejte. Zpomalte. Ničí bratři tu bydlet nebudou
[Wait. Slow down. Destroys brothers live here do not]
No one is getting married.
a nebude ani žádná svatba.
[and will not be no wedding.]
Wait, what?
Cože?
[What?]
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
Můžu s tebou mluvit, prosím? O samotě.
[Can I talk to you, please? Alone.]
No. Whatever you have to say, you can say to both of us.
Ne. Chceš-li mi něco říct, řekni nám to oběma.
[No. If you want to tell me something, tell us both.]
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
Fajn. Nemůžeš si vzít někoho, koho sotva znáš.
[Fine. You can not marry someone you hardly know.]
You can if it's true love.
Můžeš, když ho miluješ.
[You can, if you loved him.]
Anna, what do you know about true love?
Anno, co ty víš o pravé lásce?
[Anna, what do you know about true love?]
More than you.
Víc než ty.
[More than you.]
All you know is how to shut people out.
Jediné, co umíš, je uzavírat se před lidmi.
[The only thing you can do is to conclude from the people.]
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
Žádáte mě o požehnání, ale já vám ho nedám.
[You're asking me a blessing, but I will not give it to you.]
Now, excuse me.
Ne, je mi líto.
[No, I'm sorry.]
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
Vaše Výsosti, mohu-li dodat...
[Your Highness, I might add...]
No, you may not. And I think you should go.
Ne, nemůžete. A měl byste odejít.
[No you can not. And you should go.]
The party is over. Close the gates.
Slavnost končí. Zavřete brány.
[Celebration ends. Close the gates.]
Yes, Your Majesty.
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
Elso, ne. Počkej!
[Elso, no. Wait!]
Give me my glove!
Vrať mi tu rukavici.
[Give me the glove.]
Elsa, please, please.
Elso, prosím.
[Elso, please.]
I can't live like this anymore!
Já už takhle dál žít nechci.
[I no longer want to live like this anymore.]
Then leave.
Tak odejdi.
[Then leave.]
What did I ever do to you?
Co jsem ti kdy udělala?
[What have I ever done?]
Enough, Anna.
To stačí, Anno.
[That's enough, Annie.]
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
Proč jsi ke mně tak chladná?
[Why are you so cold to me?]
Why do you shut the world out?
Proč jsi tak chladná ke světu?
[Why are you so cold to the world?]
What are you so afraid of?
Čeho se pořád bojíš?
[What are you still afraid?]
I said, enough!
Řekla jsem, že stačí!
[I said that's enough!]
Sorcery.
Čáry.
[Lines.]
I knew there was something dubious going on here.
Já věděl od začátku, že tu něco neštymuje.
[I knew from the beginning that something neštymuje.]
Elsa.
Elso?
[Elso?]
There she is!
To je ona!
[That is her!]
Yes! It is her!
Ano! To je ona!
[Yes! That is her!]
Queen Elsa.
Královno Elso.
[Queen Elso.]
Our beautiful queen!
Naše překrásná královna!
[Our beautiful queen!]
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
Vaše Výsosti, jste v pořádku?
[Your Highness, are you okay?]
No.
There she is! Stop her!
Tamhle je! Chyťte ji!
[There it is! Get her!]
Please, just stay away from me. Stay away.
Prosím vás, nepřibližujte se. Jděte pryč!
[Please, stay away. Go away!]
Monster. Monster!
Monstrum. Monstrum!
[Monster. Monster!]
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
Wait, please!
Počkej, prosím!
[Wait please!]
Elsa, stop!
Elso, stůj!
[Elso, stop!]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
The fjord.
Váš fjord.
[Your fjord.]
Snow! Snow?
Sněží! Sněží?
[Snowing! Snowing?]
Yes, snow.
Are you all right? - No.
Jsi v pořádku? - Ne.
[Are you okay? - No.]
Did you know?
Věděla jsi to?
[Did you know that?]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
Ono sněží. Sněží!
[It snows. Snowing!]
The queen has cursed this land!
Královna proklela svoji zem!
[Queen cursed my country!]
She must be stopped! You have to go after her.
Musíme ji zastavit. Musíte ji zneškodnit.
[We have to stop her. You have to defuse it.]
Wait, no!
Počkat, ne.
[Wait, no.]
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
Vy jste taky čarodějnice?
[You're a witch, too?]
Are you a monster, too?
A monstrum jako ona?
[A monster like her?]
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
Ne. Já jsem úplně obyčejná.
[No. I totally ordinary.]
That's right, she is.
Přesně, obyčejná.
[Exactly common.]
In the best way.
Myslím to v dobrém.
[I mean that in a good way.]
And my sister is not a monster.
Má sestra není monstrum.
[My sister is a monster.]
She nearly killed me!
Málem mě zabila!
[He almost killed me!]
You slipped on ice. - Her ice.
Uklouzl jste na ledu. - Na jejím.
[You slipped on ice. - On her.]
It was an accident. She was scared.
Byla to nehoda. Byla vyděšená.
[It was an accident. She was terrified.]
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this.
Nechtěla to udělat, nic takového neplánovala.
[She did not do it, did not plan anything like that.]
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
Byla to moje chyba. Já ji vyprovokovala.
[It was my fault. I provoked her.]
So, I'm the one
A budu to já,
[And it will be me,]
that needs to go after her.
kdo za ní pojede.
[Who will go for it.]
Bring me my horse, please.
Vyveďte mi koně, prosím.
[Bring me a horse, please.]
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
Anno, ne. Je to nebezpečné.
[Anna, do not. Its dangerous.]
Elsa's not dangerous.
Elsa není nebezpečná.
[Elsa is not dangerous.]
I'll bring her back, and I'll make this right.
Přivedu ji zpět a vše napravíme.
[I bring it back and fix everything.]
I'm coming with you.
Pojedu s tebou.
[I'll go with you.]
No, I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
Ne. Zůstaneš tady a postaráš se o Arendelle.
[No. You stay here and take care about Arendelle.]
On my honor.
Spolehni se.
[Count on it.]
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Nyní tu bude vládnout princ Hans.
[Now there will reign Prince Hans.]
Are you sure you can trust her?
Víš jistě, že jí můžeš věřit?
[You sure he can trust her?]
I don't want you getting hurt.
Nechci, aby ti někdo ublížil.
[I do not want anyone hurt.]
She's my sister.
Je to má sestra.
[It's my sister.]
She would never hurt me.
Mně by neublížila.
[It would not hurt.]
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Na vrcholchích v noci panuje sníh,
The snow rules on the hilltops at night,
not a footprint to be seen
ani stopa po lidech
A kingdom of isolation,
Ta samota královstvím je,
The loneliness of the kingdom in which
and it looks like I'm the queen
královnou jsem vloček všech
I am the queen of all the snowflakes
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Už kvílí vítr a hřmí bouře v srdci mém
The wind is howling and the storm is thundering in my heart
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Zlobu vyšeptám v tichu mrazivém
I'll whisper out my anger in the chilling silence
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Já byla v zámku vězněná
I was trapped in a castle
Be the good girl you always had to be
skrývej city, buď skříňka zamčená,
hide your feelings, be a locked box
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
To táta chtěl, ty dny pryč jsou
That's what my dad wanted, those days are gone
Well, now they know!
Svět zná tvář mou!
The world knows my face!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
Can't hold it back any more!
chci skončit s tou hloupou hrou
I want to end the stupid game
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
Turn away and slam the door!
dveřmi prásknu za sebou
I'll slam the door behind myself
I don't care what they're going to say
Já jsem svá, to chci dokázat všem
I'm myself, I want to prove that to everyone
Let the storm rage on
V bouři rozkvétám
I'm blooming in the storm
The cold never bothered me anyway.
a mráz v duši vítězí nad sluncem.
And the cold in my soul wins over the sun.
It's funny how some distance
Je zvláštní jak z té dálky,
It's funny how from the distance,
Makes everything seem small
se všechno menší zdá
everything seems smaller
And the fears that once controlled me
I ten strach co ve mně vládnul
Even the fear that once controlled me
Can't get to me at all!
je loutka bezmocná!
is a helpless puppet!
It's time to see what I can do
Jen vyzkouším, jak mocná jsem
I'll just try how powerful I am
To test the limits and break through
A k výšinám mě zvedne zem
And the ground will raise me to heights
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
V své říši bez konce chci žít
I want to live forever in my kingdom
I'm free!
klid mít!
in peace!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
I am one with the wind and sky
volná jsem, kráčím oblohou
I am free, I'm walking through the sky
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
You'll never see me cry
mé slzy šperkem jsou
my tears are my jewelry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Já jsem svá, jsem hráč i rváč
I'm myself, I'm both the player and the fighter
Let the storm rage on...
V bouři rozkvétám...
I'm blooming in the storm...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Moc má se vzduchem vznáší v proudu neznámém
My power is floating through the air in an unknown flow
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A chladná duše září v krystalcích jak diadém
And the cold soul is shining in the crystals like a tiara
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Mé myšlenky se tříští, jedna smysl má
My thoughts are fragmented, only one makes sense
I'm never going back
Je pasé minulost,
The past is passé,
The past is in the past!
když svítat začíná!
when it begins to dawn!
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
úsvit dává mi sílu svou
the dawn is giving me its power
Let it go, let it go!
Najednou, najednou!
Suddenly, suddenly!
That perfect girl is gone
už nejsem dívenkou
I'm not a little girl any more
Here I stand in the light of day
Já jsem svá, křídla má hlas můj
I'm myself, my voice has wings
Let the storm rage on!
V bouři rozkvétám!
I'm blooming in the storm!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Chci žít v zimě bez konce život svůj.
I want to live my life in the endless winter.
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
Elsa!
Elso!
[Elso!]
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
Elso, to jsem já, Anna.
[Elso, I'm me, Anna.]
your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
Tvá sestra, která nechtěla, abys kvůli ní zmrazila léto.
[Your sister, who did not want you because it froze the summer.]
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
Omlouvám se, je to moje chyba.
[I'm sorry, it's my fault.]
Of course, none of it would have happened
Nic z toho by se nestalo,
[None of this would have happened,]
if she had just told me her secret.
kdyby mi řekla o svém tajemství.
[He had told me about his secret.]
She's a stinker.
Tajnůstkářka jedna.
[Secretive one.]
Whoa!
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
Ne, ne, ne. Vrať se!
[No no no. Come back!]
No, no, no!
Ne, ne, ne!
[No no no!]
Okay.
Tak fajn.
[OK.]
Snow. It had to be snow.
Sníh. Musel to být zrovna sníh.
[Snow. It had to be just snow.]
She couldn't have had tropical magic
Že nemohla mít tropická kouzla.
[That could be a tropical charm.]
that covered the fjords in white sand and warm...
Fjordy by zasypal bílý písek a hřál by nás teplý...
[Fjords would be covered in white sand and warm against us warm...]
Fire!
...oheň.
[... fire.]
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
Studí, studí, studí.
[Studi, shame, shame.]
"Wandering Oaken's Trading Post".
"Obchodní stanice Potulného Oakena."
["Commercial stations Oaken The wandering."]
Ooh. "And sauna"!
"A sauna."
[" A sauna."]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
Mám letní výprodej.
[I have a summer sale.]
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
Dám slevu na plavky, dřeváky
[I will give discount for swimwear, clogs]
and a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
a opalovací krém vlastní výroby, ja?
[and sunscreen own production, ja?]
Oh. Great. For now, um, how about boots?
Bezva. Ale nemáte spíš boty?
[Cool. But you have more shoes?]
Winter boots? And dresses?
Sněhule? A kožichy?
[Snowboots? A fur coats?]
That would be in our winter department.
Zkuste naše zimní oddělení.
[Try our winter Department.]
Oh. Um...
I was just wondering.
Řekněte mi...
[Tell me...]
Has another young woman...
Neprošla tudy ještě jiná
[Undergone yet another way]
The queen perhaps, I don't know,
mladá žena, třeba královna...
[A young woman, perhaps a queen...]
passed through here?
nebo tak něco?
[or something like that?]
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm
Jediný šílenec, který se toulá v bouři,
[Only a madman who wanders in the storm,]
is you, dear.
jste vy.
[you.]
You and this fellow.
A tenhle chlapík.
[And this guy.]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
Mám letní výprodej.
[I have a summer sale.]
Carrots.
Mrkve.
[Carrots.]
Huh?
Behind you.
Za tebou.
[Behind you.]
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Jistě. Promiň.
[Sure. Sorry.]
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
To je ale sibérie, že?
[But this is Siberia that?]
Wherever could it be coming from?
Odkud se to asi bere?
[Where it probably takes?]
The North Mountain.
Od Severní hory.
[From the northern mountains.]
North Mountain.
Severní hora.
[North Mountain.]
That will be forty.
To je za čtyřicet.
[That is forty.]
Forty? No, ten.
Cože? Ne, deset.
[What? No, ten.]
Oh, dear, that's no good.
Ne, to nepůjde.
[No, it's not.]
See, this is from our winter stock,
Co udeřily ty mrazy,
[What struck you frosts,]
where supply and demand have a big problem.
nabídka pokulhává za poptávkou.
[supply lagging behind demand.]
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
Chcete mi vykládat o poptávce?
[Want to tell me about demand?]
I sell ice for a living.
Já se živím prodejem ledu.
[I am a living by selling ice.]
Ooh. That's a rough business to be in right now.
To teď není nejlepší obchod.
[This is not the best deal.]
I mean, that is really...
Chci říct, že to je...
[I mean, it's...]
That's unfortunate.
To je nepříjemné.
[That's annoying.]
Still forty.
Čtyřicet.
[Forty.]
But I will throw in a visit to Oaken's sauna.
Ale přidám vám vstup do Oakenovy sauny.
[But add your entry to Oakenovy sauna.]
Hoo-hoo. Hi, family.
Ahoj, rodino.
[Hello, family.]
Hoo-hoo!
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
Mám jen deset. Mějte rozum.
[I have only ten. Grow up.]
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
Dobrá. Za deset dám jen tohle.
[All right. In ten I give you just that.]
Okay, just tell me one thing.
Chci něco vědět.
[I want to know something.]
What was happening on the North Mountain?
Co se děje na Severní hoře?
[What is happening in North Mount?]
Did it seem magical?
Nějaká magie?
[Some kind of magic?]
Yes!
Jo.
[Yeah.]
Now, back up while I deal with this crook, here.
A teď ustup. Vyřídím si to s tím lumpem.
[Now stand back. I will deal with this villain.]
What did you call me?
Jak jsi mě to nazval?
[How did you call me?]
Okay, okay. I'm out.
No jo!
[Oh yeah!]
Whoa!
Bye-bye.
Nashle!
[Bye!]
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
Ne, Svene, mrkve jsem nedostal.
[No, Sven, I got carrots.]
But I did find us a place to sleep.
Ale našel jsem nám přespání.
[But I found us sleeping.]
And it's free.
A zadarmo.
[And free.]
I'm sorry about this violence.
Za to násilí se omlouvám.
[For that I apologize violence.]
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
Přidám vám pár slanečků
[I'll add you a few herring]
so we have good feelings.
jako odškodnění.
[as compensation.]
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
Takže jen kožich a boty, ja?
[So a fur coat and boots, ja?]
Uh...
Reindeers are better than people
Sobi jsou lepší než lidi.
[Reindeer are better than people.]
Sven, don't you think that's true?
Že, Svene, pravdu mám?
[That, Sven, I'm right?]
"Yeah, people will beat you and curse you and cheat you"
Jo, lidi tě bijou a proklínaj', šidí.
[Yeah, they beat people and proklínaj' cheating.]
"Every one of them's bad, except you!"
Tebe nemyslím, dyť tě znám!
[I do not think, Why, you know!]
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
Díky, kámo.
[Thanks, buddy.]
But people smell better than reindeers
Však lidi líp voní než sobi.
[However, people smell better than reindeer.]
Sven, don't you think I'm right?
V tom, Svene, mám pravdu já!
[In fact, Sven, I'm right!]
"That's once again true, for all except you!"
Jo, jenomže ty v tom výjimkou jsi!
[Yeah, but those in it except you!]
You got me! Let's call it a night.
No teda! Tak snad dobrou noc!
[Whoops! So perhaps a good night!]
"Good night"
'Brou noc!
[' Brou night!]
Don't let the frostbite
Pojď, když k nám sen spad',
[Come join us as a dream fallout']
Bite
spát.
[sleep.]
Nice duet.
Pěkný duet.
[Nice duet.]
It's just you. What do you want?
To jsi ty? Co tu chceš?
[It's you? What do you want?]
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
Chci, abys mě vzal na Severní horu.
[I want you to take me to the North Mountain.]
I don't take people places.
Nikomu průvodce nedělám.
[Anyone doing guide.]
Let me rephrase that.
Řeknu to tedy jinak.
[Therefore I say it differently.]
Hey.
Hele!
[Hey!]
Take me up the North Mountain.
Vezmi mě na Severní horu.
[Take me to the North Mountain.]
Please.
Prosím.
[Please.]
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
Vím, jak zastavit tu zimu.
[I know how to stop this winter.]
We leave at dawn.
Vyrazíme za úsvitu.
[We'll leave at dawn.]
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
A zapomněla jsi mrkev pro Svena.
[And have you forgotten carrot for Sven.]
Oops, sorry.
Pardon.
[Sorry.]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
To jsem nechtěla.
[I did not want that.]
We leave now. Right now.
Vyrazíme hned. Okamžitě.
[We leave now. Immediately.]
Whew!
Hang on! We like to go fast.
Drž se. Jezdíme rychle.
[Good luck. We go quickly.]
I like fast. - Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Rychlost miluju.
[I love speed.]
Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
Ty nohy dolů. Jsou čerstvě natřené.
[Those legs down. They are freshly painted.]
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
Vyrostla jsi snad v lese?
[Perhaps you grew up in the woods?]
Ugh!
No, I was raised in a castle.
Ne, vyrostla jsem na zámku.
[No, I grew up in the castle.]
So, uh, tell me,
Tak mi pověz,
[So tell me,]
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
proč začala královna tak mrazivě řádit?
[why the queen so chillingly rampage?]
Oh. Well...
No...
[Well...]
It was all my fault.
To byla moje chyba.
[It was my fault.]
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
Já se zasnoubila, což ji rozzlobilo,
[I got engaged, which made her angry]
because I'd only just met him you know, that day.
protože jsem ho ten den zrovna potkala.
[because I had just met that day.]
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage, and...
Tak řekla, že našemu sňatku nepožehná.
[So she said our marriage bless.]
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
Počkat. Ty ses zasnoubila s někým, koho jsi znala sotva den?
[Wait. You're engaged to someone you barely knew the day?]
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
Jo. A pak jsem se naštvala a ona se taky naštvala,
[Yeah. And then I got mad and she was too upset,]
and then she tried to walk away, and I grabbed her glove...
chtěla odejít a já jí stáhla rukavici...
[she wanted to leave and I pulled her glove...]
Hang on!
Počkej.
[Wait.]
You mean to tell me you got engaged
Chceš mi říct, že ses zasnoubila
[Are you telling me that you were engaged]
to someone you just met that day?
s někým, koho jsi znala jen jeden den?
[with someone you knew just one day?]
Yes. Pay attention.
Ano. Dávej pozor.
[Yes. Be careful.]
But the thing is, she wore the gloves all the time,
Ona ty rukavice nosila už od malička,
[She wore those gloves since childhood,]
so I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
tak jsem si říkala, že se třeba bojí špíny.
[I thought that perhaps afraid of dirt.]
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
Rodiče tě nevarovali před cizími lidmi?
[Parents warn you in front of strangers?]
Yyyyyes, they did.
Ano, varovali.
[Yes, they warned.]
But Hans is not a stranger.
Ale Hans není cizí člověk.
[But Hans is not a stranger.]
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
Jo? Odkud pochází?
[Yeah? Where it comes from?]
"Of the Southern Isles."
Je z Jižních ostrovů.
[It is the South Island.]
What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
Jeho oblíbené jídlo? - Sendviče.
[His favorite food? - Sandwiches.]
Best friend's name? - Probably John.
Nejlepší přítel? - Pravděpodobně Franz.
[Best friend? - Probably Franz.]
Eye color? - Dreamy.
Barva očí? - Vysněná.
[Eye color? - Dream.]
Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
Velikost nohy? - Na velikosti nohy nezáleží.
[Foot size? - On foot size does not matter.]
Have you had a meal with him yet? What if you hate the way he eats?
Už jste spolu jedli? Co když bude mlaskat?
[Have you eaten together? What if I will smack?]
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
Co když se bude šťourat v nose?
[What he will poke his nose?]
Picks his nose?
Šťourat v nose?
[Picking your nose?]
And eats it.
A jíst to.
[And eat it.]
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
No dovolte, pane! Je to princ.
[Excuse me, sir! It's a prince.]
All men do it.
Dělají to všichni chlapi.
[They do this all the guys.]
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
To je jedno. Je to má pravá láska.
[It does not matter. It is my true love.]
It doesn't sound like true love.
Ta vypadá jinak.
[It looks different.]
Are you some sort of love expert?
Jsi snad nějaký expert na lásku?
[You're probably an expert on love?]
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
Ne. Ale mám přátele, co jsou.
[No. But I have friends who are.]
You have friends
Ty máš přátele,
[You have friends,]
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
co jsou experti na lásku? Tak to ti nebaštím.
[What are the experts on love? Then I nebaštím.]
Stop talking. - No, no, no. No, no.
Buď zticha. - Ne, ne, ne.
[Shut up. - No no no.]
I'd like to meet these... - No, I mean it.
Moc ráda bych je potkala... - Myslím to vážně.
[I wish I met them... - I'm serious.]
Sven, go.
Svene, běž.
[Sven, go.]
Go!
What are they? - Wolves.
Co je tam? - Vlci.
[What is there? - Wolves.]
Wolves?
Vlci?
[Wolves?]
What do we do? - I got this.
Co uděláme? - Ujedu jim.
[What do we do? - I'll miss them.]
You just... Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
Ty nespadni a nenech se sežrat.
[They do not fall and do not get eaten.]
But I want to help!
Chci ti pomáhat.
[I want to help.]
No. - Why not?
Ne! - Proč ne?
[No! - Why not?]
Because I don't trust your judgment.
Protože ti nevěřím.
[Because I believe it.]
Excuse me?
Jak prosím?
[I beg your pardon?]
Who marries a man she just met?
Kdo si vezme někoho, koho sotva zná?
[Who marries someone she barely knows?]
It's true love!
Já ho miluju!
[I love him!]
Whoa!
Whoa. Whoa!
Christopher!
Christophere!
[Christopher!]
It's "Kristoff"!
Jsem Kristoff!
[I Kristoff!]
Ow!
Duck!
Uhni!
[Move!]
You almost set me on fire!
Málem jsi mě zapálila!
[You almost got me lit!]
But I didn't.
Ale nehoříš.
[But nehoříš.]
Get ready to jump, Sven!
Připrav se na skok, Svene!
[Ready to jump, Sven!]
You don't tell him what to do.
Ty mu nemáš co rozkazovat.
[They had got nothing to command.]
I do!
Jen já!
[Just me!]
Jump, Sven!
Skoč, Svene!
[Jump, Sven!]
Phew!
But I just paid it off.
Zrovna jsem je splatil.
[I just is repaid.]
Uh-oh. No. No.
Ne. Ne!
[No. No!]
No!
Ne!
[No!]
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Ne, ne, ne...!
[No no no...!]
Grab on!
Chyť se!
[Grab!]
Pull, Sven. Pull!
Táhni, Svene. Táhni!
[Begone, Sven. Begone!]
Whoa.
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
Koupím ti nové sáně a vše, co v nich bylo.
[I'll buy you a new sled and everything in them.]
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
A pochopím, když už mi nebudeš chtít dál pomáhat.
[And I understand if you do not want to have me continue to help.]
Of course I don't want to help her anymore. In fact,
Ovšemže už jí nechci pomáhat.
[Of course, now I do not want her help.]
this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
A hlavně po téhle zkušenosti už nepomůžu nikdy nikomu.
[And especially after this experience I would never help anyone.]
It's this way?
Jdu správně?
[I go right?]
"She'll die on her own."
Ale ona sama umře.
[But she dies.]
I can live with that. - Here we go.
S tím dokážu žít. - Tudy.
[I can live with. - This way.]
"But you won't get your new sled if she's dead."
Když umře, tak nedostaneš nové sáně.
[When he dies, you get a new sled.]
I think, actually, it's up.
Asi musím nahoru.
[I probably up.]
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
Někdy mě vážně štveš.
[Sometimes really annoy me.]
Hold up! We're coming.
Počkej! Jdeme s tebou.
[Wait! We're going with you.]
You are?
Vážně?
[Really?]
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
Jasně. Klidně se ke mně přidejte.
[Sure. Feel free to add me.]
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
Je úplně zmrzlý.
[It is completely frozen.]
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
Zase roztaje. Elsa se uklidní.
[In turn melts. Elsa calm down.]
Will she?
Vážně?
[Really?]
Yeah. Now, come on.
Jo. Tak jdeme.
[Yeah. Let's go.]
This way to the North Mountain?
Na Severní horu je to tudy?
[North Mountain's way?]
More like this way.
Já bych řekl spíš tudy.
[I would say more that way.]
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
Netušila jsem, že zima může být tak překrásná.
[I did not know that winter can be so beautiful.]
Yeah.
Jo.
[Yeah.]
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
Je překrásná, že ano?
[It is beautiful, is not it?]
But it's so white.
Ale moc bílá.
[But too much white.]
You know, how about a little color?
Chtělo by to trochu barvy.
[It would take a bit of color.]
I'm thinking maybe some crimson, chartreuse.
Napadá mě třeba karmínová nebo zelenkavá.
[I wonder perhaps crimson or greenish.]
How about yellow?
A co třeba žlutá?
[And what about yellow?]
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
Ne, žlutá ne. Žlutý sníh?
[No yellow Sun. Yellow snow?]
No go.
Fujky.
[Fujky.]
Am I right?
Nemám recht?
[I do not recht?]
You're creepy.
Fujtajbl.
[Goo.]
I don't want it.
Já to nechci.
[I do not want it.]
Back at you. - Please don't drop me.
Nech si to. - Neupusťte mě.
[Keep it. - Do not drop me.]
Come on, it's just a head.
Je to jen hlava.
[It's just a head.]
All right. We got off to a bad start.
Asi jsme nezačali nejlíp.
[Maybe we did not start the best way.]
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
Fuj, to tělo.
[Ugh, it's body.]
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Počkat, na co se to dívám?
[Wait, what am I looking at?]
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
Proč visíte jako netopýři?
[Why you hang like bats?]
All right, wait one second.
Počkej, hned to napravím.
[Wait, I get it right.]
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Děkuju. - Nemáš za co.
[Thank you. - You're welcome.]
Now, I'm perfect.
Teď jsem dokonalý.
[Now I am perfect.]
Well, almost.
Téměř.
[Almost.]
It was like my whole life got turned upside down.
Jako by se mi celý život obrátil.
[As if my life turned around.]
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
To bylo moc. Promiň.
[That was too much. Sorry.]
Head rush! - I was just... Are you okay?
To byla šlupka. - Jsi v pořádku?
[It was a shell. - Are you okay?]
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
Děláš si švandu? Je mi báječně!
[Are you Švanda? It feels great!]
I've always wanted a nose.
Vždycky jsem toužil po nosu.
[I always longed for a nose.]
So cute.
Je tak mrňavý.
[It's so tiny.]
It's like a little baby unicorn.
Jako růžek jednorožce.
[Like the corner of a unicorn.]
But... Hey! Whoa!
Oh.
I love it even more.
Takhle se mi líbí ještě víc.
[That's how I like it even more.]
All right, let's start this thing over.
Dobrá, začneme hezky znovu.
[Well, let's start again pretty.]
Hi, everyone.
Ahoj vespolek.
[Hello, everyone.]
I'm Olaf.
Já jsem Olaf.
[I Olaf.]
And I like warm hugs.
Mám rád vřelá objetí.
[I like a warm embrace.]
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
No ano. Olaf.
[Well, yes. Olaf.]
And you are?
A ty jsi...
[And you...]
Oh. Um...
I'm Anna.
Já jsem Anna.
[I'm Anna.]
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
Kdo je ten srandovní osel, co s tebou jde?
[Who's the funny donkey, what are you doing?]
That's Sven.
To je Sven.
[This is Sven.]
And who's the reindeer?
A kdo je ten sob?
[And who is this method?]
Sven.
Oh, they're... Oh. Okay. That makes things easier for me.
Bezva. Líp si je zapamatuju.
[Cool. Better get them to remember.]
Aw, look at him trying to kiss my nose.
Chce mi dát pusu na nos.
[He wants to give me a kiss on the nose.]
I like you, too.
Taky se mi líbíš.
[Also, I like you.]
Olaf. Did Elsa build you? - Yeah. Why?
Olafe. Tebe postavila Elsa? - Jo. Proč?
[Olaf. He puts Elsa? - Yeah. Why?]
Do you know where she is? - Yeah. Why?
A víš, kde je? - Jo. Proč?
[And you know where he is? - Yeah. Why?]
Fascinating.
Do you think you could show us the way? - Yeah. Why?
Mohl bys nás k ní zavést? - Jo. Proč?
[Could you introduce us to her? - Yeah. Why?]
How does this work? Ow!
Jak to asi funguje?
[How about work?]
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus, here.
Přestaň, Svene. Snažíme se soustředit.
[Stop, Sven. We're trying to concentrate.]
Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.
Jo. Proč? - Řeknu ti proč.
[Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.]
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
Aby přivolala zpátky léto.
[Back to summon the summer.]
Summer?
Léto?
[Summer?]
Oh. I don't know why,
Ani nevím proč,
[I do not know why,]
but I've always loved the idea of summer
ale léto mě vždycky nesmírně přitahovalo.
[But the summer was always very attracted.]
and sun, and all things hot.
A slunce a pěkný hic.
[And the sun and the pretty hic.]
Really?
Vážně?
[Really?]
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
Koukám, že s horkem moc zkušeností nemáš.
[I guess the heat you do not have much experience.]
Nope.
Ne.
[No.]
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
Ale někdy zavřu oči
[But sometimes I close my eyes]
and imagine what it would be like when summer does come.
a představuju si, jaké by to bylo, kdyby k nám přišlo léto.
[and imagine what it would be like if the summer has come to us.]
Bees will buzz, kids will blow dandelion fuzz
Chmýříčko na nebe láká sluníčko,
[Chmýříčko the sky attracts sun]
And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer
a já zas udělám to, co sníh dělá v létě!
[and I again do what it does snow in summer!]
A drink in my hand
Jen drink objednám,
[Just order a drink,]
My snow up against the burning sand
hned šlofíka v horkém písku dám,
[just nap in the hot sand give,]
Probably getting gorgeously tanned
než se zvednu, s naháči zhnědnu
[before I pick up with bathers Brown]
In summer.
v létě!
[in summer!]
I'll finally see a summer breeze
Snad uvidím, kam vánice
[Perhaps see where blizzard]
Blow away a winter storm
se v tom parnu poděje,
[In the heat of the soil]
And find out what happens to solid water
a zjistím, jak ledu tu úsměv tuhne,
[and see how the smile of ice conditions,]
When it gets warm
když v teple je!
[when it is warm!]
And I can't wait to see
Těším se, už teď vím,
[I'm looking forward, now I know,]
What my buddies all think of me
jak své přátele překvapím,
[how to surprise your friends,]
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be
všechna srdce pro mne roztají hned
[all hearts melt for me now]
In summer!
v tom létě!
[in the summer!]
The hot and the cold are both so intense
Je chvilenku horko, zima je pak,
[Chvilenku is hot, then cold,]
Put them together It just makes sense
kdyby šly spojit, všem vytřu zrak!
[if he went unite all wipe sight!]
Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle
V zimě chci doma být, hezky to klouže,
[In winter, I want to be at home, pretty slippery,]
But put me in summer and I'll be a...
však jen vlítnu do léta, je ze mě...
[But just vlítnu the summer, it is me...]
(puddle?)
(louže?)
[(puddle?)]
Happy snowman!
...šťastný sněhulák!
[... happy snowman!]
When life gets rough
Když na draka je život,
[When the dragon's life]
I like to hold on to my dream
denně tajně sním,
[daily secretly dream]
Of relaxing in the summer sun, just letting off steam
jak mi léto zvedne náladu a páru upustím!
[how my summer lifts the mood and the pair will drop!]
Oh, the sky will be blue
Nebe znám z modrých snů,
[I know the sky blue dream]
And you guys will be there, too
tak přijeďte, budu tu.
[then come, I'll be there.]
When I finally do
Budu dělat jen to,
[I will do just that,]
What frozen things do in summer!
co dělává sníh vždy v létě!
[What delave always snow in summer!]
I'm gonna tell him.
Já mu to řeknu.
[I'll tell him.]
Don't you dare.
Opovaž se.
[Dare you.]
In summer!
Vždy v létě!
[Always in the summer!]
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Tak pojďte. K Else je to tudy.
[Come on. The Else's way.]
Let's go bring back summer!
Přivoláme léto zpátky!
[We summon the summer back!]
I'm coming!
Už běžím.
[I'm coming.]
Somebody's gotta tell him.
Někdo mu to musí říct.
[Someone needs to tell him.]
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
Ne. Dáváš to kůrou dolů.
[No. You give it zest down.]
The bark needs to be face-up.
Kůra musí být nahoru.
[The bark must be up.]
Bark down is drier. - Bark up!
Dolů to líp vyschne.
[It dries down better.]
Bark down! - Papa!
Nahoru! - Dolů!
[Up! - Down!]
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Pláště! Potřebuje někdo plášť?
[Coats! He needs someone cloak?]
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
Arendelle je vám zavázán, Vaše Veličenstvo.
[Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Majesty.]
The castle is open.
Brány jsou otevřeny.
[The gates are open.]
There is soup and hot gløgg in the Great Hall.
Je tam polévka a v hlavní síni teplý glogg.
[There is soup and warm in the main hall Glogg.]
Here, pass these out.
Rozdejte to.
[Distribute it.]
Prince Hans!
Princi Hansi!
[Hansi prince!]
Are we expected to just sit here and freeze
To tu máme sedět a mrznout,
[That we have to sit and freeze,]
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
zatímco vy rozdáváte zboží, co má Arendelle na prodej?
[while you're giving away merchandise that has Arendelle on sale?]
Princess Anna has given her orders.
Princezna Anna mi dala rozkazy.
[Princess Anne gave me orders.]
And that's another thing!
A to je další věc.
[And that's another thing.]
Has it dawned on you that your princess may be conspiring
Co když se ta vaše princeznička
[What if yours princess]
with a wicked sorceress
spikla s tou čarodějnicí
[conspires with the witch]
to destroy us all?
a plánuje nás zničit?
[and plans to destroy us?]
Do not question the princess.
Nepochybujte o princezně.
[Doubt about the princess.]
She left me in charge
Pověřila mě vládou.
[He instructed the government.]
and I will not hesitate
A já budu chránit
[And I'll protect]
to protect Arendelle from treason.
Arendelle před zradou.
[Arendelle before betrayal.]
Treason?
Před zradou?
[Before betrayal?]
Whoa! Whoa!
Prrr!
[Whoa!]
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Klid, hochu!
[Calm, boy!]
Easy.
Zklidni se.
[Calm down.]
It's Princess Anna's horse.
To je kůň princezny Anny.
[This is a horse of Princess Anne.]
So, where is the princess?
Ale kde je princezna?
[But where is the princess?]
Where could she be? - Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
Princezna Anna má problémy.
[Princess Anne has problems.]
I need volunteers to go with me to find her.
Potřebuji dobrovolníky, co mi ji pomohou najít.
[I need volunteers who will help me find her.]
I'll go. I volunteer.
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Pošlu s vámi dva muže, můj pane.
[I will send you two men, my lord.]
Be prepared for anything.
Buďte připraveni na cokoli.
[Be prepared for anything.]
And should you encounter the queen,
A kdybyste narazili na královnu,
[And if you come across a queen,]
you are to put an end to this winter.
tak tuhle zimu ukončete.
[so this winter exit.]
Do you understand?
Rozumíte mi?
[Do you understand me?]
So, how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
Jak přesně hodláš tu zimu zastavit?
[How exactly are you going to stop this winter?]
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
Promluvím si se svou sestrou.
[I'll talk with her sister.]
That's your plan?
To je tvůj plán?
[That's your plan?]
My ice business is riding on you talking to your sister?
Moje budoucnost závisí na tvém pokecu se sestrou?
[My future depends on your chat with my sister?]
Yep.
Jo.
[Yeah.]
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
Ty se jí vůbec nebojíš?
[They had no fear at all?]
Why would I be?
Proč bych měla?
[Why should I?]
Yeah. I bet she's the nicest, gentlest, warmest person ever.
Jo. Určitě je to ta nejhodnější, nejlaskavější a nejmilejší ženská na světě.
[Yeah. It's definitely the nicest, kindest, sweetest woman in the world.]
Oh. Look at that.
Koukněte.
[Look.]
I've been impaled.
Jsem skrz naskrz.
[I'm through.]
What now?
Co teď?
[What now?]
Mmm...
It's too steep.
Je to moc strmé.
[It's too steep.]
I've only got one rope and you don't know how to climb mountains.
Mám jen jedno lano, a ty po skalách lézt neumíš.
[I have only one rope, and those you can not climb over rocks.]
Says who?
Říká kdo?
[Says who?]
Hmm?
What are you doing?
Copak to děláš?
[Did you do it?]
I'm going to see my sister.
Jdu si promluvit se svou sestrou.
[I'm going to talk to her sister.]
You're gonna kill yourself.
Takhle si spíš ublížíš.
[That's how you hurt yourself more.]
I wouldn't put my foot there.
Tam bych tu nohu nedával.
[There, I gave my leg.]
You're distracting me. - Or there.
Rozptyluješ mě. - Ani tam.
[You are distracting me. - Not there.]
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
Jak víš, že se s tebou bude bavit?
[How do you know you will be entertained?]
All right. I'm just blocking you out
Vypínám vnímání,
[Shutting perception,]
because I gotta concentrate, here.
protože se musím soustředit.
[because I have to concentrate.]
You know, most people who disappear
Lidé se většinou uchylují
[People usually resort]
into the mountains want to be alone.
do hor, když chtějí být sami.
[to the mountains when they want to be alone.]
Nobody wants to be alone.
Nikdo nechce být sám.
[Nobody wants to be alone.]
Except maybe you.
Možná kromě tebe.
[Except maybe you.]
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
Já nejsem sám. Mám přátele, vzpomínáš?
[I am not alone. I have friends, remember?]
You mean, the love experts?
Myslíš ty experty na lásku?
[You mean the experts on love?]
Yes, the love experts.
Jo, ty experty na lásku.
[Yeah, those experts on love.]
Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Řekni mi, že už tam jsem.
[Tell me that I'm there.]
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
Není tady nahoře nějak řidší vzduch?
[Not up here somehow thinner air?]
Hang on.
Vydrž.
[Hold on.]
Hey, Sven?
Svene!
[Sven!]
Not sure if this is gonna solve the problem,
Nevím, jestli to vyřeší náš problém,
[I do not know if it solves our problem,]
but I found a staircase that leads exactly
ale našel jsem schody, které vedou tam,
[but I found the stairs that lead there,]
where you wanted to go.
kam potřebujeme.
[where needed.]
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
Díkybohu. Chytej!
[Thank God. Catch!]
Thanks. That was like a crazy trust exercise.
Díky. Ber to jako test důvěry.
[Thanks. Think of it as a test of confidence.]
Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
Páni. Tomu říkám led.
[Wow. I call it ice.]
I might cry.
Budu plakat.
[I will cry.]
Go ahead. I won't judge.
Posluž si. Nebudu se smát.
[Help yourself. I will not laugh.]
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
Neházej sebou, hochu. Pojď zpátky.
[Do not throw me, boy. Come back.]
I got you.
Mám tě.
[I have you.]
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
Fajn. Počkej na nás tady.
[Fine. Wait for us here.]
Flawless.
Perfektní.
[Perfect.]
Knock.
Zaklep.
[Knock.]
Just knock.
Tak zaklep.
[So knock.]
Why isn't she knocking?
Proč nezaklepe?
[Why knocks?]
Do you think she knows how to knock?
Ona neumí klepat?
[She can not knock?]
Huh. It opened.
Otevřely se.
[It opened.]
That's a first.
To je poprvé.
[This is the first time.]
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
Ty bys asi měl zůstat tady.
[You'd probably have to stay here.]
What? - The last time I introduced her to a guy,
Cože? - Když jsem jí naposledy představila chlapa,
[What? - When I introduced it last guy]
she froze everything.
všechno zmrazila.
[everything froze.]
But, but... Oh, come on!
Ale no tak.
[Come on.]
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
Je to zámek z ledu. A led je můj život.
[It's a castle out of ice. And the ice is my life.]
Bye, Sven.
Pa, Svene.
[Pa, Sven.]
You, too, Olaf.
Ty taky, Olafe.
[You, too, Olaf.]
Me? - Just give us a minute.
Já? - Dejte nám minutku.
[Me? - Give us a minute.]
Okay.
Tak jo.
[So yeah.]
One, two, three...
Jedna, dvě... Tři.
[One two Three.]
Four...
Čtyři.
[Four.]
Whoa.
Elsa?
Elso!
[Elso!]
It's me, Anna.
To jsem já, Anna.
[It's me, Anna.]
Anna.
Anno.
[Anno.]
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
Páni, Elso, vypadáš jinak.
[Wow, Elsa, you look different.]
It's a good different.
Hezky jinak.
[Nice otherwise.]
And this place...
A tenhle zámek...
[And this castle...]
It's amazing.
...je úžasný.
[...He is amazing.]
Thank you.
Děkuji.
[Thank you.]
I never knew what I was capable of.
Nikdy bych netušila, čeho všeho jsem schopná.
[I never would have had no idea what I'm capable of everything.]
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd have known...
Moc mě mrzí, co se stalo. Kdybych věděla, že...
[I'm sorry what happened. If I knew that...]
No, no, no. It's okay.
To je v pořádku.
[It's alright.]
You don't have to apologize, but you should probably go.
Nemusíš se omlouvat. Ale měla bys odejít.
[No need to apologize. But you should go.]
Please.
Prosím.
[Please.]
But I just got here.
Vždyť jsem sotva přišla.
[I've just arrived.]
You belong down in Arendelle.
Patříš dolů do Arendellu.
[You belong down to Arendellu.]
So do you.
To ty také.
[That you too.]
No, Anna, I belong here.
Ne, Anno, já zůstanu tady.
[No, Annie, I'll stay here.]
Alone.
Sama.
[Sam.]
Where I can be who I am without hurting anybody.
Mohu tu být, čím jsem, aniž bych někomu ubližovala.
[Can this be what I am without getting anyone hurt.]
Actually, about that...
Zrovna o tom chci mluvit.
[Just I want to talk about it.]
Sixty! - Wait. What is that?
Šedesát! - Co to je?
[Sixty! - What is it?]
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
Ahoj, já jsem Olaf. Mám rád vřelá objetí.
[Hi, I'm Olaf. I like a warm embrace.]
Olaf?
[Olaf?]
You built me.
Jo, postavila jsi mě.
[Yeah, you put me.]
Remember that?
Nevzpomínáš?
[You remember?]
And you're alive?
A ty žiješ?
[And you live?]
Um... I think so.
Myslím, že ano.
[I think yes.]
He's just like the one we built as kids.
Takového jsme si stavěly jako děti.
[We built such as children.]
Yeah.
Ano.
[Yes.]
Elsa, we were so close.
Elso, bývaly jsme si blízké.
[Elso, we used to be close.]
We can be like that again.
Nemůžeme to vrátit?
[We can not return?]
Catch me! Slow down!
Chyť mě! - Zpomal!
[Catch me! - Slow down!]
Anna!
Anno.
[Anno.]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
Nemůžeme. Sbohem, Anno.
[We can not. Goodbye, Anna.]
Elsa, wait.
Elso, počkej.
[Elso, wait.]
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
Ne, jen se tě snažím ochránit.
[No, I'm trying to protect.]
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
Mě nemusíš chránit, já se nebojím.
[You do not have to defend, I'm afraid.]
Please don't shut me out again.
Prosím, nebuď ke mně tak chladná.
[Please do not be so cold to me.]
Please don't slam the door
Nezamykej se!
[Do not lock it!]
You don't have to keep your distance anymore
Když si přestáváme věřit, je to zlé.
[When you stop believing, it is bad.]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Věř mi, že právě teď jak nikdy
[Believe me, now as ever]
I finally understand
tě dobře chápu snad,
[I well understand, perhaps,]
For the first time in forever
věř mi, právě teď jak nikdy
[Believe me, now as ever]
We can fix this hand in hand
můžem pravdu nevylhat.
[the truth can nevylhat.]
We can head down this mountain together.
Spolu odejdem z téhleté hory,
[Together we will from this mountain,]
You don't have to live in fear
strach tě cestou opustí.
[Fear leaves you the way.]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Vždyť přece právě teď tak šťastná
[After all, now so happy]
I will be right here
budu tam, kde jsi.
[I'll be right where you are.]
Anna.
Anno.
[Anno.]
Please go back home
Běž domů, běž,
[Go home, go,]
Your life awaits
svůj život měj.
[Have your life.]
Go enjoy the sun, and open up the gates
Užívej si slunce, brány otvírej.
[Enjoy the sun, open the gates.]
Yeah, but...
Ano, ale...
[Yes but...]
I know.
Já vím...
[I know...]
You mean well, but leave me be
Jak hodná jsi. Však musíš jít,
[How good you are. But you gotta go,]
Yes, I'm alone
chci takhle žít
[I want to live like this]
But I'm alone and free
a věčně volná být.
[and be forever free.]
Just stay away and you'll be safe from me
Jen straň se mě a budeš v bezpečí.
[Just turn away from me and you'll be safe.]
Actually, we're not
Ne, to nejsme, ne!
[No, we're not, do not!]
What do you mean, you're not?
Řekni mi, proč ne!
[Tell me, why not!]
I get the feeling you don't know
Podivné věci dějí se!
[Strange things are happening!]
What do I not know?
Týkají se mě?
[They relate to me?]
Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep
Arendelle nám přikryl sníh,
[Arendelle we covered snow]
deep snow
sníh s tmou.
[snow and darkness.]
What?
Cože?
[What?]
You kind of set off an eternal winter everywhere.
Tak nějak jsi rozpoutala nekonečnou zimu úplně všude.
[So somehow you unleash an endless winter everywhere.]
Everywhere?
Jak všude?
[As everywhere?]
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
Ale to nic, stačí spustit tání.
[But it's nothing, just start melting.]
No, I can't. I don't know how.
To nejde, já nevím jak.
[You can not, I do not know how.]
Sure you can. I know you can.
Jasně že víš. Vím to, že víš.
[Sure, you know. I know that you know.]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Protože právě teď jak nikdy...
[Because right now as ever...]
Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free!
Když volnost práh svůj překročí...
[When freedom exceeds its threshold...]
You don't have to be afraid
je už zbytečné se bát!
[it is unnecessary to worry!]
No escape from the storm inside of me
bouře v mém nitru na svět útočí!
[storm inside of me attacking the world!]
We can work this out together
Útok nejprudší, ten zvládnem!
[Sharpest attack, he'll manage!]
I can't control the curse!
Jsem na dně s vůlí svou!
[I'm down to play her!]
We'll reverse the storm you've made
Utišíme bouři tvou.
[Beating your storm.]
Anna, please you'll only make it worse!
Anno, nech mě být, jen zhoršíš to!
[Anna, let me be, just making things worse it!]
Don't panic!
Proč křičíš?
[Why are you screaming?]
There's so much fear!
Měj ze mě strach!
[Have afraid of me!]
We'll make the sun shine bright
Vzbuď slunce na střechách!
[Wake up the sun on the roof!]
You're not safe here!
Běž rychle pryč!
[Go away quickly!]
We can face this thing together
Správný klíč najdeme spolu!
[Together we can find the right key!]
No!
Ne...!
[No...!]
We can change this winter weather
Zahnat můžem krutou zimu,
[We can fight off the bitter cold,]
And everything will be all right
když pomůžem si ty a já.
[Helping you and me.]
I can't!
Já... já... ne...!
[I... I... do not...!]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Are you okay?
Jsi v pořádku?
[Are you okay?]
I'm okay.
Nic mi není.
[It's nothing.]
I'm fine.
Jsem v pořádku.
[I'm fine.]
Who's this?
Kdo to je?
[Who is it?]
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
Na tom nesejde.
[It does not matter.]
You have to go.
Musíte odejít.
[You have to leave.]
No, I know we can figure this out together.
Ne. Já vím, že společně to vyřešíme.
[No. I know that together we will solve it.]
How?
Jak?
[How?]
What power do you have to stop this winter?
Jakými kouzly vládneš, abys vše změnila?
[Curses you control to change everything?]
To stop me?
A hlavně mě?
[And most importantly to me?]
Anna, I think we should go.
Anno, měli bychom jít.
[Anna, we should go.]
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Ne, já bez tebe neodejdu, Elso.
[No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.]
Yes, you are.
Ano. Odejdeš.
[Yes. Leave.]
Stop! Put us down!
Stůj! Nech nás být!
[Stop! Leave us alone!]
Go away.
Jít pryč.
[Go away.]
Heads up!
Bacha na hlavu!
[Watch the head!]
Watch out for my butt!
A teď na zadek!
[Now butt!]
It is not nice to throw people!
Já ti dám, házet po nás sněhuláky.
[I'll give you throw at us snowmen.]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants. Okay, relax.
Kroť se, jenom klid.
[Kroto is just calm.]
Just calm down! Calm down! - Okay! All right!
Uklidni se! - Dobře!
[Calm down! - Alright!]
I'm okay. - Just let the snowman be.
Už jsem v klidu. - Nech tu obludu být.
[I'm calm. - Let there be a monster.]
I'm calm.
Jsem klidná. - Prima.
[I am calm. - Prima.]
Oh! Come on!
No tak!
[Come on!]
Oh. Look, see? Now you made him mad.
Vidíš, teď jsi ho rozdráždila.
[See, now you see him rozdráždila.]
I'll distract him. You guys go.
Odlákám ho. Vy utečte.
[Distract him. You run away.]
No, no! Not you guys!
Ne. Vy zůstaňte.
[No. You stay.]
This just got a whole lot harder.
Bez nohou to bude těžší.
[Without legs it will be harder.]
Look out!
Bacha!
[Bach!]
What are you doing?
Co to děláš?
[What are you doing?]
I got him!
Dostala jsem ho!
[I got it!]
Whoa! Stop!
Stůj!
[Stop!]
It's a hundred-foot drop.
Je to nejmíň třicet metrů.
[It is the least thirty meters.]
It's two hundred.
Je to šedesát.
[It's sixty.]
Ow!
What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
Co to děláš? - Kopu sněhovou kotvu.
[What are you doing? - Digging a snow anchor.]
Okay. What if we fall?
Dobře. A když spadneme?
[Okay. And when you fall?]
There's 20 feet of fresh powder down there.
Dole je šest metrů prašanu.
[Below is six meters of powder.]
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
Bude to jako spadnout do peřin.
[It'll be like falling into the bed.]
Hopefully.
Doufejme.
[Hopefully.]
Okay, Anna. On three.
Drž se, Anno. Na tři.
[Hold on, Anna. Three.]
One...
Raz.
[Raz.]
Okay. You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
Stačí říct kdy, jsem připravená.
[Suffice to say when I'm ready.]
Two... - I was born ready! Yes!
Dva. - Od narození.
[Two. - From birth.]
Calm down.
Uklidni se.
[Calm down.]
Tree!
Tři!
[Three!]
What the... Whoa!
Co to...
[What the...]
That happened.
To byl úlet.
[It was a fling.]
Man, am I out of shape.
Jsem nějak z formy.
[I kind of mold.]
There we go. Hey, Anna!
A je to. Anno!
[And it's done. Anna!]
Sven! Where did you guys go?
Svene! Kam jste se poděli?
[Sven! Where did you go?]
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
Ten Máršmeloun už je v čudu.
[He Máršmeloun already in čudu.]
Hey! We were just talking about you.
Zrovna jsme o tobě mluvili.
[We were just talking about you.]
All good things, all good things.
Jen v dobrém. Jen v dobrém.
[Just for good. Just for good.]
No!
Ne!
[No!]
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
Nějak výrazně tě to nezpomaluje, že ne?
[Somehow it does not slow down considerably you, do you?]
Olaf!
Olafe!
[Olaf!]
Hang in there, guys!
Držte se, vy dva!
[Hold on, you two!]
Go. Go faster!
Lez rychleji.
[Lez faster.]
Wait, what?
Počkej. Co je?
[Wait. What is?]
Ow!
Kristoff!
Kristoffe!
[Kristoff!]
Don't come back!
Nevracet se!
[Never to return!]
We won't.
Jasně.
[Sure.]
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
Měl jsi pravdu. Jako do peřin.
[You were right. As duvets.]
Olaf!
Olafe.
[Olaf.]
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
Necítím nohy. Já necítím nohy!
[I feel my legs. I feel my legs!]
Those are my legs.
To jsou moje nohy.
[These are my legs.]
Oooh. Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
Buď tak hodný a podej mi zadek.
[Be so kind and give me your ass.]
Oh. That feels better.
To je lepší.
[It is better.]
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Ahoj, Svene. On nás našel.
[Hi, Sven. He found us.]
Who's my cute little reindeer?
Kdo je můj roztomilý sobík?
[Who is my cute Sobík?]
Don't talk to him like that.
Takhle mi na něj nemluv.
[I like to talk to him.]
You're tickling me.
To šimralo.
[That tickling.]
Here.
Pojď.
[Come on.]
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Jsi celá?
[You all right?]
Thank you.
Díky.
[Thanks.]
How's your head? - Ah! Ooh!
Co tvoje hlava?
[What about your head?]
It's fine. Uh...
V pohodě.
[Cool.]
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
Nic mi není, mám tvrdou lebku.
[I'm fine, I have a hard skull.]
I don't have a skull.
Já žádnou nemám.
[I do not have one.]
Or bones.
Ani kosti.
[Nor bones.]
So, uh... So, now what?
Takže... Co bude teď?
[So... what happens now?]
Now what?
Co teď?
[What now?]
Now what?
Co teď?
[What now?]
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
Co si teď počnu?
[What are you going?]
She threw me out.
Vyhodila mě.
[She threw me.]
I can't go back to Arendelle with the weather like this.
S nepořízenou se nemůžu do Arendellu vrátit.
[I can not get nothing in return Arendellu.]
And then there's your ice business.
A co bude s tvým ledařstvím?
[And what about your ledařstvím?]
Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
S mým ledařstvím si starost nedělej.
[With my ledařstvím not worry.]
Worry about your hair!
Spíš se svými vlasy.
[Rather, with his hair.]
What? I just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
Cože? Spadla jsem z útesu. Podívej se na svoje.
[What? I fell off a cliff. Look at her.]
No, yours is turning white.
Ne, tvoje vlasy bělají.
[No, your hair whiten.]
White? It's... What?
Bělají? Cože?
[BELA? What?]
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
To proto, že tě trefila, že ano?
[That's because you hit, right?]
Does it look bad?
Vypadá to špatně?
[It looks bad?]
No. - You hesitated.
Ne. - Zaváhal jsi.
[No. - You hesitated.]
No, I didn't.
Ne, nezaváhal.
[No, he did not hesitate.]
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
Anno, potřebuješ pomoc, pojď se mnou.
[Anna, you need help, come with me.]
Okay! Where are we going?
Tak jo. Kam jdeme?
[So yeah. Where are we going?]
To see my friends.
Za mými přáteli.
[For my friends.]
The love experts?
Za experty na lásku?
[For experts on love?]
Love experts?
Experti na lásku?
[Experts in love?]
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
Neboj se, oni tě z toho dostanou.
[Do not worry, they'll get out of it.]
How do you know?
Jak to víš?
[How do you know?]
Because I've seen them do it before.
Protože jsem viděl, jak to udělali kdysi.
[Because I saw how they did it once.]
I like to consider myself a love expert.
Já jsem podle mě taky expert na lásku.
[I think I'm also an expert on love.]
Get it together.
Koukej se sebrat.
[Look to pick up.]
Control it.
Ovládej to.
[Take control of it.]
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Skrývej city. Skrývej city.
[Of hiding emotions. Of hiding emotions.]
Don't feel.
Skrývej city.
[Of hiding emotions.]
Don't feel!
Skrývej city!
[Of hiding feelings!]
Look, Sven, the sky's awake.
Hele, Svene. Obloha je vzhůru.
[Hey, Sven. The sky is awake.]
Are you cold? - A little.
Je ti zima? - Trochu.
[Are you cold? - A little.]
Uh... Wait. Come here.
Počkej, pojď sem.
[Wait, come here.]
Huh?
Ooh.
So, uh, about my friends. Well...
Víš... K těm mým přátelům...
[You know... To those of my friends...]
I say "friends"...
Říkám přátelé,
[I tell my friends,]
They're more like family.
ale je to spíš moje rodina.
[But it's more my family.]
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven.
Jako kluk jsem měl jen Svena,
[As a boy I had only Sven,]
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
a tak mě přijali mezi sebe.
[so they accepted him.]
They did?
Opravdu?
[Really?]
Yeah. I don't want to scare you.
Jo. Nerad bych tě vyděsil,
[Yeah. I would hate to scare you,]
They can be a little inappropriate and loud.
ale někdy se chovají nevhodně a křičí.
[But sometimes they behave inappropriately and screaming.]
Very loud.
Spíš řvou.
[Rather scream.]
They are also stubborn at times,
Někdy jsou tvrdohlaví
[Sometimes they are stubborn]
and a little overbearing.
a někdy nesnesitelní.
[and sometimes unbearable.]
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
A těžcí, hodně, hodně těžcí,
[A heavy, very, very heavy,]
But you'll get it. They mean well.
což všechno uvidíš. Ale myslí to dobře.
[all of which you'll see. But he means well.]
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Kristoffe, určitě jsou báječní.
[Kristoff, it's wonderful.]
Okay, then.
Tak dobře.
[Well.]
Meet my family.
Tohle je moje rodina.
[This is my family.]
Hey, guys.
Nazdar.
[Hello.]
They're rocks.
Jsou to kameny.
[They are stones.]
You are a sight for sore eyes.
Moc rád vás zase vidím.
[Very glad to see you again.]
He's crazy. - Hey look, ???'s back from vacation!
On se zbláznil.
[He was crazy.]
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Šutr vypadá drsně, jako obvykle.
[Rock looks tough, as usual.]
Clay, whoa... I don't even recognize you.
Balvane, málem bych tě nepoznal.
[Boulder, I almost did not recognize you.]
You lost so much weight.
Hodně jsi shodil.
[You dropped a lot.]
I'll distract him while you run.
Zabavím ho a ty uteč.
[I confiscate it and you run.]
Hi, Sven's family!
Ahoj, Svenova rodino.
[Hi, Svenova family.]
It's nice to meet you.
Moc rád vás poznávám.
[Very glad to meet you.]
Because I love you, Anna, I insist you run.
Mám tě rád, Anno, a trvám na tom, abys utekla.
[I love you, Anna, and I insist that you ran.]
I understand you're love experts. Ooh!
Slyšel jsem, že jste experti na lásku.
[I heard you're an expert on love.]
Why aren't you running?
Proč neutíkáš?
[Why neutíkáš?]
Uh...
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
Tak fajn. Já už budu muset...
[OK. I already I have to...]
No, no, no. Anna, wait.
Ne, Anno, stůj.
[No, Anna, stop.]
Kristoff!
Kristoffe?
[Kristoff?]
Whoa!
Hey!
Ahoj!
[Hello!]
Kristoff's home!
Kristoff je doma!
[Kristoff is home!]
Kristoff's here! Kristoff's home!
Kristoff je tady!
Wait, "Kristoff"?
Moment. Kristoff?
[Moment. Kristoff?]
Ah, let me look at you.
Ukaž se mi.
[Show me.]
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
Sundej si šaty, vyperu je.
[Take off your clothes, wash them.]
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
Ne, já si šaty sundávat nebudu.
[No, I will not take off his clothes.]
Look, it's great to see you all,
Moc rád vás vidím,
[Very glad to see you,]
but where's Granpabbie?
ale kde je Pratroll?
[but where Pratroll?]
He's napping.
Podřimuje.
[Napping.]
But look, I grew a mushroom.
Koukej, narostla mi houba.
[Look, I grew fungus.]
I earned my fire crystal.
Já dostala ohnivý krystal.
[I got a fiery crystal.]
I passed a kidney stone.
A já ledvinové kameny.
[And I kidney stones.]
Kristoff, pick me up.
Kristoffe, zvedni mě.
[Kristoff, pick me.]
You're getting big.
Ty jsi vyrostl!
[You're a grown up!]
Good for you.
Gratuluju.
[Congratulations.]
Trolls. They're trolls!
Trollové! Jsou to trollové!
[Trolls! These are the trolls!]
He's brought a girl!
Přivedl si holku!
[He brought a girl!]
A girl!
Holku!
[Girl!]
Is that a real girl?
She's like a little cupcake.
Ta je ale hezká.
[But that is pretty.]
What's going on?
Co se to děje?
[What's going on?]
I've learned to just roll with it.
Zkus si toho nevšímat.
[Try to ignore.]
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
Tak se ukaž. Jasný oči, čistej nos,
[So show. Bright eyes, nose clean,]
strong teeth!
silný zuby.
[strong teeth.]
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
Nevybral sis vůbec špatně, Kristoffe.
[You did not choose bad at all, Kristoff.]
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
Počkat. Ne.
[Wait. No.]
You've got the wrong idea.
Špatně si to vykládáte.
[Wrongly telling it.]
No. That's not why I brought her here.
Proto jsem ji nepřivedl.
[That's why I did not bring it.]
Right. We're not... I'm not...
Správně. My nejsme... Já nejsem...
[Right. We're not... I'm not...]
What's the issue, dear?
V čem je problém, drahá?
[What's the problem, dear?]
Why are you holding back from such a man?
Tobě nevyhovuje takový chlap?
[You, does not such a man?]
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
Snad proto, že tak divně jde?
[Perhaps because so strange is going on?]
What? - Or the grumpy way he talks?
Cože? - Občas mluví ošklivě?
[What? - Sometimes speaks badly?]
Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
Po kom nohy rostlé
[After whom proportioned legs]
Weirdness of his feet?
do "ó" může mít?
[to" O" can have?]
Hey!
Hej!
[Hey!]
And though we know he washes well
A přesto, že se umejvá,
[And though umejvá,]
He always ends up sort of smelly
řek' bych, že smrádne, a ne vábně.
[I should say that smrádne and not tempting.]
But you'll never meet a fella
Že má kouska citu v těle,
[It has a shred of emotion in your body,]
Who's as sensitive and sweet
může úsměv prozradit!
[may reveal a smile!]
That's nice, but...
To je hezké, ale...
[That's nice, but...]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
l jako prima chlap má svý mouchy,
[l as a nice guy has his flies,]
So, he's got a few flaws
něco zásadních vad!
[something fundamental defects!]
Like his peculiar brain, dear
Dva stejný mozky pro oba,
[Two brains the same for both,]
His thing with the reindeer
pro přítele soba.
[Friend for the reindeer.]
That's a little outside of nature's laws
Což je přírodní úkaz na kvadrát!
[Which is a natural phenomenon in the square!]
This is not about me!
Tady nejde o mě.
[This is not about me.]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
I jako prima chlap má svý mouchy,
[I like nice guy has his flies,]
But this we're certain of
však přesto věříme,
[Nevertheless, we believe,]
You can fix this fixer-upper up
že z much pilný včelky uděláš,
[that much of industrious bees do,]
With a little bit of love
jen tvou lásečku to chce!
[Only your lásečku wants it!]
Can we please just stop talking about this?
Mohli bychom prosím změnit téma?
[Could we please change the subject?]
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
Máme totiž jeden skutečný problém.
[Because we have a real problem.]
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Možná pak. Ale teď mi pověz...
[Maybe then. But now tell me...]
Is it the way that he runs scared?
Tak možná že je zbabělec?
[So maybe that's a coward?]
Or that he's socially impaired?
A lidi pro něj jsou jen věc!
[A People for him are just the thing!]
Or that he only likes to tinkle in the woods?
A taky chodívá rád čurat do lesa!
[And chodívá like to pee in the woods!]
I did not need to know that.
To jsem vědět nemusela.
[I did not know.]
Are you holding back your fondness
Řekni, co tě trápí - no tak!
[Tell me what's bothering you - come on!]
Due to his unmanly blondness?
Že je hezounek a blonďák?
[That's a pretty boy and blond?]
Or the way he covers up that he's the honest goods?
Nebo to, že dobrák je, a přesto žije sám?
[Or that it is a good man, and yet he lives alone?]
He's just a bit of a fixer-upper
I jako prima chlap má svý mouchy,
[I like nice guy has his flies,]
He's got a couple of bugs
i v kaši několik much.
[even in the mash some flies.]
(No, I don't!) - His isolation is confirmation
(Ne, nemám!) - Že sám je věčně, je nebezpečné,
[(No, I do not!) - That alone is eternal, it is dangerous,]
Of his desperation for healing hugs
v noci chladné chřadne, je pro svět vzduch!
[at night the cold wither, is the world's air!]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
I jako prima chlap má svý mouchy,
[I like nice guy has his flies,]
But we know what to do
tak poslyš nápad náš:
[listen to our idea:]
The way to fix up this fixer-upper
my mouchy tvé s jeho sezdáme,
[We fly thy with his sezdáme,]
Is to fix him up with you
ať chlapa bez chybičky máš!
[whether you're a guy flawlessly!]
Whoa!
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
Přestaň, přestaň. Tak dost!
[Stop it, stop it. Enough!]
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
Je zasnoubená s někým jiným, jasné?
[Is engaged to someone else, right?]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
I prima slečinka má svý mouchy.
[I miss having my prima flies.]
That's a minor thing
Jasně, to bych řek'!
[Yeah, I'd say'!]
Her quote "engagement" is a flex arrangement
To zasnoubení přece nemoc není!
[This engagement does not a disease!]
And by the way, I don't see no ring
Dyť heleďte - nemá prstýnek!
[Why, look here - does not ring!]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
I prima slečinka má svý mouchy
[I miss having my prima flies]
Her brain's a bit betwixt
a váhá, koho chtít!
[and hesitates, who want!]
Get the fiance out of the way
Zbav se rychle toho snoubence,
[Get rid of it quickly fiance,]
And the whole thing will be fixed
ať je všechno, jak má být!
[whether everything is as it should be!]
We're not saying you can change him
Každý se tak dlouho hledá,
[Everyone is looking for so long,]
'Cause people don't really change
však nezmění duši svou.
[but changed his soul.]
We're only saying that love's a force
Jen láska změní tě nakonec,
[Only love will change you in the end,]
That's powerful and strange
v ní mocná kouzla jsou!
[it is powerful spells!]
People make bad choices
Lidi špatně rozhodnou se,
[People choose the wrong,]
If they're mad or scared or stressed
když je žene spěch.
[when it is driven rush.]
But throw a little love their way
Však lásce pravé podlehnou.
[But true love succumb.]
Throw a little love their way
Lásce pravé podlehnou.
[True love succumb.]
And you'll bring out their best
Jen ta jim bere dech!
[Only that it takes your breath away!]
True love brings out the best
Ten cit je lékem všech.
[That sentiment is the cure all.]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
Nikdo není génius, má svý mouchy,
[Nobody's genius has his flies,]
That's what it's all about
o tom to vlastně je!
[That's what it is!]
Father! Sister! Brother!
Táta! Sestra! Bráška!
[Dad! Nurse! Brother!]
We need each other to raise us up
Tak žijem spolu,
[So we live together]
And round us out
než z kukly každý vylétne!
[pupae than anyone comes out!]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
Nikdo není génius, má svý mouchy,
[Nobody's genius has his flies,]
But when push comes to shove
a když jde za láskou,
[and when it comes to love,]
The only fixer-upper fixer
tak to pak muška mušku napravuje,
[it then corrects bead front sight,]
That can fix a fixer-upper is...
napravuje, až tu je...
[corrects when there is...]
True, true
Ta pravá,
[The right,]
True
Pravá...
[Right...]
Love!
...láska!
[... Love!]
Love, love, love
Ta láska,
[The love]
Love! True love
ta láska...
[the love...]
True
...pravá.
[... right.]
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
Bereš si, Anno, zde Kristoffa za svého právoplatného...
[Do you, Anna, here Kristoff be your lawful wedded...]
Wait, what? - You're getting married.
Cože? - Oddáváme vás.
[What? - We indulge you.]
Love!
Láska!
[Love!]
Anna?
Anno?
[Anna?]
She's as cold as ice.
Je studená jak led.
[It's cold as ice.]
There is strange magic here.
To je tou prapodivnou magií.
[This is the most bizarre magic.]
Granpabbie. - Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Pratrolle. - Honem, přiveď ji ke mně.
[Pratrolle. - Come on, bring it to me.]
Anna, your life is in danger.
Anno, tvůj život je v nebezpečí.
[Anna, your life is in danger.]
There is ice in your heart put there by your sister.
Ve tvém srdci je mráz, jež zasela tvá sestra.
[In your heart is cold, which sowed your sister.]
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
Pokud nebude odstraněn, pak se navždycky proměníš v kus ledu.
[If not corrected, you will forever turn into ice.]
What? No.
Cože? Ne.
[What? No.]
But you can remove it, right?
Ale ty ho můžeš odstranit, že?
[But you can remove it, right?]
I cannot
To nemohu.
[I can not.]
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
Odpusť, Kristoffe.
[Forgive me, Kristoff.]
If it was her head, that would be easy.
Kdyby šlo o hlavu, bylo by to snadné.
[If it was a head, it would be easy.]
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
Ale ledové srdce může rozehřát jen projev pravé lásky.
[But the heart can melt ice only a manifestation of true love.]
An act of true love?
Projev pravé lásky?
[Manifestation of true love?]
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
Třeba vřelý polibek.
[Perhaps a warm kiss.]
(Something's wrong. Are you all right?)
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Anno, pomoct ti může jen Hans.
[Annie, it can only help Hans.]
Hans.
[Hans.]
Pull us out, Sven.
Vytáhni nás, Svene.
[Pull us, Sven.]
Olaf, come on!
Olafe, poběž!
[Olaf, Come on!]
I'm coming!
Již kvačím!
[Already kvačím!]
Let's go kiss Hans!
Jedeme políbit Hanse!
[We're going to kiss Hans!]
Who is this Hans?
Kdo je ten Hans?
[Who is this Hans?]
We are here to find Princess Anna.
Přijeli jsme sem najít princeznu Annu.
[We came here to find a princess Anna.]
Be on guard, but no harm is to come to the queen.
Buďte bdělí, ale královně neubližujte.
[Be vigilant, but do not hurt the queen.]
Do you understand?
Je to všem jasné?
[Is it all clear?]
Yes, Your Grace.
The queen.
Královna!
[Queen!]
Go, go! Come on!
Honem!
[Hurry!]
There!
Rychle!
[Hurry!]
Up there!
Tamhle je!
[There it is!]
Come on!
Poběž!
[Come on!]
We got her.
Máme ji.
[We have it.]
No. Please.
Ne. Prosím.
[No. Please.]
Go around. Toss it.
Jdi z druhé strany!
[Go to the other side!]
Stay away!
Jděte pryč!
[Go away!]
Look out!
Pozor!
[Beware!]
Fire! Fire!
Střílej!
[Shoot!]
Get her!
Chyť ji!
[Catch her!]
Ah!
Come on!
Dělejte!
[Come on!]
Grab his arm.
Aim...
This way, this way!
Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Královno Elso!
[Queen Elso!]
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
Nebuďte monstrem, kterého se všichni bojí!
[Do not be a monster, whom everyone is afraid!]
Oh, no. What have... What have I done?
Ach ne. Co jsem to udělala?
[Oh, do not. What have I done?]
Why did you bring me here?
Proč jsi mě sem přivezl?
[Why did you bring me here?]
I couldn't just let them kill you.
Nemohl jsem je nechat tě zabít.
[I could not let them kill you.]
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
Ale já jsem pro Arendelle nebezpečná. Přiveď Annu.
[But I have to Arendelle dangerous. Bring Anna.]
Anna has not returned.
Anna se nevrátila.
[Anna did not return.]
If you would just stop the winter.
Mohla bys zastavit tu zimu?
[Can you stop this winter?]
Bring back summer, please.
Přivolej zpátky léto, prosím.
[Summon summer back, please.]
Don't you see?
Copak to nechápeš?
[Do not you understand?]
I can't.
Nevím jak.
[I do not know how.]
You have to tell them to let me go.
Nezbývá ti než mě pustit.
[I have no choice but to let me go.]
I will do what I can.
Udělám, co budu moct.
[I'll do what I can.]
Just hang in there.
Ještě vydrž.
[Do not hold on.]
Come on, buddy, faster!
Svene, přidej!
[Sven, add it!]
Oh, boy!
Ty bláho!
[Wow!]
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
Uvidíme se všichni v zámku!
[I'll see you all in the castle!]
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
Ať tě nikdo nevidí, Olafe!
[Let no one sees you, Olaf!]
I will!
Jasný!
[Bright!]
Hello! - It's alive!
Nazdar! - Obluda!
[Hi! - Monster!]
It's Princess Anna!
To je princezna Anna!
[This is Princess Anne!]
Are you gonna be okay?
Obejdeš se bez těch saní?
[Obejdeš without the slide?]
Don't worry about me.
O mě se neboj.
[Do not worry about me.]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
You had us worried sick. My Lady.
Měli jsme o vás hrozný strach. Má paní.
[We had so worried about you. My lady.]
Get her warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.
Musí do tepla. A najděte prince Hanse. Okamžitě!
[They have to heat. And find Prince Hans. Immediately!]
We will. Thank you.
Ano. Díky.
[Yes. Thanks.]
Make sure she's safe.
Dejte na ni pozor.
[Give her attention.]
Oh, you poor girl, you're freezing.
Chudinko malá, jste jak kus ledu.
[Poor little, you as a piece of ice.]
Oh, let's get you inside now and get you warm.
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
Musím najít princeznu Annu.
[I must find the Princess Anne.]
You cannot risk going out there again.
Další výprava by byla velice riskantní.
[Another expedition would have been very risky.]
If anything happens to her...
Kdyby se jí něco stalo...
[If anything happened to her...]
If anything happens to the princess,
Kdyby se princezně něco stalo,
[Had something happened to the Princess,]
you are all Arendelle has left.
má Arendelle už jenom vás.
[Arendelle has been just you.]
He's in here.
Tady je.
[Here is.]
Prince Hans.
Princi Hansi!
[Hansi prince!]
Anna.
Anno!
[Anna!]
You're so cold.
Jsi celá zmrzlá.
[You're all frozen.]
Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
Hansi, musíš mě políbit. - Cože?
[Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?]
Now! Now! - Slow down.
Hned. - Nač ten spěch?
[Right. - What's the rush?]
We'll give you two some privacy.
Dopřejeme vám trochu soukromí.
[We bring you a little privacy.]
What happened out there?
Co se tam venku stalo?
[What happened out there?]
Elsa struck me with her powers.
Elsa mě zasáhla svou magií.
[Elsa hit me with his magic.]
You said she'd never hurt you.
Říkalas, že ti neublíží.
[You said that you hurt.]
I was wrong.
Mýlila jsem se.
[I was wrong.]
Anna.
Anno!
[Anna!]
She froze my heart,
Zmrazila mé srdce
[I froze my heart]
and only an act of true love can save me.
a zachránit mě může jen opravdová láska.
[and save me the only true love.]
A true love's kiss.
Polibek z pravé lásky.
[Kiss of true love.]
Oh, Anna.
Anno.
[Anno.]
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
Kéž by byl někdo, kdo by tě opravdu miloval.
[I wish there was someone who really loves you.]
What?
Cože?
[What?]
You said you did.
Říkals, že jsi to ty.
[You said it was you.]
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
Jako třináctý následník v pořadí jsem neměl...
[Thirteenth successor in the order I did not...]
I didn't stand a chance.
...žádnou šanci kralovat.
[... no chance to reign.]
I knew I would have to marry into the throne somewhere.
Věděl jsem, že se musím někde k trůnu přiženit.
[I knew that I needed somewhere to the throne to marry.]
What... What are you talking about?
O čem to mluvíš?
[What are you talking about?]
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
Samozřejmě že by mi spíš vyhovovala Elsa,
[Of course I would rather meet Elsa,]
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
jenže na ní si každý vylámal zuby.
[but on her every withstood.]
But you...
Ale ty...
[But you...]
You were so desperate for love,
...jsi tolik toužila po lásce,
[... you are so longing for love,]
you were willing to marry me just like that.
že sis mě vzala hned, jenom tak.
[that you married me now, just like that.]
I figured after we married,
Napadlo mě, že až se vezmeme,
[It occurred to me that when we get married,]
I would have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
bude se muset Else stát malá nehoda.
[Else it would have become a little accident.]
Hans! No. Stop.
Hansi! Přestaň.
[Hansi! Stop.]
But then, she doomed herself,
Ale pak se odepsala sama
[But then she wrote back]
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
a tys byla tak hloupá, že jsi za ní běžela.
[and you were so stupid that you ran after her.]
Please.
Prosím.
[Please.]
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
Jediné, co mi zbývá, je zabít Elsu
[The only thing I have left is to kill Elsa]
and bring back summer.
a přivolat zpět léto.
[and summon back the summer.]
You're no match for Elsa.
Ty se Else nikdy nevyrovnáš.
[You never Else nevyrovnáš.]
No, you're no match for Elsa.
Ne, ty se Else nevyrovnáš.
[No, I'm Else nevyrovnáš.]
I, on the other hand,
Víš, co teď jsem?
[You know what I am?]
am the hero who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
Jsem hrdina, který zachrání Arendelle před zničením.
[I am a hero who saves Arendelle from destruction.]
You won't get away with this.
Tohle ti neprojde.
[That it will not pass.]
Oh...
I already have.
Už mi to prošlo.
[Have I got away with it.]
Please, somebody, help.
Prosím, pomozte mi někdo.
[Please, somebody help me.]
Please. Please.
Prosím. Prosím.
[Please. Please.]
It's getting colder by the minute.
S každou minutou je chladněji.
[With every passing minute is cooler.]
If we don't do something soon, we'll all freeze to death.
Jestli něco neuděláme, všichni tu umrzneme.
[If we do not do something, all the freeze.]
Prince Hans.
Princi Hansi.
[Prince Hans.]
Princess Anna is...
Princezna Anna...
[Princess Anne...]
Dead.
...je mrtvá.
[...is dead.]
What?
Cože?
[What?]
What happened to her?
Co se jí přihodilo?
[What had happened?]
She was killed...
Byla zavražděna.
[She was murdered.]
... by Queen Elsa.
Královnou Elsou.
[Queen Elsa.]
No!
Ne!
[No!]
Her own sister.
Vlastní sestrou?
[Own sister?]
At least we got to say our marriage vows
Ale stačili jsme si dát manželský slib,
[But we were able to give vows]
before she died in my arms.
než mi zemřela v náručí.
[before she died in my arms.]
There can be no doubt now.
Už není pochyb o tom,
[There's no doubt about it,]
Queen Elsa is a monster,
že královna Elsa je monstrum
[Elsa is the queen monster]
and we are all in grave danger.
a že jsme ve smrtelném nebezpečí.
[and that we are in mortal danger.]
Prince Hans,
Princi Hansi...
[In Prince Hans...]
Arendelle looks to you.
Arendelle k vám vzhlíží.
[Arendelle looks up to you.]
With a heavy heart,
S těžkým srdcem...
[With a heavy heart...]
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason.
...obviňuji královnu Elsu Arendellskou z velezrady.
[... Queen Elsa Arendellskou accuse of treason.]
And sentence her to death.
A odsuzuji ji k smrti.
[And I condemn her to death.]
Hurry up!
Pospěšte!
[Hurry!]
She's dangerous.
Je nebezpečná.
[It is dangerous.]
Move quickly. Careful!
Jednejte rychle. Pozor.
[Act quickly. Attention.]
It won't open! It's frozen shut.
Nejdou otevřít!
[Will not open!]
Put your back into it!
Jsou přimrzlé.
[They're frozen.]
Come on! Push!
What is it, buddy?
Copak je, Svene?
[What is it, Sven?]
Hey, watch it.
Pozor!
[Beware!]
What's wrong with you?
Co to do tebe vjelo?
[What's gotten into you?]
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
Nerozumím, když tak huhláš.
[I do not understand when so huhláš.]
Stop it! Put me down!
Přestaň! Hned mě pusť!
[Stop it! Just let me go!]
No, Sven!
Ne, Svene!
[No, Sven!]
We're not going back.
Tam se nevrátíme.
[There will not return.]
She's with her true love.
Je se svou pravou láskou.
[It is her true love.]
What the...
Co to...
[What the...]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Come on! Come on, boy.
Dělej!
[Hurry!]
Help.
Pomoc.
[Help.]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Oh, no.
Ne.
[No.]
Olaf?
[Olaf?]
Olaf. Get away from there.
Olafe, uteč odtamtud!
[Olaf, get out there!]
Wow!
So, this is heat.
Tak tohle je horko.
[So this is hot.]
I love it.
Líbí se mi.
[I like.]
Ooh! But don't touch it.
Ale nesahat.
[But do not touch.]
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
Kde je Hans? Neměl tě políbit?
[Where is Hans? He did not kiss you?]
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
Já se v něm zmýlila. On mě nemiluje.
[I do it wrong. He loves me not.]
But we ran all the way here.
Vždyť jsme za ním běželi.
[But we ran behind him.]
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here. You'll melt.
Prosím, Olafe, tady nemůžeš zůstat. Roztaješ.
[Please, Olaf, you can not stay here. Roztaješ.]
I am not leaving here until
Neodejdu, dokud nepřijdeme
[I'm not leaving until we come]
we find some other act of true love to save you.
na jiný projev pravé lásky.
[on another manifestation of true love.]
Do you happen to have any ideas?
Měla bys nějaký nápad?
[You should have an idea?]
I don't even know what love is.
Vždyť ani nevím, co to láska je.
[I do not even know what love is.]
That's okay, I do.
To neva. Já jo.
[Never mind. I do.]
Love is
Láska je,
[Love is,]
putting someone else's needs before yours.
když myslíš na druhého víc než na sebe.
[when you think of other more than themselves.]
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans and left you forever.
Jako když tě Kristoff dovezl sem za Hansem a pak tě navždy opustil.
[Like when you Kristoff brought here as Hans and then I passed away.]
Kristoff loves me?
Kristoff mě miluje?
[Kristoff loves me?]
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
Páni. Ty vážně nevíš o lásce vůbec nic, že ne?
[Wow. You really do not know anything about love, do you?]
Olaf, you're melting.
Olafe, rozpouštíš se.
[Olaf, melt it.]
Some people are worth melting for.
Někteří lidé za oběti stojí.
[Some people stand behind the victims.]
Just maybe not right this second.
Ale možná to nemusí být hned.
[But it may not be right.]
Don't worry, I've got it.
Neboj, hned to zavřu.
[Do not worry, once it closes.]
We're gonna get through... Oh, wait.
Nějak se z toho spolu... Počkat.
[Somehow it together... Wait.]
Hang on, I'm getting something.
Vydrž, něco merčím.
[Hang on, something Mercia.]
It's Kristoff and Sven!
To je Kristoff a Sven!
[That's Kristoff and Sven!]
They're coming back this way.
A vrací se k nám!
[And coming back to us!]
They... They are?
Opravdu?
[Really?]
Wow! He's really moving fast.
Páni. Jsou rychlí jako blesk.
[Wow. They are fast as lightning.]
I guess I was wrong.
Asi jsem se mýlil.
[I guess I was wrong.]
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
Kristoff tě asi nemiluje tak, aby tě opustil.
[Kristoff probably loves you so that you left.]
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
Pomoz mi, Olafe. Prosím.
[Help me, Olaf. Please.]
No, no, no! You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
Ne! Musíš zůstat u ohně a hřát se.
[No! You have to stay by the fire and get warm.]
I need to get to Kristoff.
Ale já musím za Kristoffem.
[But I have for Kristoff.]
Why?
Proč?
[Why?]
Oh, I know why!
Já už vím proč.
[I already know why.]
There's your act of true love right there!
To je ten projev pravé lásky.
[This is the manifestation of true love.]
Riding across the fjords like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
Jede za tebou na smradlavém sobovi jako rytíř.
[He goes behind you stinking reindeer as a knight.]
Come on!
Jdeme!
[Come on!]
Look out!
Bacha!
[Bach!]
Oh!
Uh... Back this way.
Zpátky, poběž!
[Back, Come on!]
We're trapped.
Jsme v pasti.
[We're trapped.]
Oh...
Whoa!
Slide, Anna!
Sklouzni se, Anno!
[Slip it is, Anna!]
We made it!
Zvládli jsme to!
[We did it!]
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Běž, běž, běž!
[Go, Go, Go!]
Come on, buddy, faster.
Přidej, Svene!
[Add, Sven!]
Kristoff!
Kristoffe!
[Kristoff!]
Keep going!
Nezastavuj se!
[Keep going!]
Kristoff!
Kristoffe!
[Kristoff!]
Come on!
Přidej!
[Join!]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
Whoa!
Sven!
Svene!
[Sven!]
Good boy.
Šikula.
[Šikula.]
Kristoff.
Kristoffe.
[Kristoff.]
Kristoff...
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Elso! Přede mnou neutečeš!
[Elso! You can not escape from me!]
Just take care of my sister.
Postarej se o mou sestru.
[Take care of my sister.]
Your sister?
Tvou sestru?
[Your sister?]
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
Vrátila se z hory slabá a zmrzlá.
[She came back from the mountains weak and frozen.]
She said that you froze her heart.
Říkala, žes jí zmrazila srdce.
[She said you froze her heart.]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
Snažil jsem se ji zachránit, ale bylo pozdě.
[I tried to save her but it was too late.]
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
Pleť měla ledovou, vlasy jí zbělaly.
[Her skin was icy, her hair turned white.]
Your sister is dead.
Tvá sestra je mrtvá.
[Your sister is dead.]
Because of you.
Jen kvůli tobě.
[Because of you.]
No.
Ne.
[No.]
Kristoff.
Kristoffe!
[Kristoff!]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Elsa?
No!
Ne!
[No!]
Anna!
Anno!
[Anna!]
Oh. Anna!
Anno...
[Anno...]
No, no!
Ne.
[No.]
Please, no.
Prosím, ne.
[Please no.]
Anna?
Anno?
[Anna?]
Anna?
Anno?
[Anna?]
Oh, Elsa.
Elso.
[Elso.]
You sacrificed yourself for me?
Ty ses pro mě obětovala?
[You've sacrificed for me?]
I love you.
Mám tě ráda.
[I love you.]
"An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart."
Projev pravé lásky, co rozehřál ledové srdce.
[Manifestation of true love that warmed icy heart.]
"Love will thaw."
Láska zahřívá.
[Love heats.]
Love. Of course.
Láska. Ovšem.
[Love. Of course.]
Elsa?
Elso?
[Elso?]
Love!
Láska.
[Love.]
I knew you could do it.
Já věděla, že to dokážeš.
[I knew you could do it.]
Hands down, this is the best day of my life.
Přiznávám, že tohle je nejlepší den mého života.
[I confess that this is the best day of my life.]
And, quite possibly, the last.
A zřejmě i poslední.
[And probably the last.]
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Olafe! Vydrž, mrňousi!
[Olaf! Hang on, kid!]
Oh, Oh, Oh!
My own personal flurry!
Můj osobní sněhový mráček!
[My personal cloud in the snow!]
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
Anno?
[Anna?]
But she froze your heart.
Vždyť ti zmrazila srdce.
[For those frozen hearts.]
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
Jediný, kdo tu má ledové srdce, jsi ty.
[Only one who has a cold heart is you.]
Wonderful!
Krása!
[Beauty!]
Setting course, sir.
Nastavuji kurs, pane.
[Setting course, sir.]
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
Odvezu toho lotra do jeho domoviny.
[I'll take the bastard to his homeland.]
We shall see what his twelve big brothers think of his behavior.
Uvidíme, co si o jeho chování pomyslí jeho dvanáct bratrů.
[We'll see what he thinks about his behavior, his twelve brothers.]
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
Arendelle vám děkuje, můj pane.
[Arendelle thanks you, my lord.]
This is unacceptable.
To je do nebe volající.
[This is blatant.]
I am a victim of fear. I've been traumatized.
Jsem obětí strachu, mám traumata.
[I am a victim of fear, I traumas.]
Ah! My neck hurts.
Mám ústřel.
[I have lumbago.]
Is there a doctor that I could see?
Potřebuji doktora, jste snad slepí?
[I need a doctor, are you blind?]
And I demand to see the queen!
Žádám slyšení u královny!
[I request an audience with the Queen!]
Oh. I have a message from the queen.
Mám pro vás od královny vzkaz.
[I have a message from the Queen.]
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever
Arendelle tímto navždy ukončuje...
[Arendelle hereby terminated forever...]
"no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown."
...veškeré obchodní styky s vévodou z Kradákova.
[... all its dealings with the Duke of Kradákova.]
"Weselton."
Kravákova.
[Kravákova.]
It's Weselton!
Je to Kravákov!
[It Kravákov!]
Come on, come on, come on!
Poběž, poběž, poběž!
[Come on, Come on, Come on!]
Okay, okay, here I come.
Dobře. Už běžím.
[Okay. I'm coming.]
Pole! - Whoops! Sorry.
Lampa. - Hopla. Pardon.
[Lamp. - Whoops. Sorry.]
Okay, Okay.
Tak jo.
[So yeah.]
Here we are. Oh!
Jdeme na to.
[Here we go.]
I owe you a sled.
Tvé nové sáně.
[Your new sled.]
Are you serious? - Yes!
To myslíš vážně? - Jo!
[Are you serious? - Yeah!]
And it's the latest model.
Je to nejnovější model.
[It's the latest model.]
No, I can't accept this.
To nemůžu přijmout.
[I can not accept.]
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
Musíš. Koukej mlčet. Ani slovo. Rozkaz královny.
[You have to. Look silent. Not a word. Queen orders.]
She's named you the Official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
Oficiálně tě jmenovala arendellským královským ledařem.
[He officially named arendellským royal iceman.]
What? That's not a thing. - Oh, sure it is.
Cože? Nic takového není. - Jasně že je.
[What? Nothing like this. - Sure it is.]
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
Je tam i držáček na kelímky. Líbí se ti?
[There is also the tab on the cups. Do you like her?]
Like it? I love it!
Líbí? Jsem nadšený!
[Like it? I'm excited!]
Whoa.
I could kiss you!
Dám ti pusu.
[I'll give you a kiss.]
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd...
Rád bych... chci říct, moc chci.
[I would like... I mean, I want too.]
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
Můžu? Můžeme... chci říct, smím to?
[Can I? I... I mean, can I do it?]
Wait, what?
Cože?
[What?]
We may.
Můžeme.
[We can.]
Summer!
Léto!
[Summer!]
Ooh...
Hello.
Ahoj.
[Hey.]
Are you ready?
Můžu začít?
[Can I start?]
Ice!
Swing me.
Postrč mě!
[Nudge me!]
Ooh...
I like the open gates.
Ty otevřené brány se mi líbí.
[They opened the gate I like.]
We are never closing them again.
Už nikdy je nezavřeme.
[We never close.]
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful, but you know I don't skate.
Elso, jsou krásné, ale víš, že neumím bruslit.
[Elso are nice, but you know I can not skate.]
Come on! You can do it!
Jen pojď, to zvládneš.
[Come on, do it.]
Look out. Reindeer coming through.
Pozor! Místo pro soba.
[Beware! Instead of reindeer.]
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
Jde mi to, jde mi to. Nejde mi to, nejde mi to!
[It comes to me, comes to me. It's not me, not me!]
Hey, guys!
Holky!
[Girls!]
That's it, Olaf.
Bezva, Olafe.
[Great, Olaf.]
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.
Skluz a odraz. Skluz a odraz.
[Slippage and reflection. Slippage and reflection.]