Born of cold and winter air
Né au sommet des montagnes
[Born on mountaintops]
And mountain rain combining
Arrosé de pluie gelée
[Watered jelly rain]
This icy force both foul and fair
Ce lac de neige cache un trésor
[The Snow Lake hides a treasure]
Has a frozen heart worth mining
très précieux qu'il faut mériter
[very valuable to be earned]
So cut through the heart
On coupe dans le vent
[Is cut in the wind]
Cold and clear
Du matin
[In the morning]
Strike for love and strike for fear
Le travail chasse le chagrin
[The job hunt grief]
See the beauty sharp and sheer
À la force de tes mains
[On the strength of your hands]
Split the ice apart
Brise la carapace
[Break the shell]
And break the frozen heart
À nous le cœur de glace
[Own the icy heart]
Watch your step! Let it go!
On soulève! En avant!
[Is lifted! Forward!]
Hup, ho
Et hup! Ho!
[And hup! Ho!]
Watch your step! Let it go!
On soulève! En avant!
[Is lifted! Forward!]
Beautiful! Powerful!
Magnifique! Fantastique!
[Gorgeous! Fantastic!]
Dangerous! Cold!
Dangereux! Froid!
[Dangerous! Cold!]
Ice has a magic can't be controlled
La nature reprend toujours ses droits
[Nature always takes its course]
Stronger than one
Plus forte que moi!
[Stronger than me!]
Stronger than ten
Plus forte que nous!
[Stronger than us!]
Stronger than a hundred men!
La glace est plus forte que tout!
[The ice is stronger than anything!]
Oh!
Born of cold and winter air
Né au sommet des montagnes
[Born on mountaintops]
And mountain rain combining
Arrosé de pluie gelée!
[Rain drizzled with jelly!]
This icy force both foul and fair
Ce lac de neige cache un trésor
[The Snow Lake hides a treasure]
Has a frozen heart worth mining
très précieux qu'il faut mériter!
[very valuable to be earned!]
Cut through the heart
On coupe dans le vent
[Is cut in the wind]
Cold and clear
Du matin!
[In the morning!]
Strike for love and strike for fear
Le travail chasse le chagrin!
[The job hunt grief!]
There's beauty and there's danger here
Quand la passion vient d'aussi loin
[When passion comes from as far]
Split the ice apart
Le danger s'efface!
[The danger is cleared!]
Beware the frozen heart
Et gare au cœur de glace...
[And ice station in the heart of...]
Come on, Sven.
Plus vite, Sven.
[Faster, Sven.]
Elsa. Psst!
Elsa!
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
Réveille-toi. Réveille-toi. Réveille-toi!
[Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!]
Anna, go back to sleep.
Anna, retourne te coucher.
[Anna ; lie down again.]
I just can't.
Je ne peux plus dormir.
[I can not sleep.]
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
Le ciel s'est réveillé. Alors je me suis réveillée.
[The sky woke up. Then I woke up.]
So, we have to play.
Et c'est l'heure de jouer.
[And it's time to play.]
Go play by yourself.
Tu peux jouer toute seule.
[You can play alone.]
Do you want to build a snowman?
Tu veux faire un bonhomme de neige?
[You want to make a snowman?]
Come on, come on, come on!
Allez, dépêche-toi! Dépêche-toi! Dépêche-toi!
[Come on, hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!]
Do the magic! Do the magic!
Fais-moi un tour de magie! Fais-moi un tour de magie!
[Do me a magic trick! Do me a magic trick!]
Oh...
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
- T'es prête? - Uh-huh.
[- Are you ready? - Uh-huh.]
This is amazing!
Oh c'est beau! Encore!
[Oh how beautiful! Again!]
Watch this!
Regarde!
[Look!]
Hi, I'm Olaf, and I like warm hugs.
Bonjour, je m'appelle Olaf et j'adore les câlins.
[Hello, my name is Olaf and I love cuddling.]
I love you, Olaf!
Je t'aime, Olaf!
[I love you, Olaf!]
Olaf...
Tickle bumps!
C'est parti!
[Let's go!]
Oh!
Hang on!
Attention!
[Warning!]
Catch me!
Attrape-moi!
[Catch me!]
Gotcha!
Again!
Encore!
[Again!]
Wait!
Attends!
[Wait!]
- Whoo-hoo! - Slow down!
Pas si vite!
[Not so fast!]
Whoo!
Anna!
Mama! Papa!
Maman! Papa!
[Mom! Dad!]
No, no...
Non..
[No..]
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
Ça va aller Anna, je suis là.
[Anna It's okay, I'm here.]
Elsa, what have you done?
Elsa, qu'est-ce que tu as fait?
[Elsa, what do you do?]
This is getting out of hand.
Tout ceci a assez duré!
[This has gone on long enough!]
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
C'était un accident. Je suis désolée, Anna!
[It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!]
Oh. She's ice cold.
Oh. Elle est frigorifiée.
[Oh. It is refrigerated.]
I know where we have to go.
Je sais où nous devons aller.
[I know where we must go.]
Ice?
La glace?
[Ice?]
Faster, Sven.
Plus vite, Sven.
[Faster, Sven.]
Sven!
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
Je vous en prie! Aidez-nous! C'est.. c'est ma fille.
[You're welcome! Help us! It's.. it's my daughter.]
It's the king.
C'est le roi.
[It is the king.]
Trolls?
Des trolls?
[Trolls?]
Shush! I'm trying to listen.
Chut! J'essaye d'écouter.
[Hush! I try to listen.]
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Mes chéris, je vais vous garder avec moi.
[My darlings, I will keep you with me.]
Your Majesty.
Votre majesté.
[Your Majesty.]
Born with the powers, or cursed?
Est-elle née avec ses pouvoirs?
[Are they born with their powers?]
Born. And they're getting stronger.
Absolument. Et ils deviennent de plus en plus forts.
[Absolutely. And they become increasingly strong.]
Here, here.
Approchez-la.
[Approach it.]
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
Heureusement son cœur n'a pas été touché.
[Fortunately his heart was not affected.]
The heart is not so easily changed.
Il aurait été très difficile de la guérir si cela était le cas.
[It would have been very difficult to cure it if that were the case.]
But the head can be persuaded.
Mais, dans la tête, ça peut s'arranger.
[But, in the head, that can be arranged.]
Do what you must.
Faites au mieux.
[Do your best.]
I recommend we remove all magic.
Je recommande d'enlever toute trace de magie.
[I recommend to remove any trace of magic.]
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
Même les souvenirs de cette magie. C'est plus prudent.
[Even the memories of this magic. It is more careful.]
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
Mais ne vous inquietez pas, elle se souviendra des bons moments.
[But do not worry, she will remember the good times.]
She will be okay.
Elle ira bien maintenant.
[She will be fine now.]
But she won't remember I have powers?
Mais elle ne se souviendra pas de mes pouvoirs?
[But she will not remember of my powers?]
It's for the best.
C'est mieux ainsi.
[It's better that way.]
Listen to me, Elsa. Your power will only grow.
Écoute-moi, Elsa.
Tes pouvoirs, ne vont cesser de grandir.
There is beauty in it...
Ta magie est pleine de beauté...
[Your magic is full of beauty...]
But also great danger.
mais elle représente un vrai danger.
[but it represents a real danger.]
You must learn to control it.
Tu dois apprendre à la contrôler.
[You must learn to control it.]
Fear will be your enemy.
La peur sera ton pire ennemi.
[Fear is your worst enemy.]
No!
Non!
[No!]
We'll protect her.
Nous la protègerons.
[We will protect.]
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
Elle peut apprendre à les contrôler. J'en suis sûr.
[It can learn to control them. I'm sure.]
Until then...
Mais d'ici là...
[But until then...]
We'll lock the gates.
Nous fermerons le château.
[We will close the castle.]
We'll reduce the staff.
Nous réduirons nos effectifs.
[We will reduce our workforce.]
We will limit her contact with people,
Nous limiterons ses contacts avec l'extérieur.
[We will limit its contacts with the outside.]
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
Ainsi, personne n'aura connaissance de ses pouvoirs.
[Thus, no one will know of its powers.]
Including Anna.
Y compris Anna.
[Including Anna.]
Elsa?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige
[I would like a snowman]
Come on, let's go and play
Oh, viens jouer avec moi!
[Oh, come play with me!]
I never see you any more
Tu te caches, on ne se voit plus
[You hide, we do not see more]
Come out the door
Dis que fais-tu?
[Say what do you do?]
It's like you've gone away
Tu n'es plus vraiment toi
[You're really over you]
We used to be best buddies, and now we're not
Nous étions sœurs et amies Mais c'est fini
[We were sisters and girlfriends But it's over]
I wish you would tell me why
J'aimerais savoir pourquoi!
[I wonder why!]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige
[I would like a snowman]
It doesn't have to be a snowman
Oui, s'il te plaît un bonhomme de neige...
[Yes, please a snowman...]
Go away, Anna.
Va-t'en, Anna.
[Go away, Anna.]
Okay, bye
Pense à moi...
[Think about me...]
The gloves will help.
Ces gants t'aideront.
[These gloves will help you.]
See? Conceal it.
Voilà. Tout est caché.
[Here. Everything is hidden.]
Don't feel it.
Cache tes pouvoirs.
[Cover your powers.]
Don't let it show.
N'en parle pas.
[Do not mention it.]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige
[I would like a snowman]
Or ride our bike around the halls?
Ou faire du vélo dans la cour
[Or biking in the courtyard]
I think some company is overdue
Je suis une fille en manque de compagnie
[I am a girl in need of company]
I've started talking to the pictures on the walls
Je parle aux murs et à ces portraits qui m'entourent!
[I talk to the walls and portraits around me!]
Hang in there, Joan.
Salut Jeanne d'Arc!
[Hi Joan of Arc!]
It gets a little lonely, all these empty rooms
Je suis seule et je m'ennuie Tu restes de glace
[I am alone and I miss you ice remains]
Just watching the hours tick by
Et moi j'attends que les heures passent...
[And I expect that the hours pass...]
I'm scared.
J'ai peur.
[I am afraid.]
It's getting stronger!
Mes pouvoirs sont de plus en plus forts!
[My powers are growing stronger!]
Getting upset only makes it worse. Calm down.
La colère ne ferait qu'empirer les choses. Calme-toi.
[Anger would only worsen things. Calm down.]
No! Don't touch me!
Non! Ne me touchez pas!
[No! Do not touch me!]
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
Je vous en prie, je ne veux pas vous faire de mal.
[Please, I do not want to hurt you.]
See you in two weeks!
On se revoit dans deux semaines.
[See you in two weeks.]
Do you have to go?
Faut-il vraiment que vous partiez?
[Do we really need you to leave?]
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Ne t'en fais pas, tout ira bien Elsa.
[Do not do not worry, everything will be fine Elsa.]
Your Highness.
Votre majesté.
[Your Majesty.]
Elsa?
Please, I know you're in there
Peux-tu ouvrir cette porte?
[Can you open that door?]
People are asking where you've been
Pourquoi restes-tu enfermée?
[Why are you locked up?]
They say "Have courage", and I'm trying to
On me dit "sois forte, le temps arrange tout"
[They told me" be strong, time heals everything"]
I'm right out here for you
Mais j'ai besoin de nous
[But I need us]
Just let me in
Pour oublier
[To forget]
We only have each other; it's just you and me
Que nous n'avons plus personne; plus aucune famille
[We have no one left ; no more family]
What are we gonna do?
Quel avenir pour nous?
[What future for us?]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige...
[I would like a snowman...]
All ashore!
On lève l'ancre!
[It sets sail!]
Welcome to Arendelle!
Bienvenue à Arendelle!
[Welcome to Arendelle!]
Ahh, merci, monsieur.
Oh, merci monsieur.
[Oh, thank you sir.]
Watch your step, please.
Attention où vous marchez.
[Mind your step.]
The gates will be opening soon.
Les portes vont bientôt s'ouvrir.
[The doors will soon open.]
Why do I have to wear this?
Pourquoi dois-je porter un costume?
[Why should I wear a suit?]
Because the queen has come of age.
Parce que la reine est en âge d'accéder au throne.
[Because the queen is old enough to access the throne.]
It's Coronation Day!
C'est le jour du couronnement!
[It is the day of the coronation!]
That's not my fault.
Ce n'est pas de ma faute.
[It is not my fault.]
What do you want, Sven?
Qu'est-ce que tu veux, Sven?
[What do you want, Sven?]
"Give me a snack."
"Donne-moi une carotte."
[" Give me a carrot."]
What's the magic word?
Quel est le mot magique?
[What's the magic word?]
"Please."
"S'il te plaît."
["Please."]
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. On partage.
[Uh! Uh- uh-uh. We share.]
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
Je n'arrive pas à croire. Ils vont enfin ouvrir les portes du château!
[I do not believe. They will finally open the doors of the castle!]
And for a whole day! Faster, Percy!
Et pour toute la journée! Dépêche-toi, William!
[And for the whole day! Hurry up, William!]
Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
Arendelle, notre partenaire commercial le plus mysterieux.
[Arendelle our most mysterious business partner.]
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets and exploit your riches.
Ouvrez ces portes que je puisse percer vos secrets et exploiter vos richesses.
[Open those doors I could break your secrets and exploit your wealth.]
Did I say that out loud?
Ai-je dit cela à voix haute?
[Did I say that out loud?]
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait to see the queen and the princess.
Oh! Vous n'imaginez pas à quel point j'ai hâte de voir la reine et la princesse.
[Oh! You can not imagine how much I look forward to seeing the queen and the princess.]
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
Je suis sûr qu'elles sont de toute beauté.
[I'm sure they are beautiful.]
I bet they are beautiful.
Oui, elles doivent être éblouissantes.
[Yes, they must be dazzling.]
Princess Anna?
Princesse Anna?
[Princess Anna?]
Huh? Yeah?
Huh? Oui?
[Huh? Yes?]
Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
Oh. Désolé de vous réveiller, madame.
[Oh. Sorry to wake you, ma'am.]
No, no, no, you didn't.
Non, non, non, j'étais levée.
[No, no, no, I was thrown.]
I've been up for hours.
Je suis debout depuis des heures.
[I am standing for hours.]
Who is it?
Qui est là?
[Who is here?]
Still me, ma'am.
Toujours moi, mademoiselle.
[Always me, miss.]
The gates will open soon. Time to get ready.
Les portes vont bientôt s'ouvrir. Il faut vous préparer.
[The doors will soon open. We must prepare.]
Of course.
Oui, bien sûr.
[Yes of course.]
Ready for what?
Me préparer pour quoi?
[Prepare me for what?]
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
Pour le couronnement de votre sœur, mademoiselle.
[For the crowning of your sister, miss.]
My sister's corneration.
Le couronnement de ma sœur.
[The coronation of my sister.]
It's Coronation Day!
Le couronnement, bien sûr!
[The coronation of course!]
It's Coronation Day!
C'est le jour du couronnement!
[It is the day of the coronation!]
The window is open!
Ouvrez les volets
[Open the shutters]
So's that door!
dans le salon!
[in the living room!]
I didn't know they did that any more
Laissez entrer cet air, il sent si bon
[Let in the air, it feels so good]
Who knew we owned 8,000 salad plates?
Et mettez les petits plats dans les grands!
[And put the dishes in large!]
For years I've roamed these empty halls
J'étais seule dans ces longs couloirs
[I was alone in the long corridors]
Why have a ballroom with no balls?
Il n'y avait pas de bal le soir
[There was no evening ball]
Finally, they're opening up the gates!
Enfin nous entrons dans l'air du temps!
[Finally we enter the times!]
There'll be actual, real, live people
Les invités seront bien vivants
[Guests will be alive]
It'll be totally strange
Et tant pis si cela dérange
[And even if it bothers]
But wow! Am I so ready for this change!
Mais moi j'avais tellement hâte que ça change!
[But I could not wait to change that!]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Et je vais fêter ce renouveau
[And I will celebrate this renewal]
There'll be music, there'll be light
Dans ma robe de satin
[In my satin dress]
For the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
I'll be dancing through the night
En dansant jusqu'au matin
[Dancing until morning]
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
Enflammée, exaltée, surexcitée
[Fiery, enthusiastic, excited]
But I'm somewhere in that zone
Ils peuvent bien dire ce qu'ils veulent
[They can say what they want]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
I won't be alone
Je ne serai plus seule
[I will not be alone]
I can't wait to meet everyone!
J'ai hâte d'accueillir tous les invités!
[I look forward to welcoming all guests!]
What if I meet The One?
Et si je rencontrais l'homme de ma vie?
[And if I met the man of my life?]
Tonight, imagine me gown and all
Ce soir je serai la plus belle
[Tonight I'll be the most beautiful]
Fetchingly draped against the wall
Dans une tenue des plus formelles
[In a more formal outfit]
The picture of sophisticated grace
Une jeune fille raffinée et pleine de grâce
[A young girl refined and full of grace]
I suddenly see him standing there
Il va apparaître tout à coup
[He will appear suddenly]
A beautiful stranger, tall and fair
Ce bel inconnu qui saura tout
[This handsome stranger who will know everything]
I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face!
Le chocolat m'aidera à faire face
[The chocolate will help me cope]
But then we laugh and talk all evening
Puis, nous parlerons toute la soirée
[Then we'll talk all night]
Which is totally bizarre
Et je me sentirai bizarre
[And I will feel weird]
Nothing like the life I've led so far
Car changer de vie c'est tout un art!
[For change of life is an art!]
For the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
There'll be magic, there'll be fun
Dans la magie d'une histoire
[In the magic of a story]
For the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
I could be noticed by someone
Qui me donne tellement d'espoir
[That gives me so much hope]
And I know it is totally crazy
Je sais que ce n'est pas raisonnable
[I know it is not reasonable]
To dream I'd find romance
De rêver de romance
[To dream romance]
But for the first time in forever
Mais je vais fêter ce renouveau
[But I will celebrate this renewal]
At least I've got a chance!
Je tenterai ma chance!
[I will try my luck!]
Don't let them in
Cache tes pouvoirs
[Cover your powers]
Don't let them see
N'en parle pas
[Do not mention it]
Be the good girl you always have to be
Fais attention, le secret survivra
[Be careful, the secret will survive]
Conceal, don't feel
Sereine, sanse peine
[Serene, barely sanse]
Put on a show
Tu règneras...
[You may reign...]
Make one wrong move and everyone will know
Un seul faux pas et tout le monde saura
[One wrong step and everybody will know]
But it's only for today
Mais ce n'est qu'une seule journée
[But this is only one day]
It's only for today
Ce n'est qu'une seule journée!
[It's only one day!]
It's agony to wait
La pression est si forte
[Pressure is so strong]
It's agony to wait
La pression est si forte
[Pressure is so strong]
Tell the guards to open up
Dites aux gardes qu'il faut ouvrir
[Tell the guards to open it]
The gate
Les portes!
[The doors!]
The gate
Les portes!
[The doors!]
For the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Cache tes pouvoirs, n'en parle pas
[Cover your powers, do not talk]
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of
Qui m'apporte ce dont j'ai rêvé
[Which brings me what I dreamed]
Be the good girl you always have to be
Fais attention, le secret survivra
[Be careful, the secret will survive]
A chance to change my lonely world
Je veux quitter ma tour d'ivoire
[I want to leave my ivory tower]
Conceal
Sois sage...
[Be good...]
A chance to find true love
Trouver l'amour ce soir!
[Find love tonight!]
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Pas d'états d'âme, de sentiments
[No moods, feelings]
I know it all ends tomorrow
Je sens que c'est le bon moment
[I feel it is the right time]
So it has to be today!
C'est maintenant ou jamais
[It's now or never]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Et je vais fêter ce renouveau
[And I will celebrate this renewal]
For the first time in forever
Je vais fêter ce renouveau
[I will celebrate this renewal]
Nothing's in my way!
Faire ce qui me plaît!
[Do what I like!]
Hey!
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Je suis désolé. Êtes-vous blessée?
[I am sorry. Are you hurt?]
Hey.
Salut.
[Hi.]
Uh... No, no, I'm okay.
Oui, euh... Non non, je vais, je vais bien.
[Yes, uh... No, no, I'm going, I'm fine.]
Are you sure?
Vous en êtes sûre?
[Are you sure?]
Yeah. I just wasn't looking where I was going.
Oui. En fait je ne regardais pas où j'allais.
[Yes I do. In fact I was not watching where I was going.]
But I'm great, actually.
Mais je vais bien, même très bien.
[But I am well, very well.]
Oh... Thank goodness.
Oh... J'ai eu si peur.
[Oh... I was so scared.]
Oh! Uh...
Oh! Euh...
[Oh! Uh...]
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Prince Hans des Îles du Sud.
[Prince Hans Southern Islands.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Princesse Anna d'Arendelle.
[Princess Anna Arendelle.]
"Princess"? My Lady.
"Princesse"? Majesté.
["Princess"? Majesty.]
Oh!
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Um... Whew.
Hi. Again.
Salut. Ça va?
[Hi. How are you?]
Oh, boy!
Désolé.
[Sorry.]
This is awkward.
C'est un peu bizarre.
[It's a little weird.]
Not "You're awkward", but just because we're...
Pas que vous soyez bizarre! Non, c'est la situation qui est bizarre.
[Not that you're weird! No, this is the situation which is weird.]
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous. Wait, what?
Vous êtes très beau. Qu'est-ce que je dis?
[You are very handsome. What do I say?]
I'd like to formally apologize
Je tiens sincèrement à m'excuser
[I sincerely apologize]
for hitting the princess of Arendelle with my horse.
d'avoir heurter la princesse d'Arendelle avec mon cheval
[to have hit the princess with my horse Arendelle]
And for every moment after.
et, pour ce qui s'est passé par la suite.
[and, for this happened subsequently.]
No! No, no. It's fine.
Non! Non non non, tout va bien.
[No! No no no, all is well.]
I'm not that princess.
Je ne suis pas cette princesse-là.
[I'm not the princess then.]
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
Je veux dire, si vous aviez heurté ma sœur Elsa
[I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa]
it would be... Yeesh!
ça aurait été... Aïïïe!
[it would have been... Aïïïe!]
Because, you know...
Évidemment...
[Obviously...]
Hello.
Salut.
[Hi.]
But, lucky you,
Mais, heureusement pour vous
[But, fortunately for you]
It's just me.
Ce n'est que moi.
[Only me.]
"Just" you?
Ce n'est "que" vous?
[It's"only" you?]
The bells. The coronation.
Les cloches. Le couronnement.
[The bells. The crowning.]
I better go.
Je.. je.. je dois vraiment y aller.
[I.. I.. I really have to go.]
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Désolée. Je.. je.. je dois y aller.
[Sorry. I.. I.. I have to go.]
Bye!
Au revoir!
[Goodbye!]
Oh, no. Oh!
Oh non. Ah!
[Oh no. Ah!]
Your Majesty, the gloves.
Votre Majesté, les gants.
[Your Majesty, gloves.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
La reine Elsa d'Arendelle.
[Queen Elsa Arendelle.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
La reine Elsa d'Arendelle!
[Queen Elsa Arendelle!]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
La reine Elsa d'Arendelle.
[Queen Elsa Arendelle.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
La princesse Anna d'Arendelle.
[Anna's Arendelle princess.]
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Oh. Là-bas? Vous êtes sûr?
[Oh. Over there? Are you sure?]
Because I don't think I'm supposed to...
Car je ne crois pas que je suis censée...
[Because I do not think I'm supposed to...]
Oh. Okay.
Euh... D'accord.
[Uh... Okay.]
Hi.
"Hi" me? Oh...
"Bonjour" euh, à moi? Oh...
["Hello" uh, me? Oh...]
Um... Hi.
Euhm... Bonjour.
[Um... Hello.]
You look beautiful.
Tu es fort belle.
[You're very beautiful.]
Thank you. You look beautiful-ler.
Merci. Tu es encore plus forte belle.
[Thank you. You're even more beautiful strong.]
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
Pas "forte." Tu n'es pas grosse.
[No" strong." You're not fat.]
But more beautiful.
Tu es fort belle aussi. Encore plus belle.
[You're very beautiful too. Even more beautiful.]
Thank you.
Merci.
[Thank you.]
So...
Alors...
[So...]
This is what a party looks like.
Ça ressemble à cela une réception.
[It looks like this reception.]
It's warmer than I thought.
C'est plus chaleureux que je croyais.
[It's warmer than I thought.]
What is that amazing smell?
Quelle est cette merveilleuse odeur?
[What is that wonderful smell?]
Chocolate.
Du chocolat.
[Chocolate.]
Your Majesty.
Votre Majesté.
[Your Majesty.]
The Duke of Weaseltown.
Le Duc de Vicieux Thon.
[The Duke of Vicious Thon.]
"Weselton"! Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
"Weselton"! Duc de Weselton, votre Majesté.
[" Weselton!" Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.]
As your closest partner in trade it seems only fitting
En tant que premier partenaire commercial je me dois de vous offrir
[As the first commercial partner I have to offer you]
that I offer you your first dance as queen.
votre première danse en tant que reine.
[your first dance as queen.]
One-two, and jump.
Un, deux, trois, quatre.
[One two three four.]
Uh...
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
C'est très aimable à vous, mais je ne danse pas.
[It's very kind of you, but I do not dance.]
Oh...
But my sister does.
Mais ma sœur en sera ravie.
[But my sister will be delighted.]
What? - Oh! Lucky you.
Quoi? - Oh! Vous en avez de la chance.
[What? - Oh! You're in luck.]
Oh, I don't think...
Oh, je ne crois pas...
[Oh, I do not think...]
If you swoon, let me know. I'll catch you.
Si vous perdez connaissance, ne vous en faites pas, c'est normal.
[If you pass out, do you worry, this is normal.]
Sorry.
Désolée.
[Sorry.]
Like an agile peacock.
Regardez-moi faire le paon.
[Watch me do the peacock.]
Ow! Ow.
Aïe! Aïe.
[Ouch! Ouch.]
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
Parlant de ça, c'est fantastique de voir le château ouvert de nouveau.
[Speaking of which, it is fantastic to see the castle open again.]
Why did they shut them in the first place?
Mais pourquoi l'avait-on fermé au juste?
[But why had closed about?]
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
Connaissez-vous la raison? Hmm?
[Do you know the reason? Hmm?]
No.
Non.
Non?
All right. Hang on!
Très bien. Accrochez-vous!
[Very good. Hold on!]
They don't call me the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
J'ai bien mérité mon surnom de Faucon Pèlerin!
[I deserved my nickname Peregrine Falcon!]
Oh-ho!
[Oh- ho!]
Like a chicken with the face of a monkey, I fly.
Regardez-moi faire le coq au visage de singe, je vole.
[Watch me make coq au monkey face, I fly.]
Let me know when you're ready
Si vous voulez une autre danse
[If you want another dance]
for another round, Milady.
Majesté venez me chercher!
[Majesty come and get me!]
Well, he was sprightly.
Et bien, il a beaucoup d'énergie.
[Well, he has a lot of energy.]
Especially for a man in heels.
Surtout pour un homme qui porte des talonettes.
[Especially for a man who wears talonettes.]
Are you okay?
Est-ce que ça va?
[Are you OK?]
I've never been better. This is so nice.
Oui, je n'ai jamais été aussi heureuse. On est à nouveau réunies.
[Yes, I have never been happier. We reunited.]
I wish it could be like this all the time.
J'aimerais tellement qu'il en soit toujours ainsi.
[I would love to keep it that way.]
Me, too.
Moi aussi.
[Me too.]
But it can't.
Mais c'est impossible.
[But it's impossible.]
Why not? - It just can't.
Pourquoi ça? C'est dingue que nous... - C'est impossible, c'est tout.
[Why this? It's crazy that we... - It's impossible, that's all.]
Excuse me for a minute.
Excuse-moi une minute.
[Excuse me a minute.]
I'd be honored.
J'en serais honoré
[I would be honored]
Glad I caught you.
J'arrive au bon moment.
[I arrive at the right time.]
Hans.
I often had a whole parlor to myself to slide!
J'avais souvent la salon de réception à moi toute seule pour...
[I often had the reception room all to myself for...]
Oops!
Sorry.
Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
Vous êtes grand, ça va vous aider, c'est sûr.
[You are great, it'll help you for sure.]
Ah.
What's this?
Qu'est-ce que c'est?
[What is it?]
Uh, I was born with it.
Je suis née avec ça.
[I was born with that.]
Although, I dreamed I was kissed by a troll.
Mais un jour, j'ai rêvé qu'un troll m'avait embrassée.
[But one day I dreamed that a troll had kissed me.]
I like it.
C'est très joli.
[It looks nice.]
Yeah, the whole thing.
Oui, ni une bouchée.
[Yes, not a bite.]
You got it.
Bravo.
[Congratulations.]
Okay, wait, wait. So, you have how many brothers?
D'accord, mais attendez, attendez. Combien avez vous.. de frères?
[Okay, but wait, wait. How did you.. brothers?]
Twelve older brothers.
Et bien, j'ai douze frères ainés.
[Well, I'm twelve older brothers.]
Three of them pretended I was invisible, literally, for two years.
Trois d'entre eux ont fait comme si j'étais invisible, littéralement, pendant deux ans.
[Three of them were like I was invisible, literally, for two years.]
That's horrible.
C'est horrible.
[It's horrible.]
It's what brothers do.
C'est ce que font les frères.
[This is what the brothers.]
And sisters.
Et les sœurs, aussi.
[And sisters, too.]
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
Elsa et moi étions très proches quand nous étions enfants.
[Elsa and I were very close when we were kids.]
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
Et puis, un jour, elle m'a.. rejetée
[And then one day, she rejected..]
and I never knew why.
et je n'ai jamais su pourquoi.
[and I never knew why.]
I would never shut you out.
Je ne vous rejeterai jamais.
[I never rejeterai you.]
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
J'ai envie de vous dire une chose
totalement insensée.
I love crazy.
Allez-y, je vous en prie.
[Go ahead, please.]
All my life has been a series of doors in my face
Toute ma vie je n'ai trouvé Que des portes fermées
[All my life I have found closed doors What]
And then suddenly I bump into you
Jusqu'au jour où Je suis tombée sur vous
[Until the day I fell on you]
I was thinking the same thing, because, like...
C'est aussi le sentiment que j'ai, parce que...
[This is also the feeling I have, because...]
I've been searching my whole life to find my own place
J'ai passé mon temps À chercher ma bonne étoile
[I spent my time To find my lucky star]
And maybe it's the party talking, or the chocolate fondue
Jusqu'à cette grande fête royale Mon cœur se régale
[Until this large royal party My heart delights]
But with you
Avec vous
[With you]
But with you I found my place
Avec vous je n'hésite plus
[With you I hesitate no longer]
I see your face
Je vous ai vu
[I saw you]
And it's nothing like I've ever known before
J'ai découvert un sentiment nouveau
[I discovered a new sense]
Love is an open door!
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
Love is an open door!
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
Love is an open door
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
With you
Pour nous
[For us]
Love is an open door
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
I mean, it's crazy
Comment expliquer
[How to explain]
What?
Quoi?
[What?]
We finish each other's
Qu'un inconnu finisse
[An unknown finish]
Sandwiches
Toutes vos phrases
[All your sentences]
That's what I was gonna say!
C'est ce que j'allais vous dire!
[That's what I was going to say!]
I've never met someone
Je ne connais personne
[I do not know anyone]
Who thinks so much like me
Qui me ressemble autant
[That looks like me as much]
Jinx! Jinx again!
- Un vœux! Encore un!
[- A wish! One again!]
Our mental synchronization
Nos âmes sont comme synchronisées
Une seule façon de l'expliquer
Can have but one explanation
You and I were just meant to be
Notre est si Évident
[Our is so Obvious]
Say goodbye
Dites adieu
[say goodbye]
To the pain of the past
Aux douleurs du passé
[The pains of the past]
We don't have to feel it anymore
Ce qui nous attend est bien plus beau
[What awaits us is more beautiful]
Love is an open door
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
Love is an open door!
L'amour est un cadeau
[Love is a gift]
Life can be so much more
Le monde sera plus beau
[The world will be more beautiful]
With you
Pour nous
[For us]
Love is an open
L'amour est un ca-
[Love is a ca-]
Door
-deau
[-deau]
Can I say something crazy?
J'ai une idée des plus insensées.
[I have an idea of the senseless.]
Will you marry me?
Voulez-vous m'épouser?
[Do you want to marry me?]
Can I say something even crazier?
J'ai une réponse encore plus insensée.
[I have one more senseless answer.]
Yes!
Oui!
[Yes!]
Coming through. Excuse me. Oh...
Attention. Excusez-moi. Oh...
[Warning. Excuse me. Oh...]
Pardon. Sorry. Oh!
Can we just get around you there?
Pourriez-vous nous laisser passer s'il vous plaît?
[Could you let us pass please?]
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Merci. Oh! Elle est là.
[Thank you. Oh! She's there.]
Elsa!
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
Je veux dire, Majesté. C'est encore moi.
[I mean, Majesty. It's me again.]
May I present Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Puis-je vous présenter le prince Hans des Îles du Sud.
[Can I introduce Prince Hans Southern Islands.]
Your Majesty.
Votre Majesté.
[Your Majesty.]
We would like...
Nous aimerions avoir...
[We would like...]
Uh, your blessing...
Euh, votre bénédiction...
[Uh, your blessing...]
Of our marriage.
pour notre mariage.
[for our wedding.]
Marriage? - Yes!
- Votre mariage?
- Oui!
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Excusez-moi, êtes-vous sérieux?
[Excuse me, are you serious?]
Well, we haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
Nous n'avons pas encore planifié tous les détails.
[We have not planned every detail.]
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
Il nous faudra quelques jours pour prévoir la cérémonie.
[It will take us a few days to plan the ceremony.]
Of course, we'll have soup, roast, and ice cream. And then...
Bien sûr, il y aura de la soupe, du rôti, de la crème glacée...
[Of course, there will be soup, roast, ice cream...]
Wait. Would we live here?
Attendez. Habiterons-nous ici?
[Wait. We will live here?]
Here? - Absolutely!
Ici? - Oui! Avec grand plaisir!
[Here? - Yes! With great pleasure!]
Anna!
Oh! We can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us.
Et nous pourrons dire à vos douze frères de vivre ici avec nous.
[And we can say to your twelve brothers to live here with us.]
What? No, no, no.
Of course we have the room......
Nous avons assez de chambres.
[We have enough rooms.]
Wait, slow down. No one's brothers are staying here.
Anna, je t'en prie. Calme-toi. Aucun de ses frères ne vivra ici
[Anna, I beg you. Calm down. None of his brothers live here]
No one is getting married.
et personne ne se mariera.
[and no one will marry.]
Wait, what?
Attends, quoi?
[Wait what?]
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
Puis-je te parler une minute? Seule à seule?
[Can I talk to you a minute? Alone alone?]
No. Whatever you have to say, you can say to both of us.
Non. Peu importe ce que tu as à dire, tu peux nous le dire à tous les deux.
[No. No matter what you have to say, you can tell us both.]
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
Parfait. On n'épouse pas un homme qu'on ne connaît pas.
[Perfect. You do not marry a man who does not know.]
You can if it's true love.
À moins que ce soit le grand amour.
[Unless this is true love.]
Anna, what do you know about true love?
Anna, que connais-tu du grand amour?
[Anna, what do you know of the great love?]
More than you.
Un peu plus que toi.
[A little more than you.]
All you know is how to shut people out.
Tout ce que tu sais faire c'est rejeter les gens.
[All you can do is to reject people.]
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
Tu as demandé ma bénédiction, et ma réponse est non.
[You asked for my blessing, and my answer is no.]
Now, excuse me.
Maintenant, je vous prie de m'excuser.
[Now, please excuse me.]
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
Votre Majesté, si je puis me permettre...
[Your Majesty, if I may...]
No, you may not. And I think you should go.
Non, je ne vous permets pas et je vous demanderai de partir.
[No, I do not allow you and ask you to leave.]
The party is over. Close the gates.
La réception est terminée, fermez les portes.
[The reception is complete, close the doors.]
Yes, Your Majesty.
Tout de suite Majesté.
[Immediately Majesty.]
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
Elsa, non, non! Attends.
[Elsa, no, no! Wait.]
Give me my glove!
Rends-moi mon gant!
[Give me back my glove!]
Elsa, please, please.
Elsa, je te supplie de m'écouter.
[Elsa, I beseech thee to hear me.]
I can't live like this anymore!
Je ne peux plus vivre de cette façon.
[I can not live that way.]
Then leave.
Alors, va-t'en.
[So go away.]
What did I ever do to you?
Qu'est-ce que je t'ai fait? Dis-le-moi.
[What did I do to you? Tell me.]
Enough, Anna.
Ça suffit, Anna.
[Enough Anna.]
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
Non, pourquoi? Pourquoi me rejettes-tu?
[No why? Why do you reject me?]
Why do you shut the world out?
Pourquoi rejettes-tu le monde entier?
[Why do you reject the world?]
What are you so afraid of?
Mais de quoi as-tu si peur?
[But what are you so afraid?]
I said, enough!
J'ai dit ça suffit!
[I said that's enough!]
Sorcery.
C'est de la sorcellerie.
[This is witchcraft.]
I knew there was something dubious going on here.
Je savais que quelque chose de douteux se passait au château.
[I knew that something suspicious was going on at the castle.]
Elsa.
There she is!
La voilà!
[There she is!]
Yes! It is her!
Queen Elsa.
Majesté.
[Majesty.]
Our beautiful queen!
Notre merveilleuse reine!
[Our wonderful Queen!]
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
Votre Majesté? Est-ce que tout va bien?
[Your Majesty? Is everything alright?]
No.
Non.
[No.]
There she is! Stop her!
Et la voilà. Arrêtez-la!
[There she goes. Stop her!]
Please, just stay away from me. Stay away.
Je vous en prie, ne vous approchez pas de moi. Ne vous approchez pas.
[Please, do not approach me. Do not approach.]
Monster. Monster!
C'est un monstre. C'est un monstre!
[He is a monster. It's a monster!]
Elsa!
Wait, please!
Attends, je t'en prie!
[Wait, I beg you!]
Elsa, stop!
Elsa, reviens!
[Elsa, come back!]
Anna!
No.
Non.
[No.]
The fjord.
Le fjord.
[The fjord.]
Snow! Snow?
De la neige! De la neige?
[Snow! Snow?]
Yes, snow.
Oui, c'est de la neige.
[Yes, that's snow.]
Are you all right? - No.
Est-ce que ça va? - Non.
[Are you OK? - No.]
Did you know?
Étiez-vous au courant?
[Were you aware?]
No.
Non.
[No.]
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
Regardez, il neige. Il neige!
[Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!]
The queen has cursed this land!
La reine a jeté un mauvais sort!
[The queen laid a curse!]
She must be stopped! You have to go after her.
Il faut l'arrêter à tout prix! Allez la rattraper.
[It must be stopped at all costs! Go catch up.]
Wait, no!
Attendez, non!
[Wait, no!]
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
Vous! Y a-t-il aussi de la sorcellerie en vous?
[You! Does he also sorcery in you?]
Are you a monster, too?
Êtes-vous un monstre, vous aussi?
[Are you a monster, too?]
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
Non, non. Je suis une fille tout à fait ordinaire.
[No no. I am a girl quite ordinary.]
That's right, she is.
Elle a raison, c'est exacte.
[She's right, that's correct.]
In the best way.
Efin, dans le bon sens du terme.
[Efin, in the good sense.]
And my sister is not a monster.
Et ma sœur n'est pas un monstre.
[And my sister is not a monster.]
She nearly killed me!
Elle a presque failli me tuer!
[She almost nearly killed me!]
You slipped on ice. - Her ice.
Vous avez glissé sur la glace. - Qu'elle a créée.
[You slipped on the ice. - That it has created.]
It was an accident. She was scared.
C'était un accident. Elle avait peur, voilà tout.
[It was an accident. She was scared, that's all.]
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this.
Elle ne l'a pas fait exprès. Elle ne voulait pas provoquer de catastrophe.
[She did not mean to. She did not provoke disaster.]
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
Tout cela est de ma faute. Je l'ai provoquée.
[This is all my fault. I caused.]
So, I'm the one
Alors, c'est à moi
[So it is for me]
that needs to go after her.
de la retrouver.
[to find her.]
Bring me my horse, please.
Qu'on m'apporte mon cheval, tout de suite.
[Bring me my horse right away.]
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
Anna, non. C'est beaucoup trop dangereux.
[Anna, no. It's much too dangerous.]
Elsa's not dangerous.
Elsa n'est pas dangereuse.
[Elsa is not dangerous.]
I'll bring her back, and I'll make this right.
Je vais la ramener ici, et tout va s'arranger.
[I'll bring her back, and everything will work out.]
I'm coming with you.
Je viens avec vous.
[I am coming with you.]
No, I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
Non, vous devez rester ici et veiller sur Arendelle.
[No, you must stay here and watch over Arendelle.]
On my honor.
Je serais honoré.
[I would be honored.]
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Le prince Hans sera résponsable du royaume.
[Prince Hans will be responsable of the realm.]
Are you sure you can trust her?
Êtes-vous sûr de lui faire confiance?
[Are you sure you trust him?]
I don't want you getting hurt.
Je ne veux pas qu'il vous arrive malheur.
[I do not want you sometimes misfortune.]
She's my sister.
C'est ma sœur.
[It's my sister.]
She would never hurt me.
Elle ne me ferait jamais mal.
[She never would hurt me.]
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
L'hiver s'installe doucement dans la nuit
Winter is settling in gently in the night
not a footprint to be seen
La neige est reine à son tour
Snow is queen itself
A kingdom of isolation,
Un royaume de solitude
A kingdom of loneliness
and it looks like I'm the queen
Ma place est là, pour toujours.
My place is there, forever.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Le vent qui hurle en moi "ne pense plus à demain"
The wind is screaming inside me, "don't think about tomorrow any more"
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Il est bien trop fort, j'ai lutté en vain.
It's really too strong, I've struggled in vain.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Cache tes pouvoirs, n'en parle pas
Hide your powers, don't talk about them
Be the good girl you always had to be
Fais attention, le secret survivra
Be careful, the secret will survive
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Pas d'états d'âme, pas de tourments
No emotions, no torments
Well, now they know!
De sentiments!
(or) feelings!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
Can't hold it back any more!
Je ne mentirai plus jamais
I won't lie ever again
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
Turn away and slam the door!
C'est décidée, je m'en vais!
It's decided, I'm going away!
I don't care what they're going to say
J'ai laissé mon enfance en été
I left my childhood in summer
Let the storm rage on
Perdue dans l'hiver
Lost in the winter
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Le froid est pour moi le prix de la liberté.
Cold for me is the price of freedom.
It's funny how some distance
Quand on prend de la hauteur
When we raise,
Makes everything seem small
Tout semble insignifiant
Everything looks insignificant
And the fears that once controlled me
La tristesse, l'angoisse et la peur
Sadness, anxiety and fear
Can't get to me at all!
M'ont quittée depuis longtemps!
Left me long ago!
It's time to see what I can do
Je veux voir ce que je peux faire
I want to see what I can do
To test the limits and break through
De cette magie pleine de mystère
With this magic full of mystery
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Le bien, le mal, je dis tant pis
Good, evil, I say let it be
I'm free!
Tant pis!
Let it be!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
I am one with the wind and sky
Les étoiles me tendent les bras
Stars are reaching out to me
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
You'll never see me cry
Non, je ne pleure pas
No, I don't cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Me voilà, oui, je suis là
Here I am, yes I'm here
Let the storm rage on...
Perdue dans l'hiver...
Lost in the winter...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Mon pouvoir vient de ciel et envahit l'espace
My power comes from the sky and invades the space
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Mon âme s'exprime en dessinant et sculptant dans la glace
My soul expresses itself drawing and carving ice
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Et mes pensées sont des fleurs de cristal gelées
And my thoughts are frozen crystal flowers
I'm never going back
Je ne reviendrai pas
I won't come back
The past is in the past!
Le passé est passé!
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Désormais plus rien ne m'arrête
Nothing can stop me any more
Let it go, let it go!
Libérée, délivrée!
Freed, released!
That perfect girl is gone
Plus de princesse parfaite
No more the perfect princess
Here I stand in the light of day
Je suis là, comme je l'ai rêvé
I am here, as I dreamt of
Let the storm rage on!
Perdue dans l'hiver
Lost in the winter
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Le froid est pour moi le prix de la liberté.
Cold for me is the price of freedom.
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
Elsa, c'est moi, Anna
[Elsa, it's me, Anna]
your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
ta sœur qui ne voulait pas que tu plonges le royaume dans l'hiver.
[your sister who did not want you plunge the kingdom in the winter.]
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
Je suis désolée. Tout est de ma faute.
[I am sorry. Everything is my fault.]
Of course, none of it would have happened
Bien sûr, rien de tout ça ne sera arrivé
[Of course, none of this will come]
if she had just told me her secret.
si elle m'a révélé son secret.
[if she revealed her secret.]
She's a stinker.
Quelle cachottière.
[What secretive.]
Whoa!
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
Oh, non. Non, non, non! Reviens!
[Oh no. No no no! Come back!]
No, no, no!
Non, non, non, non!
[No no no no!]
Okay.
Oh, très bien.
[Oh very good.]
Snow. It had to be snow.
La neige. Il fallait que ce soit de la neige.
[The snow. It had to be snow.]
She couldn't have had tropical magic
Elle n'aurait pas pu avoir des pouvoirs tropicaux
[She could not have tropical authorities]
that covered the fjords in white sand and warm...
qui auraient recouvert les fjords de sable fin et de...
[which would have covered fjords and sandy...]
Fire!
Du feu!
[Fire!]
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
J'ai froid, j'ai froid, j'ai froid.
[I am cold, I am cold, I am cold.]
"Wandering Oaken's Trading Post".
"Chez Oaken", "Bazar".
["At Oaken"," Bazaar".]
Ooh. "And sauna"!
Oh! "Et sauna".
[Oh! " And sauna".]
Hoo-hoo.
You-hou.
[You- hoo.]
Big summer blowout.
Grande liquidation d'été.
[Great summer liquidation.]
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
Cinquant pourcent sur les maillots de bain, sabots
[Least fifteen percent on swimwear, shoes]
and a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
et sur la crème solaire que je fais moi-même, ja?
[and sun cream as I do myself, ja?]
Oh. Great. For now, um, how about boots?
Oh. Génial. Mais j'aurais plutôt besoin de.. d'une paire de bottes.
[Oh. Awesome. But I would rather need.. a pair of boots.]
Winter boots? And dresses?
Des bottes d'hiver et de vêtements chauds.
[Winter boots and warm clothing.]
That would be in our winter department.
Ça sera dans notre section hiver.
[It will be in our winter section.]
Oh. Um...
Oh. Eum...
[Oh. Eum...]
I was just wondering.
Je me demandais également
[I wondered also]
Has another young woman...
si, par hasard, une autre jeune femme...
[if, by chance, another young woman...]
The queen perhaps, I don't know,
la reine peut-être n'étais pas aussi
[Queen maybe was not as]
passed through here?
passée dans votre magasin.
[spent in your store.]
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm is you, dear.
Vous êtes la seule personne assez inconsciente pour braver la tempête.
[You're the only person brave enough unconscious storm.]
You and this fellow.
Vous et cet homme.
[You and this man.]
Hoo-hoo.
You-hou.
[You- hoo.]
Big summer blowout.
Grande liquidation d'été.
[Great summer liquidation.]
Carrots.
Des carottes.
[Carrots.]
Huh?
Behind you.
Derrière vous.
[Behind you.]
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Oh! Désolée. Excusez-moi.
[Oh! Sorry. Excuse me.]
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
Oh, c'est dur une tempête en juilliet, ja?
[Oh, it is hard a storm in july, ja?]
Wherever could it be coming from?
D'où peut-il bien venir?
[Where can it come from?]
The North Mountain.
De la montagne du nord.
[From the northern mountains.]
North Mountain.
De la montagne du nord.
[From the northern mountains.]
That will be forty.
Ça vous fera quarante.
[It will make you forty.]
Forty? No, ten.
Quarante? Non, dix.
[Forty? No, ten.]
Oh, dear, that's no good.
Oh non, ce n'est pas possible.
[Oh no, that's not possible.]
See, this is from our winter stock,
Ces articles viennent de mon stock de hiver
[These items come from my winter stock]
where supply and demand have a big problem.
et la demande va très bientôt dépasser l'offre.
[and demand will soon outstrip supply.]
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
Ouais, mais moi vous voyez, j'ai le problème inverse.
[Yeah, but I see you, I have the opposite problem.]
I sell ice for a living.
Je vends des glaçons.
[I sell ice cubes.]
Ooh. That's a rough business to be in right now.
La commerce ne doit pas être très fleurissante dans les temps qui courent
[The trade should not be very flourishing in these days]
I mean, that is really...
parce que, il faut avouer que...
[because, I must admit that...]
That's unfortunate.
C'est pas de chance.
[This is not luck.]
Still forty.
Ça fera donc quarante.
[So it will be forty.]
But I will throw in a visit to Oaken's sauna.
Mai vous aurez accès au sauna de Oaken.
[You may have access to the sauna Oaken.]
Hoo-hoo. Hi, family.
You-hou, la famille.
[You- hoo, family.]
Hoo-hoo!
You-hou!
[You- hoo!]
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
Je n'ai que dix sur moi. Soyez sympa.
[I have only ten on me. Be nice.]
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
D'accord. Alors vous aurez ça et pas plus.
[Okay. Then you will have that and no more.]
Okay, just tell me one thing.
J'ai une question à vous poser.
[I have a question for you.]
What was happening on the North Mountain?
Que s'est il passé sur la montagne du nord?
[What has happened on the northern mountain?]
Did it seem magical?
Est-ce que ça ressemblait.. à la magie?
[Do it looked like magic..?]
Yes!
Oui!
[Yes!]
Now, back up while I deal with this crook, here.
Maintenant reculez-vous. Je dois négocier avec cet escrot.
[Now stand back. I have to negotiate with that escrot.]
What did you call me?
Comment m'avez-vous appelé?
[How did you call me?]
Okay, okay. I'm out.
Hé ça va! On est calme!
[Hey it's going! It is quiet!]
Whoa!
Bye-bye.
Au revoir!
[Goodbye!]
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
Non, Sven, je n'ai pas tes carottes.
[No, Sven, I'm not your carrots.]
But I did find us a place to sleep.
Mais j'ai trouvé un endroit où dormir.
[But I found a place to sleep.]
And it's free.
Et c'est gratuit.
[And it's free.]
I'm sorry about this violence.
Je suis désolé pour toute cette violence.
[I'm sorry for all this violence.]
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
Je vais vous offrir un quart de lutefisk,
[I'll give you a quarter of lutefisk,]
so we have good feelings.
pour me faire pardonner.
[to be forgiven.]
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
Alors, le manteau et les bottes, ja?
[Then, coat and boots, ja?]
Uh...
Euh...
[Uh...]
Reindeers are better than people
Les rennes sont meilleurs que les hommes
[The reindeer are better than men]
Sven, don't you think that's true?
Sven, ami, qu'en penses-tu?
[Sven, friend, what do you think?]
"Yeah, people will beat you and curse you and cheat you"
"Oui, les hommes sont méchants, médisants et têtus
[" Yes, men are wicked and slanderous stubborn]
"Every one of them's bad, except you!"
"Sauf toi, je l'ai su dès que je t'ai vu"
[" Except you, I knew when I saw you"]
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
Ah, merci mon vieux.
[Ah, thank you buddy.]
But people smell better than reindeers
Les hommes sentent moins mauvais que les rennes
[Men feel less bad than reindeer]
Sven, don't you think I'm right?
Sven, penses-tu comme moi?
[Sven, do you like me?]
"That's once again true, for all except you!"
"C'est bien vrai, ma foi! Pour tous, sauf pour toi"
[" It's true, my word to everyone except for you"]
You got me! Let's call it a night.
Tu m'as eu! Mais il se fait tard
[You got me! But it is late]
"Good night"
"Très tard"
["Very late"]
Don't let the frostbite
Rendors-toi sans peine
[Go back to sleep without trouble]
Bite
Sven
[Sven]
Nice duet.
Joli duo.
[Joli duo.]
It's just you. What do you want?
C'est vous. Que voulez-vous?
[It's you. What do you want?]
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
Je veux que vous m'emmèniez dans la montagne du nord.
[I want you to take me in the northern mountains.]
I don't take people places.
Je ne transporte pas les gens, désolé.
[I do not carry people, sorry.]
Let me rephrase that.
Je vais reposer ma question.
[I'll ask my question.]
Hey.
Take me up the North Mountain.
Emmenez-moi dans la montagne du nord.
[Take me in the northern mountains.]
Please.
S'il vous plaît.
[If you please.]
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
Je sais comment mettre fin à l'hiver.
[I know how to end the winter.]
We leave at dawn.
On partira à l'aube.
[We leave at dawn.]
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
Et vous avez oublié les carottes pour Sven.
[And you forgot the carrots for Sven.]
Oops, sorry.
Oh, désolée!
[Oh, sorry!]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
Désolée. Je ne voulais pas vous...
[Sorry. I did not want you...]
We leave now. Right now.
Nous partons. Maintenant. Sur le champ.
[We leave. Now. On the field.]
Whew!
Hang on! We like to go fast.
Accrochez-vous! On aime aller vite.
[Hold on! We like to go fast.]
I like fast. - Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
J'adore la vitesse. - Waoh! Waoh, waoh, waoh...
[I love speed. - Wow! Wow, wow, wow...]
Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
Retirez vos pieds. Je viens de vernir.
[Remove your feet. I just varnish.]
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
Je sais pas où vous avez été élevée.
[I do not know where you were high.]
Ugh!
No, I was raised in a castle.
J'ai été élevée dans un château.
[I was raised in a castle.]
So, uh, tell me,
Alors, dites-moi
[So tell me]
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
pourquoi la reine nous a plongés dans l'hiver?
[why the Queen has plunged us into the winter?]
Oh. Well...
Oh. Et bien...
[Oh. And well...]
It was all my fault.
Tout est de ma faute, je...
[This is all my fault, I...]
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
je me suis fiancée, et cela l'a mise en colère
[I got engaged, and this has angered]
because I'd only just met him you know, that day.
car d'après elle on n'epouse pas un homme, que l'on vient de rencontrer.
[because according to her wife is not a man, that we just met.]
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage, and...
Et elle s'est opposée à notre mariage et...
[She objected to our marriage and...]
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
Quoi? Vous vous êtes fiancée à un homme que vous veniez de rencontrer?
[What? You're engaged to a man that you came to meet?]
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
Oui. Et alors j'étais furieuse, alors elle s'est mise en colère
[Yes I do. And then I was furious, so she is angry]
and then she tried to walk away, and I grabbed her glove...
et elle a voulu quitter la pièce, alors j'ai attrapé son gant et ensuite...
[and she wanted to leave the room, so I grabbed his glove and then...]
Hang on!
Une seconde!
[A second!]
You mean to tell me you got engaged
C'est quand même incroyable que vous êtes en train de me dire
[It is unbelievable that you're telling me]
to someone you just met that day?
que vous étiez prête à épouser un homme que vous veniez de rencontrer!
[you were ready to marry a man you had just met!]
Yes. Pay attention.
Oui. Je viens de vous le dire.
[Yes I do. I just tell you.]
But the thing is, she wore the gloves all the time,
Mais le truc, c'est que ma sœur porte des gants tout le temps
[But the thing is that my sister wears gloves all the time]
so I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
et moi j'ai toujours cru qu'elle ne supportait pas la poussière.
[and I've always believed she could not stand the dust.]
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
Vos parents ne vous ont pas appris à vous méfier des inconnus?
[Your parents do not learn to be wary of strangers?]
Yyyyyes, they did.
Si, bien sûr que si.
[Yes, of course I do.]
But Hans is not a stranger.
Mais Hans n'est pas un inconnu.
[But Hans is not a stranger.]
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
Ah ouais? Quel est son nom de famille?
[Oh yeah? What's his last name?]
"Of the Southern Isles."
"Des Îles du Sud".
[" The Southern Islands".]
What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
Son plat préféré? - Les sandwiches.
[His favorite dish? - The sandwiches.]
Best friend's name? - Probably John.
Son meilleur ami? - Probablement John.
[His best friend? - Probably John.]
Eye color? - Dreamy.
La couleur de ses yeux? - Magnifique.
[The color of his eyes? - Gorgeous.]
Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
Sa pointure? - Sa pointure n'a aucune importance.
[His size? - Its size does not matter.]
Have you had a meal with him yet? What if you hate the way he eats?
Vous avez déjà mangé avec lui? Et s'il mangait comme un cochon?
[You have already eaten with him? And if mangait like a pig?]
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
Peut-être même qu'il mange ses crottes de nez?
[Perhaps he eats his boogers?]
Picks his nose?
Qu'il mange quoi!?
[He eats what!?]
And eats it.
Ses crottes de nez.
[His boogers.]
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
Excusez-moi, monsieur. C'est un prince.
[Excuse me sir. He is a prince.]
All men do it.
Tous les hommes le font.
[All men do.]
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
Quelle horreur. Tout ça n'a aucune importance car c'est le grand amour.
[How awful. All that does not matter because it is the great love.]
It doesn't sound like true love.
J'en ai pas l'impression.
[I not feel.]
Are you some sort of love expert?
Vous êtes un expert en amour, c'est ça?
[You are an expert in love, right?]
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
Non. Mais j'ai des amis qui le sont.
[No. But I have friends who are.]
You have friends
Vous avez des amis
[You have friends]
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
qui sont des experts en amour? J'en crois pas un mot.
[who are experts in love? I not believe a word.]
Stop talking. - No, no, no. No, no.
Taisez-vous. - Non, non, non, non, non.
[Be quiet. - No, no, no, no, no.]
I'd like to meet these... - No, I mean it.
J'aimerais bien les rencontrer... - Je suis sérieux.
[I'd like to meet... - I'm serious.]
Sven, go.
Sven, avance.
[Sven advance.]
Go!
Vite!
[Quick!]
What are they? - Wolves.
Qu'est-ce que c'est? - Des loups.
[What is it? - Wolves.]
Wolves?
Des loups?
[Wolves?]
What do we do? - I got this.
Qu'est-ce qu'il faut faire? - Je m'en occupe.
[What do we have to do? - I'm taking care of it.]
You just... Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
Vous, vous essayez... de pas tomber, et de pas vous faire dévorer.
[You, you... try not to fall off, and you do not eat.]
But I want to help!
Mais je veux vous aider!
[But I want to help!]
No. - Why not?
Non. - Pourquoi?
[No. - What for?]
Because I don't trust your judgment.
Parce que je n'ai pas confiance en votre jugement.
[Because I do not trust your judgment.]
Excuse me?
Je vous demande pardon?
[I beg your pardon?]
Who marries a man she just met?
Qui voudrait épouser un inconnu?
[Who would want to marry a stranger?]
It's true love!
C'est le grand amour!
[This is true love!]
Whoa!
Whoa. Whoa!
Christopher!
It's "Kristoff"!
C'est "Kristoff"!
[It is" Kristoff!"]
Ow!
Duck!
Baissez-vous!
[Get down!]
You almost set me on fire!
J'ai failli prendre feu!
[I almost catch fire!]
But I didn't.
Mais c'est pas arrivé.
[But that has not happened.]
Get ready to jump, Sven!
Prépare-toi à sauter, Sven.
[Get ready to jump, Sven.]
You don't tell him what to do.
Je vous interdis de lui dire quoi faire.
[I forbid you to tell him what to do.]
I do!
C'est mon boulot!
[It's my job!]
Jump, Sven!
Saute, Sven!
[Jump, Sven!]
Phew!
But I just paid it off.
Je venais de le rembourser.
[I had to pay it back.]
Uh-oh. No. No.
Oh. Non. Non.
[Oh. No. No.]
No!
Non, non!
[No no!]
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Ah! Non, non, non, non, non, non, non!
[Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!]
Grab on!
Attrapez ça.
[Grab that.]
Pull, Sven. Pull!
Tire, Sven. Tire!
[Tire, Sven. Tire!]
Whoa.
Oh, mince.
[Oh, man.]
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
Je vous rachèterai un traineau avec tout ce qu'il y avait dedans.
[I will redeem you with a sledge everything was in it.]
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
Et.. je comprendrais si vous ne vouliez plus m'aider.
[And.. I would understand if you no longer wanted to help me.]
Of course I don't want to help her anymore. In fact,
Bien sûr que je ne veux plus l'aider. En fait...
[Of course I do not want help. In fact...]
this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
toute cette histoire va me dissuader d'aider qui que ce soit à l'avenir.
[this story will dissuade me from helping anyone in the future.]
It's this way?
Est-ce que c'est par là?
[Does it mean?]
"She'll die on her own."
"Mais seule elle risque de mourir."
[" But alone it may die."]
I can live with that. - Here we go.
Ça me dérange pas. - Oui, c'est ça.
[It doest not matter to me. - Yes that's it.]
"But you won't get your new sled if she's dead."
"Mais tu n'auras pas ton traineau tout neuf si elle meurt."
[" But you do not have your brand new sled if she dies."]
I think, actually, it's up.
Je pense que c'est un peu plus loin.
[I think it is a little further.]
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
Par moments, je te déteste.
[Sometimes I hate you.]
Hold up! We're coming.
Une seconde! On arrive.
[A second! We arrive.]
You are?
C'est vrai?
[It's true?]
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
Je veux dire, c'est d'accord. Je vous laisse m'accompagner.
[I mean, that's okay. I leave you with me.]
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
Tout le pays est sous la neige.
[The whole country is under snow.]
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
Mais ça va s'arranger. Elsa va la faire fondre.
[But it will work out. Elsa will melt.]
Will she?
Vous croyez?
[You think?]
Yeah. Now, come on.
Oui. Allez, on y va.
[Yes I do. Lets' go.]
This way to the North Mountain?
C'est par là, la montagne du nord?
[That is where the northern mountain?]
More like this way.
Non, c'est plutôt dans cette direction.
[No, it's more in that direction.]
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
Je n'aurais jamais cru que l'hiver pouvait être si magnifique.
[I never thought that winter could be so beautiful.]
Yeah.
Ouais.
[Yeah.]
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
Non, c'est vrai. C'est magnifique.
[No it is true. That's wonderful.]
But it's so white.
Mais tout est si blanc.
[But everything is so white.]
You know, how about a little color?
Oh, faudrait y mettre un peu de couleur.
[Oh, would put a little color.]
I'm thinking maybe some crimson, chartreuse.
Je sais pas moi, du rouge vermillon, ou du vert sapin.
[I know myself, the vermilion red, green or fir.]
How about yellow?
Ou encore du jaune?
[Or yellow?]
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
Ah. Non, non, non, non, non. Pas jaune. Du jaune sur la neige?
[Ah. No, no, no, no, no. No yellow. Yellow on snow?]
No go.
Brrr! Non, ça va pas du tout.
[Brrr! No, it's not.]
Am I right?
J'ai pas raison?
[I not right?]
You're creepy.
C'est trop pour moi.
[It is too much for me.]
I don't want it.
Gardez.
[Keep.]
Back at you. - Please don't drop me.
J'en peux pas. - Pitié, arrêtez.
[I can not. - Please, stop.]
Come on, it's just a head.
Ça va, ce n'est qu'une tête.
[Okay, it's just a head.]
All right. We got off to a bad start.
Non! Ça commence plutôt mal.
[No! It starts rather badly.]
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
Son corps se dirige vers moi!
[Her body is heading towards me!]
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Attendez, je peux savoir pourquoi vous êtes
[Wait, I know why you are]
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
suspendus, la tête en bas, comme des chauves-souris?
[suspended upside down like bats?]
All right, wait one second.
Une seconde, c'est normal.
[A second, this is normal.]
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Merci! - Y a pas de quoi.
[Thank you! - No problem.]
Now, I'm perfect.
Là je suis parfait.
[There I am perfect.]
Well, almost.
Oui, enfin presque.
[Yes, almost.]
It was like my whole life got turned upside down.
Mais j'avais l'impression de voir le monde à l'envers.
[But I had the impression of seeing the world upside down.]
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
Désolée! Je suis désolée.
[Sorry! I am sorry.]
Head rush! - I was just... Are you okay?
Je voulais simplement... Est-ce que ça va?
[I just wanted to... Is it going?]
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
Vous plaisantez ou quoi? J'adore! Je me trouve merveilleux!
[Are you kidding or what? J'adore! I am wonderful!]
I've always wanted a nose.
Ah, j'ai toujours rêvé d'avoir un nez.
[Ah, I always dreamed of having a nose.]
So cute.
C'est trop mignon!
[This is too cute!]
It's like a little baby unicorn.
On dirait un bébé licorne.
[Looks like a baby unicorn.]
But... Hey! Whoa!
Oh.
I love it even more.
Je l'aime encore plus comme ça!
[I even like that!]
All right, let's start this thing over.
Très bien. Reprenons du début...
[Very good. Let's start...]
Hi, everyone.
Salut tout le monde.
[Hello everybody.]
I'm Olaf.
Je m'appelle Olaf
[My name is Olaf]
And I like warm hugs.
et j'adore les câlins!
[and I love hugs!]
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
Oui, bien sûr. Olaf.
[Yes of course. Olaf.]
And you are?
Et vous êtes?
[And you are?]
Oh. Um...
Oh. Euh...
[Oh. Uh...]
I'm Anna.
Je m'appelle Anna.
[I am called Anna.]
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
Comment s'appelle le drôle d'animal qui ressemble à un âne?
[Who is the strange animal that looks like a donkey?]
That's Sven.
C'est Sven.
[Sven is.]
And who's the reindeer?
Et c'est qui le renne?
[And it is that the reindeer?]
Sven.
Oh, they're... Oh. Okay. That makes things easier for me.
Oh, aussi? Oh, d'accord. Ça va être facile à retenir.
[Oh, too? Oh alright. It'll be easy to remember.]
Aw, look at him trying to kiss my nose.
Il a essayé d'embrasser mon nez.
[He tried to kiss my nose.]
I like you, too.
Moi aussi, je t'adore.
[Me too I love you.]
Olaf. Did Elsa build you? - Yeah. Why?
Olaf. C'est Elsa qui t'a créé? - Oui. Pourquoi?
[Olaf. This is Elsa who created you? - Yes. What for?]
Do you know where she is? - Yeah. Why?
Sais-tu où elle est? - Oui. Pourquoi?
[Do you know where she is? - Yes. What for?]
Fascinating.
Fascinant.
[Fascinating.]
Do you think you could show us the way? - Yeah. Why?
Tu pourrais nous y conduire? - Oui. Pourquoi?
[You could take us there? - Yes. What for?]
How does this work? Ow!
Comment ça marche?
[How it works?]
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus, here.
Arrête, Sven. J'essaie de me concentrer.
[Stop, Sven. I try to focus.]
Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.
Oui. Pourquoi? - Je vais te dire pourquoi.
[Yes I do. What for? - I'll tell you why.]
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
Il faut qu'elle fasse revenir l'été.
[It must bring again the summer.]
Summer?
L'été?
[Summer?]
Oh. I don't know why,
Oh. Je sais pas pourquoi
[Oh. I do not know why]
but I've always loved the idea of summer
mais j'ai toujours adoré l'été. C'est ma saison préférée.
[but I've always loved the summer. This is my favorite season.]
and sun, and all things hot.
Le soleil, la chaleur intense...
[The sun, the intense heat...]
Really?
Vraiment?
[Really?]
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
T'es sûr que tu t'y connais en chaleur.
[You sure you know you there into heat.]
Nope.
Non.
[No.]
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
Mais quelquefois il m'arrive de fermer les yeux
[But sometimes I sometimes close my eyes]
and imagine what it would be like when summer does come.
et d'imaginer la vie d'un bonhomme de neige en été.
[and imagine the life of a snowman in summer.]
Bees will buzz, kids will blow dandelion fuzz
Les abeilles Les pissenlits et le soleil
[The bees Dandelions and sun]
And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer
L'heure pour moi de faire Ce que la neige fait en été
[Time for me to do this than snow actually was]
A drink in my hand
Un verre, dans la main
[A drink in hand]
My snow up against the burning sand
Je m'allonge sur le sable fin
[I lie on the sand]
Probably getting gorgeously tanned
Je commence à bronzer en douceur
[I begin to tan smooth]
In summer.
En été
[In summer]
I'll finally see a summer breeze
Je sens une brise très légère
[I feel a light breeze]
Blow away a winter storm
Chasser le froid de l'hiver
[Chase the winter cold]
And find out what happens to solid water
Je plonge et je nage et je goûte au plaisir
[I dive and swim and I taste the pleasure]
When it gets warm
De ne rien faire
[Do nothing]
And I can't wait to see
Et j'ai hâte de revoir
[And I look forward to seeing]
What my buddies all think of me
Mes amis en ce jour de gloire
[My friends in this day of glory]
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be
Imaginez comme la vie sera belle
[Imagine how life will be beautiful]
In summer!
En été!
[In summer!]
The hot and the cold are both so intense
Le chaud et le froid sont faits pour s'entendre
[Hot and cold are made ​​for each other]
Put them together It just makes sense
Ils ont une âme pure et un cœur tendre
[They have a pure soul and a tender heart]
Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle
Y a ceux qui aiment Les feux de cheminée
[Are those who like Chimney fires]
But put me in summer and I'll be a...
Mais mettez-moi au soleil et je serais...
[But put me in the sun and I would be...]
(puddle?)
Happy snowman!
Un homme comblé!
[A happy man!]
When life gets rough
Quand le temps s'assombrit
[When the weather darkens]
I like to hold on to my dream
Je m'accroche à mes rêves
[I cling to my dreams]
Of relaxing in the summer sun, just letting off steam
Et là sous un soleil brûlant Je me détends
[And there in the hot sun I relax]
Oh, the sky will be blue
Quand le ciel Sera bleu
[When the sky blue Sera]
And you guys will be there, too
Vous serez là, tous les deux
[You will be there, both]
When I finally do
Pour vivre la grande
[To live the high]
What frozen things do in summer!
Aventure de la neige en été!
[Adventure snow in summer!]
I'm gonna tell him.
Je vais le lui dire.
[I'll tell him.]
Don't you dare.
Je vous l'interdis.
[I forbid you.]
In summer!
En été!
[In summer!]
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Allez, on y va. Elsa habite par là.
[Lets' go. Elsa lives there.]
Let's go bring back summer!
J'ai tellement hâte de voir... l'été!
[I can not wait to see... summer!]
I'm coming!
Je te suis!
[I following you!]
Somebody's gotta tell him.
Il faut que quelqu'un lui dise.
[Somebody told.]
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
Non, non. Tu as mis l'écorce à l'envers.
[No no. You put the bark in reverse.]
The bark needs to be face-up.
Il faut la tourner vers le haut.
[It should turn up.]
Bark down is drier. - Bark up!
Mais non, elle ne sèchera jamais!
[No, it never dries!]
Bark down! - Papa!
Papa!
[Dad!]
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Des capes. Qui a besoin d'une cape?
[Capes. Who needs a cape?]
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
Le sort d'Arendelle est entre vos mains Votre Altesse.
[The fate of Arendelle is in your hands Your Highness.]
The castle is open.
Le château est ouvert.
[The castle is open.]
There is soup and hot gløgg in the Great Hall.
Il y a de la soupe et du vin chaud dans le grand halle.
[There soup and mulled wine in the big hall.]
Here, pass these out.
Tenez, je vous laisse continuer.
[Here, I'll let you continue.]
Prince Hans!
Are we expected to just sit here and freeze
Sommes-nous censés restés les bras croisés en gelant
[Are we supposed stood idly by freezing]
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
pendant que vous distribuez toutes les ressources monnayables du royaume?
[as you distribute any marketable resources of the kingdom?]
Princess Anna has given her orders.
La princesse Anna à donner des ordres.
[Princess Anna to give orders.]
And that's another thing!
Vous faites bien d'en parler!
[You do well to talk about!]
Has it dawned on you that your princess may be conspiring
Ne vous est-il pas venu à l'esprit que votre princesse puisse comploter avec
[Is it not come to your mind that your princess can conspire with]
with a wicked sorceress
une méchante sorcière
[a wicked witch]
to destroy us all?
pour nous anéantir?
[to destroy us?]
Do not question the princess.
Je vous défends de suspecter la princesse.
[I forbid you to suspect the princess.]
She left me in charge
Elle m'a demandé de
[She asked me to]
and I will not hesitate
veiller sur la royaume
[watch over the kingdom]
to protect Arendelle from treason.
et je protègerai Arendelle de la trahison.
[and I will protect Arendelle treason.]
Treason?
De la trahison?
[Betrayal?]
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Tout doux! Tout doux.
[Softly! Softly.]
Easy.
Tout doux.
[Softly.]
It's Princess Anna's horse.
C'est le cheval de la princesse Anna.
[This is the horse of Princess Anna.]
So, where is the princess?
Que lui est-il arrivé? Où est-elle?
[What happened to him? Where is she?]
Where could she be? - Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
La princesse Anna est en danger.
[Princess Anna is in danger.]
I need volunteers to go with me to find her.
J'ai besoin de volontaires qui m'accompagneront pour la retrouver.
[I need volunteers who accompany me to find her.]
I'll go. I volunteer.
Je vous suis.
[I follow you.]
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Je vous offre l'aide de deux hommes, mon seigneur.
[I offer you the help of two men, my lord.]
Be prepared for anything.
Préparez-vous au pire.
[Prepare for the worst.]
And should you encounter the queen,
Et si vous croisez la reine Elsa
[And if you cross the Queen Elsa]
you are to put an end to this winter.
je vous demanderai de mettre fin à l'hiver.
[I ask you to end the winter.]
Do you understand?
Est-ce que vous comprenez?
[Do you understand?]
So, how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
Alors, comment comptez-vous
mettre fin à l'hiver, exactement?
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
Oh. Je vais aller parler à ma sœur.
[Oh. I'll go talk to my sister.]
That's your plan?
C'est ça, votre plan?
[That's your plan?]
My ice business is riding on you talking to your sister?
Mon travail dépend d'une discussion avec votre sœur?
[My work depends on a discussion with your sister?]
Yep.
Ouep.
[Yep.]
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
Et, vous n'avez pas du tout peur d'elle?
[And you do not at all afraid of her?]
Why would I be?
Pourquoi j'aurais peur?
[Why would I be afraid?]
Yeah. I bet she's the nicest, gentlest, warmest person ever.
Ouais. Je suis sûre que c'est la fille la plus gentille et la plus chalereuse du monde.
[Yeah. I am sure this is the nicest and most horny girl in the world.]
Oh. Look at that.
Oh. Regardez ça.
[Oh. Look at that.]
I've been impaled.
On dirait une épinglette.
[It looks like a pin.]
What now?
On fait quoi maintenant?
[What are we doing now?]
Mmm...
It's too steep.
C'est trop abrupte.
[It's too steep.]
I've only got one rope and you don't know how to climb mountains.
Je n'ai qu'une corde et vous ne savez pas escalader des montagnes.
[I have only one string and you can not climb mountains.]
Says who?
Ah oui?
[Oh yes?]
Hmm?
What are you doing?
Qu'est-ce que vous faites?
[What are you doing?]
I'm going to see my sister.
Je vais aller voir ma sœur.
[I'm going to see my sister.]
You're gonna kill yourself.
Vous allez finir par vous tuer.
[You will eventually kill you.]
I wouldn't put my foot there.
Je mettrais pas mon pied là.
[I would not put my foot there.]
You're distracting me. - Or there.
Vous me déconcentrez. - Là non plus.
[You déconcentrez me. - Here too.]
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
Vous ne savez même pas si Elsa veut vous voir?
[You do not even know if Elsa wants to see you?]
All right. I'm just blocking you out
D'accord. Alors je vais faire comme si
[Okay. So I'll pretend]
because I gotta concentrate, here.
vous n'étiez pas là, car vous me déconcentrez.
[you were not there, because you déconcentrez me.]
You know, most people who disappear
Vous savez, la plupart des gens
[You know, most people]
into the mountains want to be alone.
qui disparaissent dans les montagnes veulent être seuls.
[that disappear in the mountains want to be alone.]
Nobody wants to be alone.
Personne ne veut être seul.
[Nobody wants to be alone.]
Except maybe you.
Sauf vous peut-être.
[Except perhaps you.]
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
Je ne suis pas seul. J'ai des amis, vous vous rappelez?
[I am not alone. I have friends, remember?]
You mean, the love experts?
Vous parlez des experts en amour?
[You speak of experts in love?]
Yes, the love experts.
Oui, absolument.
[Yes absolutely.]
Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Pitié, dites-moi que j'y suis presque...
[Please, tell me I'm almost there...]
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
C'est normal qu'on ait moins d'air en altitude?
[It is normal to have less air at altitude?]
Hang on.
J'arrive.
[I arrive.]
Hey, Sven?
Hé, Sven?
[Hey, Sven?]
Not sure if this is gonna solve the problem,
Je ne suis pas sûr que ça va résoudre notre problème
[I'm not sure it will solve our problem]
but I found a staircase that leads exactly
mais j'ai trouvé un escalier qui monte exactement
[but I found a staircase that rises exactly]
where you wanted to go.
là où on veut aller.
[where we want to go.]
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
Ha-ha! C'est génial. Attrapez-moi!
[Ha- ha! It's awesome. Catch me!]
Thanks. That was like a crazy trust exercise.
Merci. Ça c'est ce qu'on appelle un exercice de confiance.
[Thank you. That's called an exercise in trust.]
Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
Alors ça, c'est de la glace.
[So that's ice.]
I might cry.
Je vais pleurer.
[I'm going to cry.]
Go ahead. I won't judge.
Allez-y. Je ne vous jugerai pas.
[Go for it. I do not judge you.]
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
Attends, tout doux, Sven. Viens ici.
[Wait, soft, Sven. Come here.]
I got you.
C'est bon, je te tiens.
[All right, I got you.]
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
Voilà. Tu restes ici, mon vieux.
[Here. You stay here, man.]
Flawless.
C'est génial.
[It's awesome.]
Knock.
Frappe.
[Hit.]
Just knock.
Frappe, allez.
[Strikes, go.]
Why isn't she knocking?
Pourquoi elle frappe pas?
[Why not hit it?]
Do you think she knows how to knock?
Tu crois qu'elle sais pas comment faire?
[You think she not know how?]
Huh. It opened.
Huh. C'est ouvert.
[Huh. It is open.]
That's a first.
Ça c'est nouveau.
[That is new.]
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
Oh. Vous.. vous devriez peut-être attendre ici.
[Oh. You.. you might want to wait here.]
What? - The last time I introduced her to a guy,
Quoi? - La dernière fois que je lui ai présenté un garçon
[What? - Last time I introduced him to a boy]
she froze everything.
elle a tout gelé autour d'elle.
[she froze everything around it.]
But, but... Oh, come on!
Mais, mais... Oh, s'il vous plaît!
[But, but... Oh, please!]
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
C'est un palace de glace. La glace, c'est toute ma vie!
[It's an ice palace. Ice, it's my life!]
Bye, Sven.
Au revoir, Sven!
[Goodbye, Sven!]
You, too, Olaf.
Toi aussi, Olaf.
[You too, Olaf.]
Me? - Just give us a minute.
Moi? - S'il te plaît, donne-nous une minute.
[I? - Please, give us a minute.]
Okay.
D'accord.
[Okay.]
One, two, three...
Un, deux, trois...
[One two Three...]
Four...
Quatre...
[Four...]
Whoa.
Elsa?
It's me, Anna.
C'est moi, Anna.
[It's me, Anna.]
Anna.
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
Waouh. Elsa, tu es, différente.
[Wow. Elsa, you are, different.]
It's a good different.
Mais dans le bon sens.
[But in a good way.]
And this place...
Et cet endroit est...
[And this place is...]
It's amazing.
absolument magnifique.
[absolutely beautiful.]
Thank you.
Merci.
[Thank you.]
I never knew what I was capable of.
Je n'ai jamais su de quoi j'étais capable.
[I never knew what I was capable.]
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd have known...
Je suis vraiment navrée de ce qui s'est passé. Si j'avais su, je...
[I'm really sorry about what happened. If I had known, I...]
No, no, no. It's okay.
Non, non, non. Ne t'en fais pas.
[No no no. Do not worry.]
You don't have to apologize, but you should probably go.
Tu n'as pas à t'excuser, mais tu dois t'en aller.
[You do not have to apologize, but you have to go away.]
Please.
Je t'en prie.
[Please.]
But I just got here.
Mais je viens à peine d'arriver.
[But I have only just arrived.]
You belong down in Arendelle.
Ta place est à Arendelle.
[You belong to Arendelle.]
So do you.
La tienne aussi.
[Yours also.]
No, Anna, I belong here.
Non, Anna, ma place est ici.
[No, Anna, my place is here.]
Alone.
Seule.
[Alone.]
Where I can be who I am without hurting anybody.
Où je peux être qui je suis, sans risquer de faire de mal aux autres.
[Where I can be who I am without risking harm to others.]
Actually, about that...
Justement, à propos de ça...
[Precisely, about that...]
Sixty! - Wait. What is that?
Soixante! - Attends. Qui est là?
[Sixty! - Wait. Who is here?]
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
Salut! Je m'appelle Olaf et j'adore les câlins!
[Hi! My name is Olaf and love hugs!]
Olaf?
You built me.
Oui. Vous m'avez créé.
[Yes I do. You created me.]
Remember that?
Vous vous en souvenez?
[You remember?]
And you're alive?
Et tu es vivant?
[And you're alive?]
Um... I think so.
Je.. euhm, je pense que oui.
[I.. Um, I think so.]
He's just like the one we built as kids.
Il est comme celui qu'on avait fait petites.
[It's like that little had been done.]
Yeah.
Oui.
[Yes I do.]
Elsa, we were so close.
Elsa, nous étions si proches.
[Elsa, we were so close.]
We can be like that again.
Nous pourrions l'être à nouveau.
[We could be again.]
Catch me! Slow down!
Attrape-moi! - Pas si vite!
[Catch me! - Not so fast!]
Anna!
No.
Non.
[No.]
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
C'est impossible. Au revoir, Anna.
[It's impossible. Goodbye, Anna.]
Elsa, wait.
Elsa, attends.
[Elsa, wait.]
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
Non, j'essaie simplement de te proteger.
[No, I'm just trying to protect you.]
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
Tu n'as pas à me proteger. Je n'ai pas peur.
[You do not have to protect me. I am not afraid.]
Please don't shut me out again.
Je t'en prie, ne me rejettes pas à nouveau.
[I beg you, do not reject me again.]
Please don't slam the door
Ne claques pas la porte
[Do not slap the door]
You don't have to keep your distance anymore
Tu n'as pas le droit de me fuire de la sorte
[You do not have the right to flee me like this]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Car je veux fêter ce renouveau
[Because I want to celebrate this renewal]
I finally understand
Qui va changer ton destin
[Which will change your destiny]
For the first time in forever
Je veux fêter ce renouveau
[I want to celebrate this renewal]
We can fix this hand in hand
Avec toi main dans la main
[With you hand in hand]
We can head down this mountain together.
Nous nous libérerons de ce fardeau.
[We free ourselves of this burden.]
You don't have to live in fear
Tu ne dois plus avoir peur
[You must not be afraid]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Car je vais fêter ce renouveau
[Because I will celebrate this renewal]
I will be right here
Avec toi, ma sœur
[With you, my sister]
Anna.
[Anna.]
Please go back home
Rentre au royaume
[Returned to the kingdom]
Your life awaits
Tout est fini
[It's all over]
Go enjoy the sun, and open up the gates
Le soleil t'attend, ouvre-toi à la vie
[The sun awaits you open yourself to life]
Yeah, but...
Oui mais...
[Yes but...]
I know.
Je sais.
[I know.]
You mean well, but leave me be
Ne m'en veux pas, de vous quitter
[Do not want me to leave you]
Yes, I'm alone
Me voilà seule
[Here I am alone]
But I'm alone and free
Mais libre et délivrée
[But free and delivered]
Just stay away and you'll be safe from me
Éloigne-toi et tu sera sauvée
[Walk away and you will be saved]
Actually, we're not
Non, je ne crois pas
[No I do not think so]
What do you mean, you're not?
Non, tu ne crois pas?
[No, do not you think?]
I get the feeling you don't know
Tu ne semble pas au courant
[You do not seem aware]
What do I not know?
Moi pas au courant?
[I not know?]
Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep
Arendelle est figé figé figé
[Arendelle froze frozen frozen]
deep snow
hors du temps
[out of time]
What?
Comment?
[How?]
You kind of set off an eternal winter everywhere.
Tu as plongé dans un hiver éternel le pays tout entier.
[You have plunged into eternal winter the entire country.]
Everywhere?
Le pays tout entier?
[The whole country?]
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
Mais ce n'est rien, provoque le dégel.
[But this is nothing, causes the thaw.]
No, I can't. I don't know how.
Non, je ne peux pas. J'en suis incapable.
[No I can not. I can not do.]
Sure you can. I know you can.
Mais oui, voyons. Tu en es capable.
[Yes, see. You are capable.]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Parce qu'il faut fêter ce renouveau
[Because we must celebrate this renewal]
Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free!
Oh... Ni libérée, ni délivrée!
[Oh... Neither liberated nor delivered!]
You don't have to be afraid
Tu n'auras plus jamais peur
[You will never fear]
No escape from the storm inside of me
Dites-moi comment ne pas désespérer
[Tell me how not to despair]
We can work this out together
Ensemble nous ferons ce qu'il faut
[Together we will do what it takes]
I can't control the curse!
Ce don est si intense!
[This gift is so intense!]
We'll reverse the storm you've made
Pour sortir de cette torpeur
[To get out of this torpor]
Anna, please you'll only make it worse!
Toutes ces belles promesses n'ont pas de sens!
[All these promises have no meaning!]
Don't panic!
Rassure-toi
[Do not worry]
There's so much fear!
Ce sera pire!
[It will be worse!]
We'll make the sun shine bright
Le soleil reviendra!
[The sun will come back!]
You're not safe here!
Tu vas souffrir!
[You will suffer!]
We can face this thing together
Face au mauvais sort nous sommes deux!
[Facing the bad luck we are two!]
No!
Non!
[No!]
We can change this winter weather
Nous revivrons des jours heureux!
[We will relive happy days!]
And everything will be all right
Quand cet hiver disparaîtra!
[When this winter will disappear!]
I can't!
Adieu!
[Farewell!]
Anna!
Are you okay?
Est-ce que ça va?
[Are you OK?]
I'm okay.
Oui ça va.
[Yes I'm ok.]
I'm fine.
Je vais bien.
[I'm fine.]
Who's this?
Qui est-ce?
[Who is it?]
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
Non, enfin ça n'a aucune importance. Il faut...
[No, well it does not matter. It is necessary...]
You have to go.
Il faut que tu t'en ailles.
[We need you to go.]
No, I know we can figure this out together.
Non. Je sais que nous pouvons trouver une solution ensemble.
[No. I know we can find a solution together.]
How?
What power do you have to stop this winter?
Tu as des pouvoirs magiques pour arrêter l'hiver?
[You have magical powers to stop the winter?]
To stop me?
Ou pour m'arrêter?
[Or to stop me?]
Anna, I think we should go.
Anna, on devrait y aller.
[Anna, we should go.]
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Non, je ne pars pas sans toi, Elsa.
[No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.]
Yes, you are.
Oui, il le faut.
[Yes it is needed.]
Stop! Put us down!
Arrêtez! Reposez-nous!
[Stop! Rest us!]
Go away.
Allez-vous-en.
[Go away.]
Heads up!
Baissez-vous!
[Get down!]
Watch out for my butt!
Attention à mon arrière!
[Attention to my back!]
It is not nice to throw people!
C'est n'est pas poli de jeter de la neige sur les gens.
[It's not polite to throw snow on people.]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants. Okay, relax.
Woah, woah, woah, woah. On se calme, ma bagarreur. Lâchez-moi
[Woah, woah, woah, woah. Calm down, my fighter. Let me go]
Just calm down! Calm down! - Okay! All right!
On se calme! On se calme! - C'est bon, ça va.
[Calms you! Calms you! - All right, okay.]
I'm okay. - Just let the snowman be.
Je suis calme. - Laissez-le tranquille.
[I'm calm. - Leave him alone.]
I'm calm.
Je suis calme.
[I'm calm.]
Oh! Come on!
Oh! Non! Je...
[Oh! No! I...]
Oh. Look, see? Now you made him mad.
Et voilà. Vous l'avez énervé maintenant.
[There you go. You've pissed now.]
I'll distract him. You guys go.
Je vais faire diversion. Allez-vous-en.
[I'll create a diversion. Go away.]
No, no! Not you guys!
Non, non, non! Pas toi!
[No no no! Not you!]
This just got a whole lot harder.
Ça va être plus difficile que prévu.
[It will be more difficult than expected.]
Look out!
Attention!
[Warning!]
What are you doing?
Qu'est-ce que vous faites?
[What are you doing?]
I got him!
Je l'ai eu!
[I got it!]
Whoa! Stop!
Arrêtez!
[Stop!]
It's a hundred-foot drop.
C'est un saut de trente mètres.
[That's a jump of thirty meters.]
It's two hundred.
Je dirais plus que soixante-sept.
[I would say more sixty seven.]
Ow!
What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
Qu'est-ce que vous faites? - Je plante une ancre dans la neige.
[What are you doing? - I plant an anchor in the snow.]
Okay. What if we fall?
D'accord. Et si on tombe?
[Okay. And if we fall?]
There's 20 feet of fresh powder down there.
Il y a six mètres de poudreuse en bas.
[There are six meters of powder down.]
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
Ce serait comme aterrir sur un oreiller.
[It would be like aterrir on a pillow.]
Hopefully.
Ça j'espère.
[That I hope.]
Okay, Anna. On three.
Okay, Anna. À trois.
[Okay, Anna. At three.]
One...
Un...
[A...]
Okay. You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
D'accord. Dites-moi quand je dois sauter.
[Okay. Tell me when I have to jump.]
Two... - I was born ready! Yes!
Deux... - Je vais y arriver, je suis la meilleure!
[Two... - I'll get there, I'm the best!]
Calm down.
Du calme.
[Calm.]
Tree!
Trois!
[Three!]
What the... Whoa!
Attendez!
[Wait!]
That happened.
J'en étais sûr.
[I was sure of it.]
Man, am I out of shape.
Oh, faut que je me mette au sport.
[Oh, I have to put myself in sport.]
There we go. Hey, Anna!
Et voilà. Hé Anna!
[There you go. Hey Anna!]
Sven! Where did you guys go?
Sven! Où êtes-vous?
[Sven! Where are you?]
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
On a réussi à semer la grande guimauve.
[We managed to sow large marshmallow.]
Hey! We were just talking about you.
Hé! On parlait justement de toi...
[Hey! We were just talking about you...]
All good things, all good things.
Mais on disait que du bien, que du bien.
[But it was said that good, but good.]
No!
Non!
[No!]
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
Je suis pas sûr que ça sert à grand-chose ce que je fais.
[I'm not sure it serves much what I do.]
Olaf!
Hang in there, guys!
Vous en faites pas pour moi!
[Do not worry for me!]
Go. Go faster!
Plus vite. Plus vite!
[Faster. Faster!]
Wait, what?
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
[What is going on?]
Ow!
Kristoff!
Don't come back!
Ne revenez jamais!
[Never come back!]
We won't.
C'est promis.
[I promise.]
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
Hé, vous aviez raison. C'est comme un oreiller.
[Hey, you were right. It's like a pillow.]
Olaf!
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
Je sens plus mes jambes. Je sens plus mes jambes!
[I feel my legs. I feel my legs!]
Those are my legs.
Parce que ce sont mes jambes.
[Because these are my legs.]
Oooh. Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
Tu m'attrapes mon arrier s'il te plaît?
[You catch me my BACK please?]
Oh. That feels better.
Ah. Je me sens beaucoup mieux.
[Ah. I feel much better.]
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Oh regarde, Sven! Il nous a retrouvés!
[Oh look, Sven! He found us!]
Who's my cute little reindeer?
C'est qui mon petit renne préféré.
[Who is my favorite little reindeer.]
Don't talk to him like that.
Ne lui parlez pas comme ça.
[Do not talk to her like that.]
You're tickling me.
Arrête de me chatouiller.
[Stop tickling me.]
Here.
J'arrive.
[I arrive.]
Whoa!
Woah!
[Woah!]
Are you okay?
Ça va?
[How are you?]
Thank you.
Merci.
[Thank you.]
How's your head? - Ah! Ooh!
Et votre tête? - Ah! Ouh!
[And your head? - Ah! Ooh!]
It's fine. Uh...
Ce n'est rien. Euh..
[It is nothing. Uh..]
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
Je vais bien. J'ai le crâne solide.
[I'm fine. I have the solid skull.]
I don't have a skull.
Moi, j'ai pas de crâne.
[I have no head.]
Or bones.
Et pas de squelette.
[And no skeleton.]
So, uh... So, now what?
Alors, euhm... On fait quoi maintenant?
[So, Um... What do we do now?]
Now what?
On fait quoi?
[What do we do?]
Now what?
On fait quoi!?
[What do we do!?]
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
Mais qu'est-ce que je vais faire?
[But what will I do?]
She threw me out.
Elle m'a rejetée.
[She rejected.]
I can't go back to Arendelle with the weather like this.
Je ne peux pas retourner à Arendelle si l'hiver est toujours là.
[I can not go back to Arendelle if the winter is still there.]
And then there's your ice business.
Et puis, 'y a votre travail aussi. Qu'est-ce que vous allez faire?
[And' there is your work too. What are you going to do?]
Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
Ne vous inquitez pas pour mon travail.
[Do not worry for my work.]
Worry about your hair!
Mais plus pour vos cheveux!
[But not for your hair!]
What? I just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
Quoi? On viens de tomber d'une falaise. Vous vous êtes regardé?
[What? It just fell off a cliff. You've watched?]
No, yours is turning white.
Non, les vôtres deviennent blancs.
[No, yours turn white.]
White? It's... What?
Blanc? C'est.. quoi?
[White? What's this?]
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
C'est parce qu'elle vous a touchée, c'est ça?
[This is because it has affected you, right?]
Does it look bad?
J'ai l'air bizarre?
[I look weird?]
No. - You hesitated.
Non. - T'as hesité.
[No. - You hesitated.]
No, I didn't.
Non, pas du tout.
[No, not at all.]
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
Anna, vous avez besoin d'aide. Alors allons-y.
[Anna, you need help. So let's go.]
Okay! Where are we going?
D'accord! Où est-ce qu'on va?
[Okay! Where are we going?]
To see my friends.
On va voir mes amis.
[We'll see my friends.]
The love experts?
Les.. experts en amour?
[.. The experts love?]
Love experts?
Les experts en amour?
[Experts in love?]
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
Et ne vous en faites pas. Il vont régler votre problème.
[And do not worry. It will solve your problem.]
How do you know?
Comment savez-vous?
[How do you know?]
Because I've seen them do it before.
Parce que je les ai déjà vus faire.
[Because I've seen them do.]
I like to consider myself a love expert.
Moi aussi je suis un expert en amour.
[I too am an expert on love.]
Get it together.
Tu vas y arriver.
[You can do it.]
Control it.
Contrôle-toi.
[Control yourself.]
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Ça va aller, ça va aller.
[It's okay, it's okay.]
Don't feel.
Il faut que tu arrives
[You have to arrive]
Don't feel!
à te contrôler.
[to control you.]
Look, Sven, the sky's awake.
Regarde, Sven, le ciel se réveille.
[Look, Sven, the sky awakens.]
Are you cold? - A little.
Vous avez froid? - Un peu.
[You are cold? - A little.]
Uh... Wait. Come here.
Euh... attendez. Venez ici.
[Uh... wait. Come here.]
Huh?
D'accord
[Okay]
Ooh.
So, uh, about my friends. Well...
Sinon... au sujet de mes amis, en fait...
[Otherwise... about my friends, actually...]
I say "friends"...
je devrais plutôt dire
[I should say]
They're more like family.
qu'ils sont comme ma famille.
[they are like my family.]
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven.
Enfin bref, quand j'étais petit il n'y avait que moi et Sven.
[Anyway, when I was little it was just me and Sven.]
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
Jusqu'à ce que... à ce qu'ils m'adoptent en quelque sorte.
[Until... that they adopt me somehow.]
They did?
C'est vrai?
[It's true?]
Yeah. I don't want to scare you.
Ouais. Je ne veux pas vous effrayer
[Yeah. I do not want to scare you]
They can be a little inappropriate and loud.
mais ils sont un peu différents... et bruyants.
[but they are a little different... and noisy.]
Very loud.
Très bruyants.
[Very noisy.]
They are also stubborn at times,
Ils sont aussi têtus, parfois
[They are also stubborn, sometimes]
and a little overbearing.
et un peu autoritaire.
[and a little bossy.]
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
et lourds aussi. Vraiment, vraiment très lourds.
[and also heavy. Really, really heavy.]
But you'll get it. They mean well.
Ce qui peut surprendre. Mais vous verrez, ça ira. Ils sont très gentils.
[What may surprise. But you'll see, it'll. They are very nice.]
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Kristoff, ils ont l'air merveilleux.
[Kristoff, they look wonderful.]
Okay, then.
Très bien, alors.
[Very well then.]
Meet my family.
Voici ma famille.
[Here is my family.]
Hey, guys.
Salut.
[Hi.]
They're rocks.
Ce sont des rochers.
[Just rocks.]
You are a sight for sore eyes.
Woah, tu es magnifique!
[Woah, you're beautiful!]
He's crazy. - Hey look, Magma's back from vacation!
Il est complètement cinglé.
[It is completely crazy.]
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Rocko est toujours aussi chic à ce que je vois.
[Rocko is always so chic that I see.]
Clay, whoa... I don't even recognize you.
Clarice, woah... Je t'avais pas reconnue.
[Clarice, woah... I had not recognized you.]
You lost so much weight.
I'll distract him while you run. - Didn't realize how much I missed you guys.
Je vais faire diversion, enfuis-toi.
[I'll create a diversion, fled down.]
Hi, Sven's family!
Salut la famille de Sven!
[Hi Sven family!]
It's nice to meet you.
C'est génial de faire votre connaissance.
[It's great to meet you.]
Because I love you, Anna, I insist you run. - Guys, I've got so much to tell you.
Parce que je tiens à toi Anna, j'insiste, va-t'en.
[Because I want you to Anna, I insist, go away.]
I understand you're love experts. Ooh! - Stop kissing Crystal and find Grandpabbie!
On m'a dit que vous étiez des experts en amour. Ooh!
[I was told you were the experts in love. Ooh!]
Why aren't you running?
Pourquoi tu ne t'enfuis pas?
[Why do not you run away?]
Uh...
Euh...
[Uh...]
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
D'accord. Alors, je vais m'en aller.
[Okay. So I am going away.]
No, no, no. Anna, wait.
Allez. - Non, non, non. Anna, attendez.
[Come on. - No no no. Anna, wait.]
Kristoff!
Whoa!
Hey!
Kristoff's home!
Kristoff est revenu!
[Kristoff is back!]
Kristoff's here! Kristoff's home!
Kristoff est revenu!
[Kristoff is back!]
Wait, "Kristoff"?
Attends, "Kristoff"?
[Wait," Kristoff"?]
Ah, let me look at you.
Ah, laisse-moi te regarder.
[Ah, let me look at you.]
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
Enlève tes vêtements, je vais les laver.
[Take off your clothes, I'll wash them.]
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
Non! Non, je vais garder mes vêtements.
[No! No, I'll keep my clothes.]
Look, it's great to see you all,
C'est génial de vous retrouver
[It's great to see you]
but where's Granpabbie?
mais où est grand-père?
[but where is Grandpa?]
He's napping.
Il fait une sièste.
[It makes a siesta.]
But look, I grew a mushroom.
Mais regarde! J'ai un champignon qui a poussé.
[But look! I have a fungus that grew.]
I earned my fire crystal.
J'ai gagné mon cristal de feu.
[I won my fire crystal.]
I passed a kidney stone.
J'ai eu un calcul au rein.
[I had a kidney calculation.]
Kristoff, pick me up.
Kristoff, prends-moi dans tes bras.
[Kristoff, take me in your arms.]
You're getting big.
T'es devenu un grand garçon.
[You're a big boy now.]
Good for you.
Je suis impressioné.
[I am impressed.]
Trolls. They're trolls!
Des trolls. Ce sont des trolls!
[Trolls. They are trolls!]
He's brought a girl!
Il nous amène une fille!
[It brings us a girl!]
A girl!
Une fille!
[A girl!]
Is that a real girl?
She's like a little cupcake.
What's going on?
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
[What is going on?]
I've learned to just roll with it.
J'ai appris à m'y habituer.
[I learned to get used to.]
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
Une minute. Des yeux vifs, nez fonctionnel
[One minute. Lively eyes, nose functional]
strong teeth!
excellente dentition!
[excellent teeth!]
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
Oui, oui. Elle est parfaite pour notre Kristoff.
[Yes Yes. It is perfect for our Kristoff.]
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
Attendez une seconde.
[Wait a second.]
You've got the wrong idea.
Attends, attends. Tu te trompes.
[Wait wait. You're wrong.]
No. That's not why I brought her here.
Non, ce n'est pas pour
ça que je l'amène.
Right. We're not... I'm not...
C'est vrai. On est pas... Je suis pas...
[It's true. It's not... I'm not...]
What's the issue, dear?
Que se passe-t-il mon ange?
[What happens there my angel?]
Why are you holding back from such a man?
Pourquoi refusez-vous les avances d'un si beau garçon?
[Why do you refuse the advances of a beautiful boy?]
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
Est-ce parce qu'il marche de travers?
[Is it because he walks awry?]
What? - Or the grumpy way he talks?
Quoi? - Qu'il a mauvais charactère?
[What? - That he has bad Character?]
Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
Ou c'est drôles de poires
[Or it's funny pears]
Weirdness of his feet?
Qui lui servent de pieds?
[Which serve as feet?]
Hey!
And though we know he washes well
Pour se laver il attend la pluie
[To wash it expects rain]
He always ends up sort of smelly
Il a son odeur bien à lui
[It has the smell of his own]
But you'll never meet a fella
Mais on ne connaît personne
[But one does not know anyone]
Who's as sensitive and sweet
D'aussi tendre et attentionné
[For as tender and caring]
That's nice, but...
C'est gentil, mais...
[That's nice, but...]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
Il est peut-être moins que parfait
[It may be less than perfect]
So, he's got a few flaws
Il est peu raffiné
[It is not refined]
Like his peculiar brain, dear
Son cerveau à l'envers
[His brain upside]
His thing with the reindeer
Sa passion pour les cerfs
[His passion for deer]
That's a little outside of nature's laws
C'est vrai qu'il a l'air un peu perturbé
[Yes it looks a little perturbed]
This is not about me!
Surtout ne les écoutez pas!
[Above all, do not listen!]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
Il est peut-être un peu moins que parfait
[It is perhaps a little less than perfect]
But this we're certain of
Mais on est sûr qu'un jour
[But we are sure that one day]
You can fix this fixer-upper up
Il pourra devenir presque parfait
[It may become almost perfect]
With a little bit of love
Il suffit d'un peu d'amour
[Just a little love]
Can we please just stop talking about this?
S'il vous plaît, est-ce qu'on pourrait changer de sujet?
[Please, do what we could change the subject?]
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
Nous sommes là parce que nous avons un veritable problème.
[We are here because we have a real problem.]
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Ça se voit. Alors, dites-moi trésor
[It shows. So tell me treasure]
Is it the way that he runs scared?
Est-ce parce que c'est un gros peureux?
[Is it because it's a big coward?]
Or that he's socially impaired?
Que, des amis, il en a peu?
[That, friends, there are few?]
Or that he only likes to tinkle in the woods?
Qu'il aime faire pipi dans l'herbe au fond des bois?
[He likes to pee in the grass in the woods?]
I did not need to know that.
Ça, je ne voulais pas savoir.
[That I do not want to know.]
Are you holding back your fondness
C'est pas que vous le trouvez laid?
[It's not that you find ugly?]
Due to his unmanly blondness?
C'est un charmant petit blondinet
[This is a charming little blond]
Or the way he covers up that he's the honest goods?
Son humilité cache l'âme et la bonté d'un roi
[His humility conceals the soul and goodness of a king]
He's just a bit of a fixer-upper
Il est peut-être un peu moins que parfait
[It is perhaps a little less than perfect]
He's got a couple of bugs
Les poux et les puces l'aiment bien
[Lice and fleas like him]
(No, I don't!) - His isolation is confirmation
(Ce n'est pas vrai!) - Cette drôle d'attitude C'est la solitude
[(This is not true!) - This funny attitude this loneliness]
Of his desperation for healing hugs
Il n'a pas l'habitude des gros câlins!
[It did not used to big hugs!]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
Il est peut-être un peu moins que parfait
[It is perhaps a little less than perfect]
But we know what to do
Mais nous savons pourquoi
[But we know why]
The way to fix up this fixer-upper
Il faut que vous fassiez le premier pas
[We need you to make the first step]
Is to fix him up with you
Allez, on compte jusqu'à trois
[Come on, count to three]
Whoa!
Woah!
[Woah!]
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
Maintenant, ça suffit. Ça suffit!
[Enough is enough. That's enough!]
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
Elle a déjà quelqu'un. Cette jeune fille est fiancée.
[She already has somebody. This girl is betrothed.]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
Elle est peut-être un peu moins que parfaite
[It is perhaps a little less than perfect]
That's a minor thing
Tout ça est très vague
[All this is very vague]
Her quote "engagement" is a flex arrangement
Elle n'est que fiancée tout ça peut s'arranger.
[It is only engaged all this can be arranged.]
And by the way, I don't see no ring
Oui, d'autant plus qu'elle n'a pas de bague!
[Yes, especially since it does not ring!]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
Elle est peut-être un peu moins que parfaite
[It is perhaps a little less than perfect]
Her brain's a bit betwixt
Elle est toute chamboulée!
[It is all out of whack!]
Get the fiance out of the way
Débarrassons-nous du fiancé
[Let's get rid of the bridegroom]
And the whole thing will be fixed
Et là tout sera réglé!
[And then everything will be settled!]
We're not saying you can change him
N'essayez pas de le changer
[Do not try to change]
'Cause people don't really change
Ici-bas nul n'est parfait
[Down here nobody is perfect]
We're only saying that love's a force
Mais l'amour est un sentiment fort
[But love is a strong sense]
That's powerful and strange
Qui reste plein de secrets
[Which remains full of secrets]
People make bad choices
On fait de mauvais choix
[We made ​​bad choices]
If they're mad or scared or stressed
Quand on est triste ou qu'on a peur
[When we are sad or we are afraid]
But throw a little love their way
Donnons aux autres un peu d'amour
[Give others a little love]
Throw a little love their way
Donnons-leur un peu d'amour!
[Give them some love!]
And you'll bring out their best
Ça les rendra meilleurs!
[It'll make the best!]
True love brings out the best
Oui, l'amour rend meilleur!
[Yes, love makes best!]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
Oui, nous sommes tous un peu moins que parfaits!
[Yes, we're all a little less than perfect!]
That's what it's all about
Sinon ce ne serait pas drôle!
[Otherwise it would not be funny!]
Father! Sister! Brother!
Le père! La sœur! Le frère!
[The father! Sister! Brother!]
We need each other to raise us up
On a tous besoin les uns des autres
[We all need each other]
And round us out
Chacun son rôle
[Each role]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
C'est vrai on est tous un peu moins que parfaits
[It's true we're all a little less than perfect]
But when push comes to shove
Mais comme il faut faire court
[But as it must be short]
The only fixer-upper fixer
Ce qui rend presque parfaits
[Making it almost perfect]
That can fix a fixer-upper is...
les gens un peu moins que parfaits c'est...
[people a little less than perfect is...]
True, true
De l'amour, de l'amour
[Of love, love]
True
C'est l'amour
[It's love]
Love!
L'amour
[love]
Love, love, love
La la l'amour
[The love]
Love! True love
L'amour
[love]
True
L'amour
[love]
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
Acceptez-vous, Anna, de prendre pour époux Kristoff, pour le meilleur et pour le pire...
[Accept yourself, Anna, to take to Kristoff husband, for better or for worse...]
Wait, what? - You're getting married.
Attendez, quoi? - Je vous marie.
[Wait, what? - I married you.]
Love!
L'amour!
[Love!]
Anna?
She's as cold as ice.
Elle est frigorifiée.
[It is refrigerated.]
There is strange magic here.
Je sens une étrange magie.
[I feel a strange magic.]
Granpabbie. - Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Grand-père. - Kristoff, approche-la s'il te plaît.
[Grandfather. - Kristoff, approach it please.]
Anna, your life is in danger.
Anna, votre vie est en danger.
[Anna, your life is in danger.]
There is ice in your heart put there by your sister.
Vous avez de la glace dans le cœur à cause de votre sœur.
[You have ice in the heart because of your sister.]
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
Si.. si nous la retirons pas vous serez transformé en bloc de glace pour toujours.
[If not.. if we retire you will be transformed into a block of ice forever.]
What? No.
Quoi? Non.
[What? No.]
But you can remove it, right?
Tu peux la guérir, n'est-ce pas?
[You can cure it, is not it?]
I cannot
Non, je regrette.
[No I regret.]
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
Je suis navré Kristoff.
[I'm sorry Kristoff.]
If it was her head, that would be easy.
Si sa tête avait été touchée, ça aurait été facile.
[If his head had been affected, it would have been easy.]
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
Mais seule une véritable preuve d'amour peut faire dégeler un cœur.
[But only a real proof of love can thaw a heart.]
An act of true love?
Une véritable preuve d'amour?
[A real proof of love?]
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
Un baiser d'amoureux peut-être.
[A loving kiss, perhaps.]
(Something's wrong. Are you all right?)
Oh non, Anna. Est-ce que ça va?
[Oh no, Anna. Are you OK?]
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Anna, vous devez aller voir Hans.
[Anna, you must go to Hans.]
Hans.
Pull us out, Sven.
Amène-nous là-bas, Sven.
[Bring us there, Sven.]
Olaf, come on!
Olaf, on s'en va!
[Olaf, we're going!]
I'm coming!
Oui, j'arrive!
[Yes I'm coming!]
Let's go kiss Hans!
Allons embrasser Hans!
[Hans will embrace!]
Who is this Hans?
Mais qui est ce "Hans"?
[But who is this"Hans"?]
We are here to find Princess Anna.
Nous sommes venus chercher la princesse Anna.
[We came for Princess Anna.]
Be on guard, but no harm is to come to the queen.
Restez sur vos gardes, mais ne faites aucun mal à la reine.
[Stay alert, but do no harm to the queen.]
Do you understand?
Vous avez compris?
[You understood?]
Yes, Your Grace.
Oui mon seigneur.
[Yes my Lord.]
The queen.
C'est la reine!
[This is the Queen!]
Go, go! Come on!
Allons Siegfried! Dépêchez-vous.
[Let Siegfried! Hurry up.]
There!
Up there!
Là-haut!
[Up there!]
Come on!
Suis-moi.
[Follow me.]
We got her.
Elle est là.
[She's there.]
No. Please.
Non, pitié.
[No, sorry.]
Go around. Toss it.
Viens par là. Vise-la!
[Come this way. Vise- la!]
Stay away!
N'approchez pas!
[Do not approach!]
Look out!
Fire! Fire!
Feu! Feu!
[Fire! Fire!]
Get her!
Arrête-toi!
[Stop!]
Ah!
Come on!
On arrive!
[We arrive!]
Grab his arm.
Accrochez-vous.
[Hold on.]
Aim...
Je l'ai...
[I got it...]
This way, this way!
Par ici!
[This way!]
Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Votre majesté!
[Your Majesty!]
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
Ne devenez pas le monstre qu'ils prétendent que vous êtes.
[Do not become the monster they claim you are.]
Oh, no. What have... What have I done?
Non, mais... Qu'est-ce que j'ai fait?
[No, but... What did I do?]
Why did you bring me here?
Pourquoi suis-je enfermée ici?
[Why am I locked up here?]
I couldn't just let them kill you.
Je ne voulais pas qu'ils vous tuent.
[I do not want them to kill you.]
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
Mais je suis un danger pour Arendelle. Je veux voir Anna.
[But I'm a danger to Arendelle. I want to see Anna.]
Anna has not returned.
Anna n'est pas revenue.
[Anna has not returned.]
If you would just stop the winter.
Il faut que vous mettiez fin à l'hiver.
[It is necessary that you end winter.]
Bring back summer, please.
Faites revenir l'été, je vous en prie.
[Sauté the summer, please.]
Don't you see?
J'en suis incapable.
[I can not do.]
I can't.
Je ne peux rien faire.
[I can not do anything.]
You have to tell them to let me go.
Vous devez leur demander de me libérer.
[You must ask them to release me.]
I will do what I can.
Je vais faire ce que je peux.
[I'll do what I can.]
Just hang in there.
Accrochez-vous.
[Hold on.]
Come on, buddy, faster!
Allez, plus vite Sven. Plus vite!
[Come on, faster Sven. Faster!]
Oh, boy!
Woah!
[Woah!]
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
Je vous rejoins au château, d'accord?
[I'll meet you at the castle, right?]
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
Fais-toi discret, Olaf!
[Make thee discreet, Olaf!]
I will!
C'est promis!
[I promise!]
Hello! - It's alive!
Coucou! - Il est vivant!
[Hello! - He is alive!]
It's Princess Anna!
C'est la princess Anna.
[It is the princess Anna.]
Are you gonna be okay?
Vous êtes sûr que vous allez vous en sortir?
[Are you sure you're going to get out?]
Don't worry about me.
Ne vous en faites pas pour moi.
[Do you worry for me.]
Anna!
You had us worried sick. My Lady.
Nous étions morts d'inquiètude. Majesté.
[We were worried dead. Majesty.]
Get her warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.
Amenez-la au chaud, et allez chercher le prince Hans immediatement.
[Bring her warm, and go for Prince Hans immediately.]
We will. Thank you.
J'y vais, merci beaucoup.
[I go, thank you very much.]
Make sure she's safe.
Prenez bien soin d'elle.
[Take good care of her.]
Oh, you poor girl, you're freezing.
Oh, let's get you inside now and get you warm.
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
Je vais repartir chercher la princesse Anna.
[I'll start looking Princess Anna.]
You cannot risk going out there again.
Vous ne pouvez pas prendre à nouveau ce risque.
[You can not take that risk again.]
If anything happens to her...
Si quelque chose lui arrivait...
[If anything happened to him...]
If anything happens to the princess,
Si quelque chose arrivait à la princesse
[If something happened to the Princess]
you are all Arendelle has left.
vous seriez le seul à pouvoir régner sur Arendelle.
[you'd be the only one able to rule over Arendelle.]
He's in here.
Il est ici.
[It is here.]
Prince Hans.
Anna.
You're so cold.
Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
Hans, vous devez m'embrasser.
[Hans, you have to kiss me.]
Now! Now! - Slow down.
Tout de suite. Tout de suite! - Calmez-vous.
[Right now. Right now! - Calm down.]
We'll give you two some privacy.
Laissons-leur un peu d'intimité.
[Give them some privacy.]
What happened out there?
Que s'est-il passé là-bas?
[What happened there?]
Elsa struck me with her powers.
Elsa m'a blessée avec ses pouvoirs.
[Elsa hurt me with his powers.]
You said she'd never hurt you.
Mais, vous disiez qu'elle ne vous ferait jamais de mal.
[But you said she would never do you wrong.]
I was wrong.
J'avais tort.
[I was wrong.]
Anna.
She froze my heart,
Elle a gelé mon cœur et...
[It froze my heart and...]
and only an act of true love can save me.
seule une véritable preuve d'amour peut me sauver.
[only real proof of love can save me.]
A true love's kiss.
Un baiser d'amour.
[A kiss of love.]
Oh, Anna.
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
Si seulement quelqu'un était amoureux de vous.
[If only someone was in love with you.]
What?
Quoi?
[What?]
You said you did.
Mais... vous disiez que vous m'aimiez.
[But... you said you loved me.]
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
Étant le treizième de ma lignée dans mon royaume
[Being the thirteenth of my line in my kingdom]
I didn't stand a chance.
je n'avais aucune chance d'accéder au throne.
[I had no chance of reaching the throne.]
I knew I would have to marry into the throne somewhere.
Ce n'est que par le mariage que je pouvais espérer régner un jour.
[It is only through marriage I could hope one day to reign.]
What... What are you talking about?
Mais... mais de quoi est-ce que vous parlez?
[But... but what do you mean?]
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
En tant qu'heritière, Elsa était mon premier choix, bien sûr.
[As heir, Elsa was my first choice, of course.]
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
Mais beaucoup d'autres avaient échoué avant moi.
[But many others had failed before me.]
But you...
Alors que vous...
[While you...]
You were so desperate for love,
Vous étiez si désespérée
[You were so desperate]
you were willing to marry me just like that.
vous étiez prête à m'épouser comme ça. Sans même me connaître.
[you were ready to marry me like that. Without even knowing me.]
I figured after we married,
J'avais prévu après notre mariage
[I had expected after our wedding]
I would have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
d'organiser un petit accident pour Elsa.
[arrange a little accident for Elsa.]
Hans! No. Stop.
Hans! Non, arrêtez.
[Hans! No, stop.]
But then, she doomed herself,
Mais elle s'est elle-même condamnée
[But she herself condemned]
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
et vous avez été assez idiote pour aller la rechercher.
[and you were stupid enough to go look for it.]
Please.
Je vous en prie.
[You're welcome.]
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
Tout ce qui me reste à faire maintenant, c'est de tuer Elsa.
[All that remains to do now is to kill Elsa.]
and bring back summer.
afin de ramener l'été.
[to bring the summer.]
You're no match for Elsa.
Vous n'êtes pas de taille à affronter Elsa.
[You are not match for Elsa.]
No, you're no match for Elsa.
Non, c'est vous qui n'êtes pas de taille à l'affronter.
[No, it is you who are not strong enough to face it.]
I, on the other hand,
Moi, en revanche...
[I, however...]
am the hero who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
Je suis le héros qui s'apprête à sauver Arendelle de la déstruction.
[I am the hero who is about to save Arendelle destruction.]
You won't get away with this.
Vous ne vous en tirerez pas comme ça.
[You do not get away like that.]
Oh...
I already have.
Désolé, c'est déjà fait.
[Sorry, it's already done.]
Please, somebody, help.
Pitié, aidez-moi. Au secours.
[Please, help me. Help.]
Please. Please.
Pitié. Pitié.
[Pity. Pity.]
It's getting colder by the minute.
Il fait de plus en plus froid.
[It's getting colder.]
If we don't do something soon, we'll all freeze to death.
Si nous ne faisons rien, nous allons tous mourir gelés.
[If we do nothing, we will all die frozen.]
Prince Hans.
Princess Anna is...
La princess Anna est...
[The princess Anna is...]
Dead.
Morte.
[Dead.]
What?
Quoi?
[What?]
What happened to her?
Que lui est-il arrivé?
[What happened to him?]
She was killed...
Elle a été tuée
[She was killed]
... by Queen Elsa.
par la reine Elsa.
[by Queen Elsa.]
No!
Non!
[No!]
Her own sister.
Sa propre sœur.
[His own sister.]
At least we got to say our marriage vows
Au moins nous avons prononcé nos vœux de mariage
[At least we have delivered our wedding vows]
before she died in my arms.
avant qu'elle ne s'éteigne dans mes bras.
[before she goes off in my arms.]
There can be no doubt now.
Il n'y a plus aucun doute à présent.
[There is no doubt now.]
Queen Elsa is a monster,
La reine Elsa est un monstre
[Queen Elsa is a monster]
and we are all in grave danger.
et nous sommes tous encore en danger.
[and we are all still in danger.]
Prince Hans,
Arendelle looks to you.
Arendelle se remet à vous.
[Arendelle returns to you.]
With a heavy heart,
C'est le cœur lourd
[It's heavy heart]
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason.
que j'accuse la reine Elsa d'Arendelle de trahison
[I accuse the queen of treason Elsa Arendelle]
And sentence her to death.
et ordonne son éxecution.
[and ordered his execution.]
Hurry up!
Venez, allons la chercher.
[Come, let's go get her.]
She's dangerous.
Elle est dangereuse.
[It is unsafe.]
Move quickly. Careful!
Agissez avec vigilance et détermination.
[Act with vigilance and determination.]
It won't open! It's frozen shut.
La porte est bloquée.
[The door being blocked.]
Put your back into it!
Come on! Push!
Attention!
[Warning!]
What is it, buddy?
Qu'y a-t-il, mon vieux?
[What is it, man?]
Hey, watch it.
Hé, fais attention.
[Hey, careful.]
What's wrong with you?
Mais qu'est-ce qui te prend?
[But what are you doing?]
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
Je ne comprends rien quand tu parles comme ça.
[I do not understand when you talk like that.]
Stop it! Put me down!
Arrête! Repose-moi tout de suite!
[Stopped! Put me right away!]
No, Sven!
Non, Sven!
[No, Sven!]
We're not going back.
On ne retourne pas là-bas.
[It does not return there.]
She's with her true love.
Elle est avec son grand amour.
[It is with great love.]
What the...
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
[What is going on?]
Anna!
Come on! Come on, boy.
Dépêche-toi. Allez, Sven!
[Hurry up. Come on, Sven!]
Help.
Au secours.
[Help.]
Anna!
Oh, no.
Oh, non.
[Oh no.]
Olaf?
Olaf. Get away from there.
Olaf! Éloigne-toi du feu.
[Olaf! Move away from the fire.]
Wow!
Waouh.
[Wow.]
So, this is heat.
Alors, c'est ça la chaleur.
[So that's the heat.]
I love it.
J'adore ça.
[I love it.]
Ooh! But don't touch it.
Ooh! Mais faut pas y toucher.
[Ooh! But should not touch it.]
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
Alors, où est Hans? Vous vous êtes embrassés?
[So where is Hans? You've kissed?]
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
Je me suis trompée sur lui. Ce n'était pas le grand amour.
[I was wrong about him. It was not the great love.]
But we ran all the way here.
Mais on est revenus ici pour lui.
[But we came back here for him.]
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here. You'll melt.
Va-t'en Olaf, tu ne peux pas rester ici. Tu vas fondre.
[Olaf Go away, you can not stay here. You'll melt.]
I am not leaving here until
Je ne partirai pas
[I will not leave]
we find some other act of true love to save you.
tant que nous n'aurons pas trouver une autre preuve d'amour pour te sauver.
[As we will not find another proof of love to save you.]
Do you happen to have any ideas?
Est-ce que t'as une idée par hasard?
[Do you have an idea by chance?]
I don't even know what love is.
Je ne sais même pas ce qu'est l'amour.
[I do not even know what love is.]
That's okay, I do.
C'est pas grave. Moi, je sais!
[I do not mind it. I know!]
Love is
L'amour, c'est...
[Love is...]
putting someone else's needs before yours.
faire passer les besoins de l'autre avant les siens.
[to put the needs of others before his own.]
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans and left you forever.
Comme... tu sais comme quand Kristoff t'as ramenée ici auprès de Hans et t'as quittée pour toujours.
[Because... you know like when you got Kristoff brought here by Hans and have left you forever.]
Kristoff loves me?
Kristoff... est amoureux de moi?
[Kristoff... is in love with me?]
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
Waouh, tu ne connais vraiment rien à l'amour, toi, on dirait.
[Wow, you really know anything about love, you, it seems.]
Olaf, you're melting.
Olaf, tu commences à fondre.
[Olaf, you start to melt.]
Some people are worth melting for.
Certaines personnes ont le don de vous faire fondre.
[Some people have the gift to make you melt.]
Just maybe not right this second.
Mais moins vite, ça m'arrangerait.
[But less quickly, it would suit me.]
Don't worry, I've got it.
T'inquiète, je m'en occupe.
[Do not worry, I'm on it.]
We're gonna get through... Oh, wait.
On va trouver une solution. Tu— Attends...
[We will find a solution. You wait...]
Hang on, I'm getting something.
Une minute, je vois quelque chose.
[One minute, I see something.]
It's Kristoff and Sven!
C'est Kristoff et Sven!
[This is Kristoff and Sven!]
They're coming back this way.
Ils reviennent par ici.
[They come back here.]
They... They are?
Quoi? C'est vrai?
[What? It's true?]
Wow! He's really moving fast.
Waouh! Il revient vraiment très vite.
[Whoa! It really comes back very quickly.]
I guess I was wrong.
Je pense que j'avais tort.
[I think I was wrong.]
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
Kristoff ne t'aime pas assez pour faire une croise sur toi.
[Kristoff do not love you enough to make a cross on you.]
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
Viens m'aider. Olaf, s'il te plaît.
[Come help me. Olaf, please.]
No, no, no! You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
Non, non, non, non, non! Tu dois rester près du feu pour te réchauffer.
[No, no, no, no, no! You have to stay near the fire to warm you.]
I need to get to Kristoff.
Je dois aller rejoindre Kristoff.
[I have to go get Kristoff.]
Why?
Pourquoi?
[What for?]
Oh, I know why!
Oh, je sais pourquoi!
[Oh, I know why!]
There's your act of true love right there!
Ta véritable preuve d'amour est juste là!
[Your true proof of love is right there!]
Riding across the fjords like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
En train de chevaucher à travers les fjords tel le roi des rennes qui sent un peu fort.
[By train to ride through the fjords as the king of reindeers that smells a bit strong.]
Come on!
Suis-moi!
[Follow me!]
Look out!
Attention!
[Warning!]
Oh!
Uh... Back this way.
Demi-tour.
[Turn around.]
We're trapped.
Ah! On est piégés.
[Ah! It is trapped.]
Oh...
Whoa!
Slide, Anna!
Glisse, Anna!
[Slips, Anna!]
We made it!
On a réussi!
[We did it!]
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Vas-y, vas-y, vas-y, vas-y, vas-y, vas-y!
[C'mon, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon!]
Come on, buddy, faster.
Allez, mon vieux. Plus vite!
[Come on, man. Faster!]
Kristoff!
Keep going!
Continue sans moi!
[Continue without me!]
Kristoff!
Come on!
Plus vite!
[Faster!]
No.
Non.
[No.]
Whoa!
Woah!
[Woah!]
Whoa!
Woah!
[Woah!]
Sven!
Good boy.
T'es le meilleur.
[You are the best.]
Kristoff.
Kristoff...
Anna!
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Elsa! Vous ne pourrez pas vous échapper.
[Elsa! You can not escape.]
Just take care of my sister.
Promettez-moi de veiller sur ma sœur.
[Promise me to look after my sister.]
Your sister?
Votre sœur?
[Your sister?]
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
Elle est revenue de la montagne,
faible et frigorifiée.
She said that you froze her heart.
Elle a affirmé que vous lui avez gelé le cœur.
[She said that you froze her heart.]
No.
Non.
[No.]
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
J'ai essayé de la sauver, mais il était trop tard.
[I tried to save her, but it was too late.]
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
Sa peau était gelée et ses cheveux tout blancs.
[His skin was frozen and his white hair.]
Your sister is dead.
Votre sœur est morte.
[Your sister is dead.]
Because of you.
Par votre faute.
[By your fault.]
No.
Non.
[No.]
Kristoff.
Anna!
Elsa?
No!
Non!
[No!]
Anna!
Oh. Anna!
No, no!
Non, non!
[No no!]
Please, no.
Pitié, non.
[Please, no.]
Anna?
Oh, Elsa.
You sacrificed yourself for me?
Tu t'es sacrifiée pour me sauver la vie?
[You've sacrificed to save my life?]
I love you.
Parce que je t'aime.
[Because I love you.]
"An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart."
"Une véritable preuve d'amour peut faire fondre un cœur gelé."
[" A real proof of love can melt a frozen heart."]
"Love will thaw."
"L'amour guérit tout."
["Love heals everything."]
Love. Of course.
L'amour, bien sûr!
[Love, of course!]
Elsa?
Love!
L'amour!
[Love!]
I knew you could do it.
Je savais que tu pouvais y arriver.
[I knew you could do it.]
Hands down, this is the best day of my life.
Je suis sûr d'une chose, c'est le plus beau jour de ma vie.
[I am sure of one thing is the happiest day of my life.]
And, quite possibly, the last.
Et certainement le dernier, aussi.
[And certainly the last, too.]
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Oh, Olaf! Accroche-toi, mon ami.
[Oh, Olaf! Hold on, my friend.]
Oh, Oh, Oh!
My own personal flurry!
Ma tempête de neige personnelle!
[My personal snow storm!]
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
But she froze your heart.
Mais, elle avait gelé votre cœur.
[But she froze your heart.]
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
Le seul cœur de glace ici, c'est le vôtre.
[The only heart ice here is yours.]
Wonderful!
C'est merveilleux.
[That's wonderful.]
Setting course, sir.
On lève l'ancre.
[The anchor is lifted.]
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
Je vais renvoyer cette crapule dans son pays.
[I'll send this scoundrel in his country.]
We shall see what his twelve big brothers think of his behavior.
Nous verrons ce que ses douze frères ainés pensent de son comportement.
[We'll see what his twelve older brothers think his behavior.]
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
Arendelle vous remercie, mon seigneur.
[Arendelle thank you, my lord.]
This is unacceptable.
C'est absolument inacceptable.
[This is absolutely unacceptable.]
I am a victim of fear. I've been traumatized.
Je suis une victime. J'ai été traumatisé.
[I am a victim. I was traumatized.]
Ah! My neck hurts.
Ah! J'ai mal au cou.
[Ah! I have a sore neck.]
Is there a doctor that I could see?
Pourrais-je voir un médecin je vous prie?
[Can I see a doctor please?]
And I demand to see the queen!
Et j'exige de voir la reine!
[And I demand to see the Queen!]
Oh. I have a message from the queen.
Oh. J'ai justement un message de la reine.
[Oh. I just happen to a message from the Queen.]
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever
"Arendelle met fin de manière définitive
[" Arendelle ends permanently]
"no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown."
"à ses échanges commerciaux avec le duc de Vicieux Thon."
[" to its trade with the Duke of Vicious Thon."]
"Weselton."
It's Weselton!
C'est Weselton!
[This is Weselton!]
Come on, come on, come on!
Venez, venez, venez!
[Come, come, come!]
Okay, okay, here I come.
Dépêchez-vous, dépêchez-vous. D'accord, je me dépêche.
[Hurry up, hurry up. Okay, I hurry.]
Pole! - Whoops! Sorry.
Pôteau! - Oups! Désolée.
[Post Rocker! - Oops! Sorry.]
Okay, Okay.
Ça y est, ça y est.
[That's it, that's it.]
Here we are. Oh!
On est arrivés. Oh!
[We arrived. Oh!]
I owe you a sled.
Je vous avais promis un traineau.
[I promised you a sledge.]
Are you serious? - Yes!
Vous êtes sérieuse? - Oui!
[Are you serious? - Yes!]
And it's the latest model.
Et c'est le tout dernier modèle.
[And that's the latest model.]
No, I can't accept this.
Non, je ne peux pas accepter.
[No, I can not accept.]
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
Bien sûr que oui. Ce ne sera ni repris ni échangé, ordre de la reine.
[Yes of course. This will not be returned or exchanged order of the Queen.]
She's named you the Official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
Elle vient d'ailleurs de vous nommer livreur de glaçons officiel d'Arendelle.
[She has also just you name deliveryman Official Arendelle of ice.]
What? That's not a thing. - Oh, sure it is.
Quoi? Ça n'existe pas. - Bien sûr que ça existe.
[What? It does not exist. - Of course it exists.]
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
Et, il y a même un porte-gobelet. Il vous plaît?
[And there is even a cup holder. Please?]
Like it? I love it!
S'il me plaît? Je l'adore!
[Please me? I love it!]
Whoa.
Woah.
[Woah.]
I could kiss you!
Je pourrais vous embrasser.
[I could kiss you.]
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd...
Enfin, je veux dire, j'en ai envie.
[Well, I mean, I feel like it.]
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
Mais... je peux? Nouvons-pous? Je veux dire, pouvons-nous?
[But I can? Nouvons - lice? I mean, can we?]
Wait, what?
Qu'est-ce que je dis?
[What do I say?]
We may.
Avec plaisir.
[With pleasure.]
Summer!
C'est l'été!
[It's summer!]
Ooh...
Ah! Ooh...
[Ah! Ooh...]
Hello.
Salut.
[Hi.]
Are you ready?
Vous êtes prêts?
[Are you ready?]
Ice!
Swing me.
Ooh...
I like the open gates.
C'est si bon d'ouvrir le château.
[It's so good to open the castle.]
We are never closing them again.
Nous ne refermerons plus jamais ces portes.
[We never refermerons these doors.]
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful, but you know I don't skate.
Oh, Elsa. Ils sont magnifiques. Mais je ne sais pas patiner.
[Oh, Elsa. They are beautiful. But I do not know skate.]
Come on! You can do it!
Lance-toi, tu vas y arriver.
[Throw yourself, you can do it.]
Look out. Reindeer coming through.
Attention. Renne droit devant.
[Warning. Reindeer ahead.]
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
J'y arrive. J'y arrive. Non! J'y arrive pas. J'y arrive pas.
[I arrive there. I arrive there. No! I can not. I can not.]
Hey, guys!
Coucou les filles!
[Hello girls!]
That's it, Olaf.
Vas-y Olaf, pousse-la.
[Olaf Go ahead, shoot it.]
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.
Glisse et pivote. Glisse et pivote.
[Slides and swings. Slides and swings.]