English subtitles
Sottotitoli by Resh
Translation or [Google Translate output]
Born of cold and winter air
Quando il vento avvolge i monti
When the wind wraps around the mountains
And mountain rain combining
Con il suo gelido abbraccio,
with its cold embrace,
This icy force both foul and fair
L'unione forma un cuore freddo
The combination forms a cold heart
Has a frozen heart worth mining
Dal quale nasce il ghiaccio.
From which comes the ice.
So cut through the heart
Spaccato in due
Split in two,
Cold and clear
Mostrerà
(it will) show
Strike for love and strike for fear
Quello che l'uomo ancora non sa.
what man does not yet know.
See the beauty sharp and sheer
Spezza il cuore a metà
Breaks the heart in half
Split the ice apart
E ognuno saprà
And everyone will know...
And break the frozen heart
Qual è la verità.
... what is the truth.
Watch your step! Let it go!
Vieni qui, tira su!
Come here, pull up!
Hup, ho
Ehi, tu
Hey, you
Watch your step! Let it go!
Vieni qui, tira su!
Come here, pull up!
Beautiful! Powerful!
Lucido! Splendido!
Shiny! Beautiful!
Dangerous! Cold!
Solido! Duro!
Solid! Hard!
Ice has a magic can't be controlled
Fai attenzione al suo lato oscuro.
Pay attention to its dark side.
Stronger than one
Vince con te,
(It) wins with you,
Stronger than ten
Vince con noi,
(It) wins with us,
Stronger than a hundred men!
Vince con duemila eroi!
(It) wins with two thousand heroes!
Oh!
Born of cold and winter air
Quando il vento avvolge i monti
When the wind wraps around the mountains
And mountain rain combining
Col suo gelido abbraccio,
With its cold embrace,
This icy force both foul and fair
L'unione forma un cuore freddo
The combination forms a cold heart
Has a frozen heart worth mining
Dal quale nasce il ghiaccio.
From which comes the ice.
Cut through the heart
Spezzalo in due
Split in two,
Cold and clear
Mostrerà
(it will) show
Strike for love and strike for fear
Quello che l'uomo ancora non sa.
what man does not yet know.
There's beauty and there's danger here
Dividi il cuore a metà
Divide the heart in half,
Split the ice apart
E ognuno saprà
and everyone will know
Beware the frozen heart
Che forza enorme ha.
what huge strength it has.
Come on, Sven.
Andiamo, Sven.
[Come on, Sven.]
Elsa. Psst!
Elsa!
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
Sveglia, sveglia, svegliati!
[Wake up, wake up, wake up!]
Anna, go back to sleep.
Anna, torna a dormire.
[Anna, go back to sleep.]
I just can't.
Non ce la faccio.
[I can not do it.]
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
ll cielo è sveglio, perciò sono sveglia.
[The sky is awake, so I'm awake.]
So, we have to play.
Perciò giochiamo.
[So we play.]
Go play by yourself.
Gioca da sola.
[Play alone.]
Do you want to build a snowman?
Vuoi fare un pupazzo di neve?
[Want to make a snowman?]
Come on, come on, come on!
Andiamo, andiamo!
[Come on, come on!]
Do the magic! Do the magic!
Fai la magia!
[Make magic!]
Oh...
Ready? - Uh-huh.
Pronta?
[Ready?]
This is amazing!
E stupenda!
[Is beautiful!]
Watch this!
Guarda questo!
[Watch this!]
Hi, I'm Olaf, and I like warm hugs.
Ciao, io sono Olaf, e amo i caldi abbracci.
[Hello, I'm Olaf, and I love the warm hugs.]
I love you, Olaf!
Ti adoro, Olaf!
[I adore you, Olaf!]
Olaf...
Tickle bumps!
Che brividi!
[That chills!]
Oh!
Hang on!
Tieniti!
[Keep!]
Catch me!
Prendimi!
[Take me!]
Gotcha!
Presa!
[Grip!]
Again!
Ancora!
[Yet!]
Wait!
Aspetta!
[Wait!]
Slow down!
Rallenta!
[Slow down!]
Whoo!
Anna!
Mama! Papa!
Madre, padre!
[Mother, father!]
No, no...
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
Va tutto bene, Anna, ci penso io.
[It's all right, Anna, I got it.]
Elsa, what have you done?
Elsa, che cosa hai fatto?
[Elsa, what did you do?]
This is getting out of hand.
Non lo domini più.
[Not more domains.]
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
È stato un incidente. Perdonami, Anna!
[It was an accident. Forgive me, Anna!]
Oh. She's ice cold.
È fredda come il ghiaccio.
[It's cold as ice.]
I know where we have to go.
So dove portarla.
[I know where to take her.]
Ice?
Ghiaccio?
[Ice?]
Faster, Sven.
Più veloce, Sven.
[Faster, Sven.]
Sven!
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
Per favore! Aiuto! È mia figlia.
[Please! Help! It's my daughter.]
It's the king.
È il re.
[It is the king.]
Trolls?
Troll?
[Troll?]
Shush! I'm trying to listen.
Sto cercando di sentire!
[I'm trying to hear!]
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Che carini, vi terrò con me.
[How nice, I will keep with me.]
Your Majesty.
Maestà.
[Majesty.]
Born with the powers, or cursed?
È nata con i poteri, o è un maleficio?
[It was born with the powers, or is it a curse?]
Born. And they're getting stronger.
Ci è nata, si intensificano.
[There arose, they intensified.]
Here, here.
Qui, qui.
[Here, here.]
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
Siete fortunati che non si ha il cuore.
[You are lucky that you have no heart.]
The heart is not so easily changed.
Il cuore non è facile da cambiare.
[The heart is not easy to change.]
But the head can be persuaded.
Ma con la testa si può provare.
[But with the head you can try.]
Do what you must.
Fate ciò che dovete.
[Do what you must.]
I recommend we remove all magic.
Consiglio di togliere tutta la magia.
[Council to remove all the magic.]
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
Perfino i ricordi della magia, per sicurezza.
[Even the memories of magic, for safety.]
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
Ma non temete. Lascerò il divertimento.
[But fear not. I'll leave the fun.]
She will be okay.
Se la caverà.
[He'll do.]
But she won't remember I have powers?
Ma non ricorderà che io ho i poteri?
[But it does not remember that I have powers?]
It's for the best.
È per il suo bene.
[It's for his own good.]
Listen to me, Elsa. Your power will only grow.
Ascoltami, Elsa. Il tuo potere crescerà.
[Listen, Elsa. Your power will grow.]
There is beauty in it...
C'è bellezza in esso...
[There is beauty in it...]
But also great danger.
Ma anche un grande pericolo.
[But also a great danger.]
You must learn to control it.
Devi imparare a controllarlo.
[You must learn to control it.]
Fear will be your enemy.
La paura sarà tua nemica.
[Fear is your enemy.]
No!
We'll protect her.
La proteggeremo.
[We will protect it.]
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
Imparerà a controllarlo. È certo.
[Learn to control it. It is certain.]
Until then...
Fino ad allora...
[Until then...]
We'll lock the gates.
Chiuderemo le porte.
[We will close the doors.]
We'll reduce the staff.
Ridurremo i domestici.
[We will reduce the household.]
We will limit her contact with people,
Limiteremo i contatti con le persone.
[We limit contacts with people.]
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
E terremo segreti i suoi poteri a tutti.
[And we keep secret his powers at all.]
Including Anna.
Compresa Anna.
[Including Anna.]
Elsa?
Translation from
http://youtu.be/06d4VI2v22o
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Sei già in piedi oppure dormi?
Are you awake or are you sleeping?
Come on, let's go and play
Giochiamo insieme, dai!
Let's play together, come on!
I never see you any more
Da quando non ti vedo più
Since, when I do not see you,
Come out the door
Mi sento giù
I feel sad
It's like you've gone away
Mi manchi molto, sai?
I miss you so much, do you know?
We used to be best buddies, and now we're not
Noi siamo tanto amiche! O forse no
We are such good friends! Or maybe not
I wish you would tell me why
Che cosa ti ho fatto mai?
What did I ever do to you?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Se tu vuoi spiegarmi come
If you want to explain to me how,
It doesn't have to be a snowman
Faremo un bel pupazzo insieme.
we will make a snowman together.
Go away, Anna.
Vattene via, Anna!
Go away, Anna!
Okay, bye
Okay, ciao.
Okay, bye.
The gloves will help.
I guanti aiuteranno.
[The gloves will help.]
See? Conceal it.
Visto? Celarlo.
[See? Conceal it.]
Don't feel it.
Domarlo.
[Quell it.]
Don't let it show.
Non mostrarlo.
[Do not show.]
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Sei già sveglia o oppure dormi?
Are you awake or are you sleeping?
Or ride our bike around the halls?
Vuoi fare un giro insieme a me?
Do you want to ride with me?
I think some company is overdue
Mi annoio troppo, non ne posso più!
I am getting bored, I can't stand it any more!
I've started talking to the pictures on the walls
Parlare ai quadri non diverte poi granché
Talking to the pictures isn't much fun!
Hang in there, Joan.
Ferma, Giovanna!
Stay there, Joan!
It gets a little lonely, all these empty rooms
Giochiamo con la neve, o con quel che vuoi,
Let's play with the snow, or whatever you want,,
Just watching the hours tick by
Ma esci, ti prego, dai!
But come out, please, come on!
I'm scared.
Ho paura.
[I'm scared.]
It's getting stronger!
Sta diventando più potente!
[It is becoming more powerful!]
Getting upset only makes it worse. Calm down.
Disperarsi peggiorerà solo le cose. Calma.
[Despair will only worsen things. Calm.]
No! Don't touch me!
No, non toccatemi!
[No, do not touch me!]
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
Non voglio farvi del male.
[I do not want to hurt you.]
See you in two weeks!
Ci vediamo fra due settimane!
[See you in two weeks!]
Do you have to go?
Dovete proprio andare?
[Must you go?]
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Andrà tutto per il meglio, Elsa.
[It will be all for the best, Elsa.]
Your Highness.
Elsa?
Please, I know you're in there
Puoi lasciarmi entrare?
Can you let me in?
People are asking where you've been
Prima eri sempre accanto a me.
Before, you were always by my side.
They say "Have courage", and I'm trying to
Vorrei capire perché proprio tu
I would like to understand why you...
I'm right out here for you
Non vuoi avermi più
... don't you want to have me...
Just let me in
insieme a te
... with you.
We only have each other; it's just you and me
Ed ora che faremo? Siamo sole, ormai.
And now what are we going to do? We are alone now.
What are we gonna do?
Quale conforto avrò?
What consolation am I going to have?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Ora tu mi manchi troppo!
I miss you too much now!
All ashore!
Tutti a terra!
[Everybody to the ground!]
Welcome to Arendelle!
Benvenuti ad Arendelle!
[Welcome to Arendelle!]
Ahh, merci, monsieur.
Watch your step, please.
Attenzione, per favore.
[Take care, please.]
The gates will be opening soon.
Le porte si apriranno presto.
[The doors will open soon.]
Why do I have to wear this?
Perché devo vestirmi così?
[Why do I dress like this?]
Because the queen has come of age.
La regina ha raggiunto la maggiore età.
[The queen has come of age.]
It's Coronation Day!
C'è l'incoronazione!
[There's coronation!]
That's not my fault.
Non è colpa mia.
[It's not my fault.]
What do you want, Sven?
Che cosa vuoi Sven?
[What do you want Sven?]
"Give me a snack."
"Uno spuntino!"
["Snack!"]
What's the magic word?
Qual è la parola magica?
[What's the magic word?]
"Please."
"Per favore!"
["Please!"]
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
Dividiamo.
[We divide.]
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
È incredibile, aprono le porte!
[It's amazing, open the door!]
And for a whole day! Faster, Percy!
E per un giorno intero! Presto, Percy!
[And for a whole day! Soon, Percy!]
Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
Arendelle, il nostro alleato commerciale più misterioso!
[Arendelle, our commercial ally more mysterious!]
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets and exploit your riches.
Apre le porte e svela sil segreto delle sue ricchezze.
[It opens its doors and reveals sil secret of his riches.]
Did I say that out loud?
L'ho detto ad alta voce?
[I said it out loud?]
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait to see the queen and the princess.
I miei occhi non vedono l'ora d'ammirare la regina e la principessa.
[My eyes can not wait to admire the queen and the princess.]
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
Scommetto che sono molto carine.
[I bet they are very pretty.]
I bet they are beautiful.
Io scommetto che sono bellissime.
[I bet you are beautiful.]
Princess Anna?
Principessa Anna?
[Princess Anna?]
Huh? Yeah?
Sì?
[Yes?]
Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
Perdonate se vi ho svegliata, Altezza.
[Forgive me if I woke you up, Highness.]
No, no, no, you didn't.
No, no per niente.
[No, no not at all.]
I've been up for hours.
Sono sveglia da ore.
[I'm awake, for hours.]
Who is it?
Chi è?
[Who is it?]
Still me, ma'am.
Sono sempre io, Altezza.
[Still me, Highness.]
The gates will open soon. Time to get ready.
Presto le porte saranno aperte. Dovete prepararvi.
[Soon the doors will be open. You must get ready.]
Of course.
Ma certo.
[Of course.]
Ready for what?
Prepararmi per cosa?
[Get ready for what?]
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
L'incoronazione di vostra sorella, Altezza.
[The coronation of your sister, Highness.]
My sister's corneration.
"La cronazione" di mia sorella.
[The "cronazione" of my sister.]
It's Coronation Day!
Il giorno dell'incoronazione!
[The day of the coronation!]
It's Coronation Day!
Il giorno dell'incoronazione!
[The day of the coronation!]
The window is open!
La luce che irrompe
Light is bursting in
So's that door!
Fin quassù!
Up to here!
I didn't know they did that any more
Credevo che non accadesse più!
I thought it wouldn't happen again!
Who knew we owned 8,000 salad plates?
Non ho mai visto tanti piatti, qua!
I've never seen so many dishes, here!
For years I've roamed these empty halls
Ormai, da tempo immemore
It's been time immemorial
Why have a ballroom with no balls?
Qui non si vede un ospite!
since we've had a guest here!
Finally, they're opening up the gates!
Oggi quel cancello si aprirà.
Today that gate is going to open.
There'll be actual, real, live people
Quanta gente incontreremo,
Many people we're going to meet,
It'll be totally strange
in quell’enorme via vai.
in that huge bustle.
But wow! Am I so ready for this change!
Mi sento emozionata più che mai!
I feel excited like never before!
'Cause for the first time in forever
Questa è la vita che volevo
This is the life I wanted
There'll be music, there'll be light
Niente mura da guardare.
No walls to stare at.
For the first time in forever
Avrò quello che sognavo
I'm going to have what I dreamed
I'll be dancing through the night
Oggi io potrò ballare.
Today I will dance.
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
Non posso sopportare l’attesa
I can't stand to wait
But I'm somewhere in that zone
Penso che forse impazzirò
I think I might go crazy
'Cause for the first time in forever
Però stasera, di sicuro,
But tonight, for sure,
I won't be alone
Mi divertirò.
I'm going to have fun.
I can't wait to meet everyone!
Incontrerò tutti, non vedo l'ora!
I'm going to meet everyone, I can't wait for it!
What if I meet The One?
E se incontrassi... Quello Giusto?
What if I met... The One?
Tonight, imagine me gown and all
Avrò uno splendido abito
I'll be wearing a beautiful dress
Fetchingly draped against the wall
Semplice ma bellissimo,
Simple, but wonderful,
The picture of sophisticated grace
Ammireranno tutti quanti me!
Everybody will admire me!
I suddenly see him standing there
E poi, d'improvviso, lui è lì
Then suddenly there he is
A beautiful stranger, tall and fair
Nessuno è più bello di così
Nobody is more handsome than him
I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face!
Ed è meglio se mi butto sul buffet
Better if I plunge into the buffet
But then we laugh and talk all evening
Staremo insieme fino all'alba,
We'll stay together until dawn,
Which is totally bizarre
Lui si innamorerà
He will fall in love
Nothing like the life I've led so far
Solo che ancora non lo sa!
Only he doesn't know it yet!
For the first time in forever
Oggi, per la prima volta,
Today, for the first time,
There'll be magic, there'll be fun
Proprio come per magia,
Just as by magic,
For the first time in forever
Ho La vita che sognavo,
I have the life I dreamed of
I could be noticed by someone
Per una notte, in mano mia.
In my hands for one night
And I know it is totally crazy
È un'idea del tutto pazzesca,
It's an absolutely crazy idea
To dream I'd find romance
E sembra folle, ma...
And it sounds insane, but...
But for the first time in forever
Credo di avere per davvero
I think I really have...
At least I've got a chance!
Un'opportunità.
... a chance.
Don't let them in
Non dire mai
Never tell...
Don't let them see
La verità.
... the truth.
Be the good girl you always have to be
Se sei brava, nessuno lo saprà.
If you're a good girl, nobody will know.
Conceal, don't feel
Celare, domare
Conceal, quell
Put on a show
Perché io so
Because I know...
Make one wrong move and everyone will know
Che è un segreto e lo proteggerò.
... it's a secret and I'll protect it.
But it's only for today
Proprio oggi, tuttavia
Just today, though,
It's only for today
Quest'oggi, tuttavia,
Today, however,
It's agony to wait
L'attesa è un'agonia.
Waiting is agony.
It's agony to wait
L'attesa è un'agonia!
Waiting is agony!
Tell the guards to open up
Ma ormai lo show avrà
But now the show will
The gate
Il via!
Start!
The gate
Il via!
Start!
For the first time in forever
Oggi per la prima volta
Today, for the first time
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Non dire mai la verità.
Never tell the truth.
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of
La vita, forse, cambierà.
Life might change
Be the good girl you always have to be
Se sei brava, nessuno lo saprà.
If you're a good girl, nobody will know.
A chance to change my lonely world
Finora ero sola, ma...
Till now I've been alone, but...
Conceal
Celare
A chance to find true love
Da oggi, chi lo sa.
... from now on, who knows.
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Dovrai soffrire, ancora un po'.
You'll have to suffer a little
I know it all ends tomorrow
È un giorno da ricordare,
It's a day to be remembered,
So it has to be today!
Sono certa che lo sia!
I'm pretty sure it is!
'Cause for the first time in forever
E so che per la prima volta
And I know that for the first time
For the first time in forever
Quella vita che, sognavo
The life I dreamed of
Nothing's in my way!
Oggi sembra mia!
Today seems to be mine!
Hey!
(Thanks to FlamSparks for the preceding!)
(http://youtu.be/pPOkn995UCs)
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Sono desolato, ti sei fatta male?
[I'm sorry, did you hurt yourself?]
Hey.
Ciao.
[Hello.]
Uh... No, no, I'm okay.
No, tutto bene.
[No, all right.]
Are you sure?
Sicura?
[You sure?]
Yeah. I just wasn't looking where I was going.
Sì, ero sovrappensiero.
[Yes, I was lost in thought.]
But I'm great, actually.
Ma sto bene, davvero.
[But I'm fine, really.]
Oh... Thank goodness.
Grazie al cielo.
[Thank Heaven.]
Oh! Uh...
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Principe Hans delle Isole del Sud.
[Prince Hans of Southern Islands.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Principessa Anna di Arendelle.
[Princess Anne of Arendelle.]
"Princess"? My Lady.
"Principessa"? Milady.
["Princess"? Milady.]
Oh!
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Um... Whew.
Hi. Again.
Ciao. Di nuovo.
[Hello. Again.]
Oh, boy!
Oh, perbacco!
[Oh my!]
This is awkward.
Imbarazzante.
[Embarrassing.]
Not "You're awkward", but just because we're...
No, non tu, ma solo perché siamo...
[No, not you, but only because we...]
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous. Wait, what?
Io sono imbarazzante, tu sei bellissimo. Aspetta, che?
[I'm awkward, you're beautiful. Wait, what?]
I'd like to formally apologize
Mi scuso per aver urtato
[I apologize for hitting]
for hitting the princess of Arendelle with my horse.
la principessa di Arendelle.
[the princess of Arendelle.]
And for every moment after.
E per tutto il resto.
[And for everything else.]
No! No, no. It's fine.
No, fa niente.
[No, that's okay.]
I'm not that princess.
Io non sono così.
[I'm not so.]
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
Se avessi urtato mia sorella Elsa,
[If I hit my sister Elsa,]
it would be... Yeesh!
sarebbe stato un...
[It would be a...]
Because, you know...
Perché, sai...
[Because, you know...]
Hello.
Ciao.
[Hello.]
But, lucky you,
Ma per tua fortuna...
[But lucky for you...]
It's just me.
sono solo io.
[I'm just me.]
"Just" you?
"Solo" tu?
["Only you?]
The bells. The coronation.
Le campane, l'incoronazione.
[The bells, the coronation.]
I better go.
Meglio che vada.
[I better go.]
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Devo andare. Meglio che vada.
[I have to go. I better go.]
Bye!
Addio.
[Goodbye.]
Oh, no. Oh!
Your Majesty, the gloves.
Vostra Maestà, i guanti.
[Your Majesty, the gloves.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
Elsa, Regina di Arendelle.
[Elsa, Queen of Arendelle.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
Elsa, Regina di Arendelle!
[Elsa, Queen of Arendelle!]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
La regina di Arendelle, Elsa.
[The queen of Arendelle, Elsa.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
La principessa di Arendelle, Anna.
[The princess of Arendelle, Anna.]
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Qui? Sicuro?
[Here? Safe?]
Because I don't think I'm supposed to...
Perché non credo che io debba...
[Because I do not think I should...]
Oh. Okay.
D'accordo.
[All right.]
Hi.
Salve.
[Hi.]
"Hi" me? Oh...
"Salve a me? Oh...
["Hello me? Oh...]
Um... Hi.
Um.... Salve.
[Um.... Hello.]
You look beautiful.
Sei molto bella.
[You're very beautiful.]
Thank you. You look beautiful-ler.
Grazie. Tu sei spaventosamente bella.
[Thank you. You are frighteningly beautiful.]
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
Non "spaventosa"...
[Not "scary"...]
But more beautiful.
Solo più bella.
[Only prettier.]
Thank you.
Grazie.
[Thank you.]
So...
Allora...
[Then...]
This is what a party looks like.
Le feste sono così...
[Party as well...]
It's warmer than I thought.
È più caldo di quanto pensassi.
[It's hotter than I thought.]
What is that amazing smell?
Cos'è questo profumo delizioso?
[What is this delicious smell?]
Chocolate.
Cioccolato!
[Chocolate!]
Your Majesty.
Vostra Maestà.
[Your Majesty.]
The Duke of Weaseltown.
Il duca di Wafertown.
[The Duke of Wafertown.]
"Weselton"! Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
"Weselton"! Il duca di Weselton, Vostra Maestà!
["Weselton"! The Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty!]
As your closest partner in trade it seems only fitting
Come vostro major alleato commerciale...
[As your major ally commercial...]
that I offer you your first dance as queen.
è doveroso invitarvi al primo ballo da regina.
[it is right to invite you to the first dance queen.]
One-two, and jump.
Uno, due, saltello.
[One, two, hop.]
Uh...
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
Grazie, più troppo non ballo.
[Thank you, most do not dance too.]
Oh...
But my sister does.
Ma mia sorella sì!
[But my sister, yes!]
What? - Oh! Lucky you.
Allora? - Che fortunata!
[So what? - How lucky!]
Oh, I don't think...
Non credo...
[I do not believe...]
If you swoon, let me know. I'll catch you.
Se svenire, ditelo. Vi prenderò.
[If you pass out, say so. I will take you.]
Sorry.
Scusa.
[Sorry.]
Like an agile peacock.
Come un agile pavone.
[As a nimble peacock.]
Ow! Ow.
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
A proposito... È splendido che abbia aperto le porte.
[By the way... It's wonderful to have opened the doors.]
Why did they shut them in the first place?
Perché sono state tanto chiuse?
[Why he was so closed?]
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
Ne conoscete la ragione?
[Do you know the reason?]
No.
All right. Hang on!
D'accordo. Tenetevi.
[All right. Stay.]
They don't call me the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
Non per niente mi chiamano Il Re del Caschè!
[No wonder they call me King of Caschè!]
Oh-ho!
Like a chicken with the face of a monkey, I fly.
Come un pollo dalla faccia da scimmia, volo!
[Like a chicken-faced monkey, fly!]
Let me know when you're ready
Ditemi quando siete pronta
[Tell me when you're ready]
for another round, Milady.
per un altro giro, Milady.
[for another round, Milady.]
Well, he was sprightly.
Beh, molto agile.
[Well, very agile.]
Especially for a man in heels.
Specie per un uomo con i tacchi alti.
[Especially for a man with high heels.]
Are you okay?
I've never been better. This is so nice.
Mai stata meglio. È così bello.
[Never better. It's so beautiful.]
I wish it could be like this all the time.
Mi piacerebbe che fosse così sempre.
[I wish it were always so.]
Me, too.
Anch'io.
[Me too.]
But it can't.
Ma non si può.
[But you can not.]
Why not? - It just can't.
Perché no? - Non si può.
[Why not? - You can not.]
Excuse me for a minute.
Scusa ???.
[Excuse me ???.]
I'd be honored.
Glad I caught you.
Ti ho presa, grazie cielo.
[I've got you, thank heaven.]
Hans.
I often had a whole parlor to myself to slide!
Una volta avevo un salone per scivolare!
[Once I had a room to slip!]
Oops!
Sorry.
Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
Il tuo fisico aiuta, credo.
[Your physical help, I think.]
Ah.
What's this?
Che cos'è?
[What is it?]
Uh, I was born with it.
Ci sono nata.
[I was born there.]
Although, I dreamed I was kissed by a troll.
Ma in sogno mi ha baciata un troll.
[But in the dream he kissed a troll.]
I like it.
Mi piace.
[I like it.]
Yeah, the whole thing.
Si, in un sol boccone.
[Yes, in one gulp.]
You got it.
Ce l'hai fatta.
[You did.]
Okay, wait, wait. So, you have how many brothers?
Bravo, scusa ???. E quanti sono fratelli?
[Bravo, excuse me ???. And how many brothers?]
Twelve older brothers.
Dodici grandi di me
[Twelve older than me]
Three of them pretended I was invisible, literally, for two years.
Tre di loro hanno finto che io fossi invisibile, letteralmente, per due anni.
[Three of them pretended I was invisible, literally, for two years.]
That's horrible.
È orribile.
[It's horrible.]
It's what brothers do.
Il fratelli lo fanno così.
[The brothers do so.]
And sisters.
Anche le sorelle.
[Even the sisters.]
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
Elsa e io eravamo unite da piccole.
[Elsa and I were joined when we were small.]
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
Un giorno, mi ha esclusa dalla sua vita...
[One day, I was excluded from her life...]
and I never knew why.
e ancora non so il perché.
[and still I do not know why.]
I would never shut you out.
Io non ti escluderei mai.
[I do not exclude you ever.]
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
Ecco, vorrei... Posso dire una follia?
Well, I'd wish... Can I say a crazy thing?
I love crazy.
Amo le follie.
I love crazy things.
All my life has been a series of doors in my face
Ho sperato molte volte in qualcosa per me
So many times did I hope in something for me
And then suddenly I bump into you
Come un fulmine sei comparso tu.
Then you appeared like lightning.
I was thinking the same thing, because, like...
È la stessa cosa che penso io, perché...
I think the same, because...
I've been searching my whole life to find my own place
Non avevo mai trovato un posto, finché,
I had never found a place, until,
And maybe it's the party talking, or the chocolate fondue
All’improvviso una speranza o qualcosa di più.
Suddenly a hope, or something more.
But with you
Ma se noi...
But if we...
But with you I found my place
Ma se noi stiamo insieme
But if we are together
I see your face
Mi sento bene.
I feel good.
And it's nothing like I've ever known before
Ed è facile, adesso che io so
And it's easy, now that I'm aware...
Love is an open door!
Che occasione ho!
of the chance I've got!
Love is an open door!
Che occasione ho!
of the chance I've got!
Love is an open door
Che occasione ho
of the chance I've got!
With you
Con te
with you
Love is an open door
Che occasione ho
of the chance I've got!
I mean, it's crazy
Non trovi strano...
Don't you think it's odd...
What?
Cosa?
We finish each other's
Sentirsi davvero...
Feeling so...
Sandwiches
Simili!
alike!
That's what I was gonna say!
Stavo per dirlo io!
I was going to say that!
I've never met someone
È bello accorgersi
It's wonderful to realize
Who thinks so much like me
Che sono uguale a te.
That I'm just like you.
Jinx! Jinx again!
Flic! Flic di nuovo!
Flic! Flic again!
Our mental synchronization
Abbiamo fatto un duetto
We're a duet
Can have but one explanation
che sembra proprio perfetto.
that seems just perfect.
You and I were just meant to be
Tu ormai lo sai più di me
And you know it better than me
Say goodbye
Dì addio
say goodbye
To the pain of the past
Alla malinconia.
To sadness
We don't have to feel it anymore
Tutto cambia, ora che io so
Everything is different now that I'm aware...
Love is an open door
Che occasione ho
of the chance I've got!
Love is an open door!
Che occasione ho
of the chance I've got!
Life can be so much more
E non ti lascerò
And I won't leave you
With you
Mai più - Perché - Lo so - Che tu
Forever - Because - I know - That you
Love is an open
Sei tutto ciò che
Are everything
Door
Ho.
I've got.
Can I say something crazy?
Posso dire una follia?
Can I say a crazy thing?
Will you marry me?
Vuoi sposarmi?
Can I say something even crazier?
Posso dire una follia ancora più folle?
Can I say an even crazier crazy thing?
Yes!
Sì!
Coming through. Excuse me. Oh...
Pardon. Sorry. Oh!
Scusate, permesso.
[Sorry, permission.]
Can we just get around you there?
Possiamo girarvi intorno?
[We can turn away around?]
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Grazie. Eccola lì.
[Thank you. There it is.]
Elsa!
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
Voglio dire, Regina. Sono sempre io.
[I mean, Regina. It's always me.]
May I present Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Vi presento il principe Hans delle Isole del Sud.
[Meet Prince Hans Island South.]
Your Majesty.
Maestà.
[Majesty.]
We would like...
Vorremmo...
[We would like...]
Uh, your blessing...
La vostra benedizione...
[Your blessing...]
Of our marriage.
Al nostro matrimonio!
[At our wedding!]
Marriage? - Yes!
Che? Matrimonio? - Sì!
[What? Marriage? - Yes!]
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Perdona, sono confusa.
[Forgive, I'm confused.]
Well, we haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
Dobbiamo ancora decidere i dettagli.
[We still have to decide the details.]
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
Ma pianificheremo tutto.
[But we will plan everything.]
Of course, we'll have soup, roast, and ice cream. And then...
Ci saranno zuppa, arrosto, e gelato.
[There will be soup, roast, and ice cream.]
Wait. Would we live here?
Aspetta. Vivremo qui?
[Wait. We will live here?]
Here? - Absolutely!
Qui? Assolutamente sì!
[Here? Yes absolutely!]
Anna!
Oh! We can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us.
Invitiamo i tuoi dodici fratelli a stare qui.
[We invite your twelve brothers stay here.]
What? No, no, no.
Of course we have the room......
ll posto c'è!
[The place is!]
Wait, slow down. No one's brothers are staying here.
Calma. Una momento. Nessun fratello starà qui.
[Calm. A moment. No brother will stay here.]
No one is getting married.
Nessuno matrimonio.
[No marriage.]
Wait, what?
Aspetta, che?
[Wait, what?]
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
Posso parlarti, per favore? In privato.
[Can I talk to you, please? In private.]
No. Whatever you have to say, you can say to both of us.
No. Puoi parlare a tutti e due.
[No. You can talk to both.]
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
Bene. Non sposi un uomo che conosci appena.
[All right. Do not marry a man you barely know.]
You can if it's true love.
Sì, se è vero amore.
[Yes, it is true love.]
Anna, what do you know about true love?
Anna, cosa sai del vero amore?
[Anna, what do you know about true love?]
More than you.
Molto più di te.
[Much more than you.]
All you know is how to shut people out.
Tu escludi solo la gente dalla tua vita.
[You may only exclude people from your life.]
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
Chiedete la mia benedizione. La mia risposta è no.
[Ask my blessing. My answer is no.]
Now, excuse me.
Con permesso.
[With permission.]
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
Maestà, se permettete.
[Majesty, if you will.]
No, you may not. And I think you should go.
No, e penso che tu debba andare.
[No, and I think you should go.]
The party is over. Close the gates.
La festa è finita. Chiudete le porte.
[The party is over. Close the doors.]
Yes, Your Majesty.
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
Elsa, no, no! Aspetta.
[Elsa, no, no! Wait.]
Give me my glove!
Elsa, please, please.
Ridammi il guanto!
[Give me the glove!]
I can't live like this anymore!
Elsa, ti prego. Ti prego non posso più vivere così io!
[Elsa, please. I pray I can live like me!]
Then leave.
Allora vattene.
[Then go.]
What did I ever do to you?
Che cosa ti ho fatto?
[What have I done?]
Enough, Anna.
Basta, Anna.
[Just, Anna.]
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
No perché? Perché mi escludi?
[No, why? Why do you exclude?]
Why do you shut the world out?
Perché escludi il mondo?
[Why exclude the world?]
What are you so afraid of?
Di cosa hai tanta paura?
[What are you so afraid?]
I said, enough!
Ho detto, basta!
[I said, enough!]
Sorcery.
Stregoneria.
[Witchcraft.]
I knew there was something dubious going on here.
Sapevo che c'era sotto qualcosa di losco.
[I knew something was fishy.]
Elsa.
There she is!
Eccola!
[Here it is!]
Yes! It is her!
Sì! È lei!
[Yes! And she!]
Queen Elsa.
Regina Elsa.
[Queen Elsa.]
Our beautiful queen!
La nostra bella regina!
[Our beautiful queen!]
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
Vostra Maestà, state proprio bene?
[Your Majesty, you are just fine?]
No.
There she is! Stop her!
Eccola! Fermatela!
[Here it is! Stop it!]
Please, just stay away from me. Stay away.
Vi prego, state lontani da me. State lontani.
[Please, stay away from me. Stay away.]
Monster. Monster!
Mostro. Mostro!
[Monster. Monster!]
Elsa!
Wait, please!
Aspetta. Ti prego!
[Wait. Please!]
Elsa, stop!
Elsa, fermati!
[Elsa, stop!]
Anna!
No.
The fjord.
Il fiordo.
[The fjord.]
Snow! Snow?
Neve! Neve?
[Snow! Snow?]
Yes, snow.
Si, neve.
[Yes, snow.]
Are you all right? - No.
Stai bene? - No.
[Are you OK? - No.]
Did you know?
Lo sapevi?
[Did you know?]
No.
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
Guardate, nevica, nevica!
[Look, it's snowing, it's snowing!]
The queen has cursed this land!
La regina ha maledetto questa terra!
[The queen has cursed this land!]
She must be stopped! You have to go after her.
Deve essere fermata! Inseguitela!
[It must be stopped! Chase her!]
Wait, no!
Aspettate, no!
[Wait, no!]
You! ls there sorcery in you, too?
Tu! Sei una strega anche tu?
[You! You're a witch, too?]
Are you a monster, too?
Sei anche tu un mostro?
[Are you a monster?]
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
No, no, sono una persona comune.
[No, no, I'm an ordinary person.]
That's right, she is.
Si, comune è vero.
[Yes, it's true common.]
In the best way.
In senso buono.
[In a good way.]
And my sister is not a monster.
E mia sorella non è un mostro.
[And my sister is not a monster.]
She nearly killed me!
Stava per uccidermi.
[He was going to kill me.]
You slipped on ice. - Her ice.
Siete scivolato ghiaccio. - Sul suo ghiaccio.
[You slipped ice. - On his ice.]
It was an accident. She was scared.
È stato un incidente. Si è spaventata.
[It was an accident. It is scared.]
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this.
Non voleva farlo. Non voleva niente di tutto questo.
[He would not do it. He did not want none of this.]
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
È stata colpa mia. L'ho ???.
[It was my fault. I???.]
So, I'm the one
that needs to go after her.
Bring me my horse, please.
Portatemi il cavallo.
[Bring the horse.]
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
Anna, no. È troppo pericoloso.
[Anna, no. It's too dangerous.]
Elsa's not dangerous.
Elsa non è pericolosa.
[Elsa is not dangerous.]
I'll bring her back, and I'll make this right.
La riporterò qui, si sistemerà tutto.
[Bring her back here, we will settle everything.]
I'm coming with you.
Vengo con te.
[I come with you.]
No, I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
No. C'è bisogno di te ad Arendelle.
[No. We need you to Arendelle.]
On my honor.
Sul mio onore.
[On my honor.]
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Lascio il principe Hans in carica.
[I leave Prince Hans in charge.]
Are you sure you can trust her?
Sei sicura di poterti fidare di lei?
[Are you sure you can trust her?]
I don't want you getting hurt.
Non voglio che ti faccia del male.
[I do not want to hurt you.]
She's my sister.
È mia sorella.
[And my sister.]
She would never hurt me.
Non mi farebbe mai del male.
[It would never hurt.]
"Let It Go" transcript and translation
from FlamSparks http://youtu.be/P9HPQVrBLx4
Sung by Serena Autieri
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
La neve che cade sopra di me
The snow is falling on me
not a footprint to be seen
copre tutto... col suo oblio
covering everything... with its oblivion
A kingdom of isolation,
In questo remoto regno
In this distant kingdom
and it looks like I'm the queen
La regina... sono io
The queen... is me
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Ormai la tempesta nel mio cuore irrompe già
The storm is already breaking into my heart
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Non la fermerà la mia volontà
My will won't hold it
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Ho conservato ogni bugia
I kept every lie
Be the good girl you always had to be
Per il mondo la colpa è solo mia
To the world the fault is only mine
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Così non va, non sentirò
It can't go on like this, I'm not going to listen to
Well, now they know!
... un altro "no"!
... another "no"!
Let it go, let it go!
D'ora in poi lascerò
From now on I'll let
Can't hold it back any more!
che il cuore mi guidi un po'
my heart lead me a little
Let it go, let it go!
Scorderò quel che so
I'll forget what I know
Turn away and slam the door!
E da oggi cambierò
And starting from today I'll change
I don't care what they're going to say
Resto qui, non andrò più via
I'm staying here, I won't go away ever again
Let the storm rage on
Sono sola ormai
Now I'm alone
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Da oggi il freddo è casa mia.
Starting from today the cold is my home.
It's funny how some distance
A volte è un bene
Sometimes it's good
Makes everything seem small
poter scappare un po'
to run away for a while
And the fears that once controlled me
Può sembrare un salto enorme
It may seem like a huge jump
Can't get to me at all!
Ma io l'affronterò!
But I will face it!
It's time to see what I can do
Non è un difetto, è una virtù
It isn't a fault, it's a virtue
To test the limits and break through
E non la fermerò mai più
And I won't hold it ever again
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Nessun ostacolo per me
No obstacle for me
I'm free!
Perché...
Because...
Let it go, let it go!
... d'ora in poi troverò
... from now on I'll find
I am one with the wind and sky
... la mia vera identità
... my true identity
Let it go, let it go!
E vivrò, sì vivrò
And I'll live, yes I'll live
You'll never see me cry
per sempre in libertà!
forever free!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Se è qui il posto mio
If my place is here
Let the storm rage on...
Io lo scoprirò.
I will find it out.
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Il mio potere si diffonde intorno a me
My power is spreading around me
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Il ghiaccio aumenta e copre ogni cosa accanto a sé
Ice is gathering and covering everything by
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Un mio pensiero cristallizza la realtà
A thought from me crystallizes reality
I'm never going back
Il resto è storia ormai
What's left is history by now
The past is in the past!
Che passa e se ne va!
Passing by and going away!
Let it go, let it go!
Io lo so, sì, lo so
I know, yes, I know
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Come il sole tramonterà
I'll set like the sun
Let it go, let it go!
Perché poi, perché poi,
Because then, because then,
That perfect girl is gone
All'alba sorgerò
I'll rise at dawn
Here I stand in the light of day
Ecco qua la tempesta che
Here is the storm that
Let the storm rage on!
non si fermerà!
wont stop!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Da oggi il destino appartiene a me.
Starting from today fate belongs to me.
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
Elsa, sono io, Anna...
[Elsa, it's me, Anna...]
your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
La tua sorellina che non voleva farti congelare l'estate.
[Your sister did not want to make you freeze the summer.]
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
Mi dispiace. È colpa mia.
[I'm sorry. It's my fault.]
Of course, none of it would have happened
Certo non sarebbe successo
[Certainly it would not have happened]
if she had just told me her secret.
se lei mi avesse rivelato il suo segreto.
[if she had revealed his secret.]
She's a stinker.
Che altezzosa!
[That haughty!]
Whoa!
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
No, torna indietro!
[No, come back!]
No, no, no!
Okay.
Bene.
[All right.]
Snow. It had to be snow.
Neve. Doveva essere neve.
[Snow. It had to be snow.]
She couldn't have had tropical magic
Non poteva avere una magia tropicale...
[He could not have a magic tropical...]
that covered the fjords in white sand and warm...
che coprisse i fiordi di sabbia bianca e caldo...
[that covered the fjords of white sand and warm...]
Fire!
Fuoco!
[Fire!]
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
Freddo, freddo, freddo.
[Cold, cold, cold.]
"Wandering Oaken's Trading Post".
"Emporio Querciola Vagabonda".
["Emporio Querciola Vagabonda".]
Ooh. "And sauna"!
"E sauna"!
["And sauna"!]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
??? grande svendita.
[??? big sale.]
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
Costumi a metà prezzo, zoccoli
[Costumes for half price, hooves]
and a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
e protezione solare di mia invenzione, yah?
[and sunscreen of my invention, yah?]
Oh. Great. For now, um, how about boots?
Oh. Bene. Per ora, che ne dite di scarponi?
[Oh. All right. For now, how about boots?]
Winter boots? And dresses?
Scarponi invernali e abiti?
[Winter boots and clothes?]
That would be in our winter department.
Sono nel reparto invernale.
[I am in department winter.]
Oh. Um...
I was just wondering.
Mi chiedevo...
[I was wondering...]
Has another young woman...
Se un'altra giovani fanciulla,
[If another young girl,]
The queen perhaps, I don't know,
la regina, magari...
[the queen, maybe...]
passed through here?
fosse passata di qua?
[He had passed this way?]
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm
L'unica pazza ad uscire con questa tempesta,
[The only crazy to go out in this storm,]
is you, dear.
sei tu.
[is you.]
You and this fellow.
Tu e il montanaro.
[You and mountaineer.]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
??? grande svendita.
[??? big sale.]
Carrots.
Carote.
[Dear You.]
Huh?
Behind you.
Dietro di te.
[Behind you.]
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Giusto. Perdon a me.
[Right. Forgive me.]
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
Una tempesta coi fiocchi a luglio, sì?
[A storm slap in July, yes?]
Wherever could it be coming from?
Chissà da dove viene?
[Who knows where it comes from?]
The North Mountain.
Dalla Montagna del Nord.
[From the North Mountain.]
North Mountain.
La Montagna del Nord.
[The North Mountain.]
That will be forty.
Sono quaranta.
[I'm forty.]
Forty? No, ten.
Quaranta? No, dieci.
[Forty? No, ten.]
Oh, dear, that's no good.
Oh, caro, non ???.
[Oh, dear, no???.]
See, this is from our winter stock,
Queste sono le provviste invernali...
[These are equipped with winter...]
where supply and demand have a big problem.
Quando per domanda e offerta è un grosso problema.
[When to supply and demand is a big problem.]
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
Vuoi parlare del problema di domanda e offerta?
[Do you want to talk about the problem of supply and demand?]
I sell ice for a living.
Io vendo ghiaccio per vivere.
[I sell ice to live.]
Ooh. That's a rough business to be in right now.
Commercio duro portare avanti ora.
[Business tough carry on now.]
I mean, that is really...
Insomma è una situazione...
[In short it is a situation...]
That's unfortunate.
... congelata.
[... frozen.]
Still forty.
Sempre quaranta.
[Always forty.]
But I will throw in a visit to Oaken's sauna.
Ma offro una visitina nella mia sauna.
[But I offer a visit in my sauna.]
Hoo-hoo. Hi, family.
Ciao, famiglia!
[Hello, family!]
Hoo-hoo!
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
Dieci è tutto ciò che ho. Vienimi incontro.
[Ten is all I have. Meet me.]
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
Ma certo, con dieci prendi questo e piu.
[Of course, with ten take this and more.]
Okay, just tell me one thing.
Dimmi solo una cosa.
[Just tell me one thing.]
What was happening on the North Mountain?
Quello che succedeva sulla Montagna del Nord...
[What happened on the North Mountain...]
Did it seem magical?
sembrava una magia?
[It seemed a magic?]
Yes!
Sì!
[Yes!]
Now, back up while I deal with this crook, here.
E ora, spostati che sistemo questo furfante.
[And now, moved to settle this villain.]
What did you call me?
Cosa mi hai detto?
[What did you say?]
Okay, okay. I'm out.
Va bene, va bene.
[Okay okay.]
Whoa!
Bye-bye.
Addio!
[Goodbye!]
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
No. Sven, niente carote.
[No. Sven, no carrots.]
But I did find us a place to sleep.
Ma ho trovato dove dormire.
[But I found where to sleep.]
And it's free.
Ed è gratis.
[And it's free.]
I'm sorry about this violence.
Mi scuso di cotanta violenza.
[I apologize of so much violence.]
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
Aggiungo un quarto di lutefisk
[Add a quarter of lutefisk]
so we have good feelings.
???
[???]
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
La abiti e scarponi, yah?
[The clothes and boots, yah?]
Uh...
Reindeers are better than people
Sono migliori le renne;
Reindeers are better;
Sven, don't you think that's true?
Sven, tu ne sai di più!
Sven, you know about it more!
"Yeah, people will beat you and curse you and cheat you"
"L'umano è cattivo, crudele, nocivo,"
"The human is evil, cruel, noxious,"
"Every one of them's bad, except you!"
"Solo uno è buono e sei tu."
"Only one is good and that's you."
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
Grazie, amico.
Thanks, buddy.
But people smell better than reindeers
Ma l’uomo profuma ogni tanto;
But man smells occasionally;
Sven, don't you think I'm right?
Sven, forse tu lo sai?
Sven, maybe you know it?
"That's once again true, for all except you!"
"Mi chiedo perché non valga per te."
"I ask myself why with you it doesn't apply."
You got me! Let's call it a night.
Non saprei. È tardi lo sai.
I wouldn't know. It's late, you know.
"Good night"
"Buonanotte."
"Goodnight."
Don't let the frostbite
Tu non deludermi
You won't let me down...
Bite
Mai.
... ever.
Nice duet.
Bel duetto.
[Beautiful duet.]
It's just you. What do you want?
Sei solo tu. Che vuoi?
[You're just you. What do you want?]
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
Portami sulla Montagna del Nord.
[Bring on the North Mountain.]
I don't take people places.
Non porto la gente nei posti.
[They do not bring people in places.]
Let me rephrase that.
Bene. Riformulò.
[All right. Rephrase.]
Hey.
Ehi.
[Hey.]
Take me up the North Mountain.
Portami sulla Montagna del Nord.
[Bring on the North Mountain.]
Please.
Per favore.
[Please.]
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
Senti. Io so come fermare l'inverno.
[Listen. I know how to stop the winter.]
We leave at dawn.
Partiamo all'alba.
[We leave at dawn.]
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
E porta le carote per Sven.
[And bring carrots for Sven.]
Oops, sorry.
Oh, scusa.
[Oh sorry.]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
Scusa, non volevo...
[Sorry, I did not want...]
We leave now. Right now.
Partiamo subito. Subitissimo.
[We start now. Now-now.]
Whew!
Hang on! We like to go fast.
Tieniti forte! Amiamo andare veloci.
[Hold fast! We love to go fast.]
I like fast. - Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Amo la velocità.
[I love the speed.]
Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
Giù i piedi. È laccata di fresco.
[Down feet. It is lacquered fresh.]
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
Ma sei cresciuta in una stalla?
[But you grow up in a stable?]
Ugh!
No, I was raised in a castle.
No, in un castello.
[No, in a castle.]
So, uh, tell me,
E, dimmi...
[And, tell me...]
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
Perché la regina ha la ghiaccio-mania?
[Because the queen has the ice - mania?]
Oh. Well...
Beh...
[Well...]
It was all my fault.
È stata colpa mia.
[It was my fault.]
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
Mi sono fidanzata e lei si è infuriata...
[I got engaged and she was angry...]
because I'd only just met him you know, that day.
perché l'avevo conosciuto quel giorno.
[because I had known that day.]
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage, and...
Lei non ha benedetto il matrimonio...
[She has blessed the marriage...]
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
Scusa. Hai incontrato un uomo e ti ci sei fidanzata quel giorno?
[Sorry. You met a man and you're there girlfriend that day?]
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
Sì. ?????
[Yes.?????]
and then she tried to walk away, and I grabbed her glove...
?????
[?????]
Hang on!
Una momento!
[A moment!]
You mean to tell me you got engaged
????
[????]
to someone you just met that day?
????
[????]
Yes. Pay attention.
Sì. Presta attenzione.
[Yes. Be careful.]
But the thing is, she wore the gloves all the time,
Ma lei indossa sempre i guanti...
[But she always wears gloves...]
so I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
Perciò credevo che fosse fissata con lo sporco.
[So I thought it was fixed with dirt.]
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
I tuoi non ti hanno messa in guardia sugli sconosciuti?
[Your not you have warned about strangers?]
Yyyyyes, they did.
Sì, certo.
[Yes sure.]
But Hans is not a stranger.
Ma Hans non è uno sconosciuto.
[But Hans is not a stranger.]
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
Ah, sì? Qual è il suo cognome?
[Oh yes? What is your surname?]
"Of the Southern Isles."
"Delle Isole del Sud."
["Islands of the South."]
What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
Cibo preferito? - ???
[Favorite food? -???]
Best friend's name? - Probably John.
???? - Probabilmente John.
[???? - Probably John.]
Eye color? - Dreamy.
Colore degli occhi? - Da sogno.
[Eye color? - From dream.]
Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
Numero di scarpe? - ???
[Shoe size? -???]
Have you had a meal with him yet? What if you hate the way he eats?
Hai mai cenato con lui? E se non ti piace come mangia?
[Have you ever had dinner with him? And if you do not like how you eat?]
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
Se si scaccola?
[If scaccola?]
Picks his nose?
Si scaccola?
[Scaccola?]
And eats it.
E ??? le mangia.
[E??? eats.]
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
??? signore, lui è un principe.
[??? Sir, he's a prince.]
All men do it.
I maschi lo fanno tutti.
[The males do it all.]
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
D'accordo. Non conta molto. È vero amore.
[All right. It does not matter much. True love.]
It doesn't sound like true love.
Non sembra vero amore.
[It does not seem true love.]
Are you some sort of love expert?
Sei una specie di esperto in amore?
[You're something of an expert in love?]
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
No, ma ho amici esperti.
[No, but I've experienced friends.]
You have friends
???
[???]
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
... esperti in amore? Non la bevo.
[... Experts in love? Do not buy that.]
Stop talking. - No, no, no. No, no.
Ora zitta. - No, no, no. No, no.
[Now shut up. - No no no. No no.]
I'd like to meet these... - No, I mean it.
Voglio incontrarli... - ???
[I want to meet them... -???]
Sven, go.
Sven, corri.
[Sven, run.]
Go!
What are they? - Wolves.
È cosa sono? - Lupi.
[They are what? - Wolves.]
Wolves?
Lupi?
[Wolves?]
What do we do? - I got this.
Che facciamo? - Ci penso io.
[What do we do? - I'll do it.]
You just... Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
Tu... Non cadere e non farti mangiare.
[You... Do not fall and not get eaten.]
But I want to help!
Ma voglio aiutarti!
[But I want to help!]
No. - Why not?
No. - Perché no?
[No. - Why not?]
Because I don't trust your judgment.
Non mi fido del tuo giudizio.
[I trust your judgment.]
Excuse me?
Come, prego?
[How, pray?]
Who marries a man she just met?
???
[???]
It's true love!
È vero amore!
[True love!]
Whoa!
Whoa. Whoa!
Christopher!
It's "Kristoff"!
Mi chiamo Kristoff!
[My name Kristoff!]
Ow!
Duck!
Giù!
[Down!]
You almost set me on fire!
Stavi per ??? !
[You were going to??? !]
But I didn't.
Ma non l'ho fatto.
[But I did not.]
Get ready to jump, Sven!
Prepare a saltare, Sven!
[Prepare to jump, Sven!]
You don't tell him what to do.
Non dirgli quello che deve fare!
[Do not tell him what to do!]
I do!
Jump, Sven!
Salta, Sven!
[Salta, Sven!]
Phew!
But I just paid it off.
L'avevo finito appena pagata.
[I had just finished paid.]
Uh-oh. No. No.
No!
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Grab on!
Aggrappati!
[Hold on!]
Pull, Sven. Pull!
Tira, Sven. Tira.
[Tira, Sven. Tira.]
Whoa.
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
Ti ricomprerò la slitta. E quello che c'era dentro.
[I will buy the sled. And what was inside.]
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
E capirò se non vorrai aiutarmi più.
[And I will understand if you do not want to help me more.]
Of course I don't want to help her anymore. In fact,
Certo che non la aiuterò più.
[Of course I do not help the most.]
this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
Questa storia mi ha convinto: non aiuterò più nessuno.
[This story has convinced me: I will not help anyone.]
It's this way?
È di qua?
[You here?]
"She'll die on her own."
"Da sola morirà."
["By itself he will die."]
I can live with that. - Here we go.
Me ne farò una ragione. - Ecco fatto.
[I will make a right. - I have done.]
"But you won't get your new sled if she's dead."
"Ma non avrai la slitta nuova se morirà."
["But you will not die if the new sled."]
I think, actually, it's up.
Credo che sia lassù.
[I think it's up there.]
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
Certe volte non ti sopporto.
[Sometimes I can not stand you.]
Hold up! We're coming.
Aspetta. Arriviamo!
[Wait. Here we come!]
You are?
Davvero?
[Really?]
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
Cioè, certo, vi permetto di accompagnarmi.
[That is, of course, allow you to accompany me.]
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
È completamente ghiacciata.
[It is completely frozen.]
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
???
[???]
Will she?
Yeah. Now, come on.
Sì, andiamo.
[Yes, let's go.]
This way to the North Mountain?
È laggiù la Montagna del Nord?
[Is there the Mountain North?]
More like this way.
Più lassù.
[More up there.]
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
Non credevo che l'inverno fosse così bello.
[I did not think that the winter was so beautiful.]
Yeah.
Sì.
[Yes.]
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
È bello vero, no?
[It's real nice, no?]
But it's so white.
Ma è tutto così bianco.
[But everything is so white.]
You know, how about a little color?
Che ne dite di un po' di colore?
[How about a bit' of color?]
I'm thinking maybe some crimson, chartreuse.
Pensavo al rosso cremisi, al verde Caraibi.
[I thought to crimson red, green Caribbean.]
How about yellow?
E il giallo?
[And the yellow?]
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
No, giallo no. Giallo sulla neve?
[No, no yellow. Yellow snow?]
No go.
Non va.
[It does not work.]
Am I right?
Dico bene?
[Am I right?]
You're creepy.
Fai spavento!
[Make fright!]
I don't want it.
Non lo voglio.
[I do not want it.]
Back at you. - Please don't drop me.
Riprendilo. - Cado.
[Take it back. - Cado.]
Come on, it's just a head.
Orsù, è solo una testa.
[Come on, it's just a head.]
All right. We got off to a bad start.
Cominciamo male.
[Let's start badly.]
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
Ah! il corpo.
[Ah! the body.]
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Ehi, che cosa vedo?
[Hey, what do I see?]
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
State a testa in giù come pipistrelli?
[State upside down like bats?]
All right, wait one second.
Aspetta.
[Wait.]
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Grazie. - Figurati.
[Thank you. - Imagine.]
Now, I'm perfect.
Ora sono perfetto.
[Now I am perfect.]
Well, almost.
Quasi perfetto!
[Almost perfect!]
It was like my whole life got turned upside down.
Era come se tutta la mia vita fosse sottosopra.
[It was as if my whole life was upside down.]
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
Troppo forte. Scusa!
[Too strong. Sorry!]
Head rush! - I was just... Are you okay?
Che vertigini! - Stai bene?
[What vertigo! - Are you OK?]
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
Scherzi? Una meraviglia!
[Seriously? A marvel!]
I've always wanted a nose.
Lo volevo da sempre un nasino.
[I always wanted a little nose.]
So cute.
Che carino.
[So cute.]
It's like a little baby unicorn.
È come un piccolo unicorno.
[It's like a little unicorn.]
But... Hey! Whoa!
Oh.
I love it even more.
Lo amo ancora di più.
[I love him even more.]
All right, let's start this thing over.
Va bene, ricominciamo da capo.
[Okay, we start over.]
Hi, everyone.
Ciao a tutti.
[Hello everyone.]
I'm Olaf.
Io sono Olaf.
[I'm Olaf.]
And I like warm hugs.
E amo i caldi abbracci.
[And I love the warm hugs.]
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
È vero, Olaf!
[True, Olaf!]
And you are?
E tu sei?
[And you are?]
Oh. Um...
I'm Anna.
Io sono Anna.
[I am Anna.]
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
E chi è quel somarello lì?
[And who is the donkey there?]
That's Sven.
Quello è Sven.
[What is Sven.]
And who's the reindeer?
E la renna chi è?
[And the reindeer who is?]
Sven.
Oh, they're... Oh. Okay. That makes things easier for me.
Okay. È più facile ???.
[Okay. It's easier???.]
Aw, look at him trying to kiss my nose.
???, vuole baciarmi il naso.
[???, He wants to kiss my nose.]
I like you, too.
Mi piaci anche tu.
[I like you too.]
Olaf. Did Elsa build you? - Yeah. Why?
Olaf. Ti ha fatto Elsa? - Sì, perché?
[Olaf. Did you Elsa? - Yes because?]
Do you know where she is? - Yeah. Why?
Tu sai dove? - Sì, perché?
[Do you know where? - Yes because?]
Fascinating.
Do you think you could show us the way? - Yeah. Why?
Puoi indicarci la strada? - Sì, perché?
[You can show us the way? - Yes because?]
How does this work? Ow!
Come funziona?
[How does it work?]
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus, here.
??? devo concentrarmi.
[??? I have to focus.]
Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.
Sì, perché? - Te lo dico io perché.
[Yes because? - I'll tell you why.]
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
Elsa deve far tornare l'estate.
[Elsa must bring back the summer.]
Summer?
L'estate?
[Summer?]
Oh. I don't know why,
Non so perché...
[I do not know why...]
but I've always loved the idea of summer
ma ho sempre amato l'idea dell'estate.
[but I've always loved the idea of the summer.]
and sun, and all things hot.
E il sole, il caldo afoso.
[And the sun, the sultry heat.]
Really?
Davvero?
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
Mi sa che non hai molta familiarità col caldo!
I think that you don't have so much familiarity with heat!
Nope.
No!
Nope!
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
Ma a volte amo chiudere gli occhi
But sometimes I love to close my eyes
and imagine what it would be like when summer does come.
e immaginare come sarebbe se venisse l'Estate!
and to imagine how it would be if Summer came!
Bees will buzz, kids will blow dandelion fuzz
Basta che l'ape svolazzi accanto a me
It is enough that the bee flutters next to me
And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer
ed io ricordo in un attimo quel che amo!
and I remember in a moment what I love!
A drink in my hand
Un drink? Lo vorrei!
A drink? I would!
My snow up against the burning sand
Magari anch'io mi abbronzarsi!
Perhaps I would tan too!
Probably getting gorgeously tanned
Penso all'estate perché...
I think of the summer because...
In summer.
... la amo!
... I love it!
I'll finally see a summer breeze
Le onde, il mare, la marea,
The waves, the sea, the tide,
Blow away a winter storm
e poi, caldo a volontà!
and then, heat at will!
And find out what happens to solid water
Se il sole si incontra col ghiaccio freddo
If the sun meets with the cold ice
When it gets warm
chissà che fa?
who knows what will happen?
And I can't wait to see
E lo sai credo che...
And you know, I think...
What my buddies all think of me
... guarderebbero tutti me
... everyone will watch me
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be
Il mio sex-appeal dà il meglio di sè
My sex-appeal gives the best of itself
In summer!
d'Estate!
in Summer!
The hot and the cold are both so intense
Uniamo il freddo ed il caldo intenso,
Let's combine the cold and the intense heat,
Put them together It just makes sense
ecco un'idea che ha davvero senso!
here's an idea that really makes sense!
Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle
Solo d'Estate il mio cuore si scalda,
Only in Summer my heart warms,
But put me in summer and I'll be a...
la gioia che provo pensandoci
but I'd be merrily thinking of
(puddle?)
(cadulda?)
(melted ice?)
Happy snowman!
è enorme!
being huge!
When life gets rough
E' questo il sogno
This is the dream
I like to hold on to my dream
che mi piace da morire;
that I love;
Of relaxing in the summer sun, just letting off steam
Ti rilassa e poi ti aiuta un pò se vuoi sbollire!
It relaxes you and then helps you a bit if you want to cool down!
Oh, the sky will be blue
Sole caldo su di noi
Hot sun is on us
And you guys will be there, too
ci sareste anche voi!
you would be there too!
When I finally do
Un'estate da Re
A Royal Summer
What frozen things do in summer!
da vivere in tre, insieme!
the three of us living together!
I'm gonna tell him.
Io glielo dico.
I'm going to tell him.
Don't you dare.
Non ci provare!
Don't try!
In summer!
Insieme!
Together!
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Let's go bring back summer!
??? far tornare l'estate!
[??? bring back the summer!]
I'm coming!
Arrivo!
[Arrival!]
Somebody's gotta tell him.
Qualcuno glielo deve dire!
[Someone has to tell him!]
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
No, hai messo la corteccia in giù.
[No, you put down the bark.]
The bark needs to be face-up.
La corteccia deve stare in su.
[The bark should be up.]
Bark down is drier. - Bark up!
In giù secca meglio. - Corteccia in su!
[Down dry better. - Bark up!]
Bark down! - Papa!
Corteccia in giù! - Papa!
[Bark down! - Papa!]
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Una coperta. A chi serve una coperta?
[A blanket. Who needs a blanket?]
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
Arendelle è in debito con voi.
[Arendelle is in your debt.]
The castle is open.
Il castello è aperto.
[The castle is open.]
There is soup and hot gløgg in the Great Hall.
C'è zuppa e glogg caldo nel grande salone.
[There is soup and glogg hot in the great hall.]
Here, pass these out.
Ecco, distribuiteli.
[Here, distribute them.]
Prince Hans!
Principe Hans!
[Prince Hans!]
Are we expected to just sit here and freeze
Volete che restiamo qui a gelare...
[You want us to stay here to freeze...]
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
mentre voi regalate tutti i beni di Arendelle?
[while you give away all the goods Arendelle?]
Princess Anna has given her orders.
La principessa ha dato ordini...
[The princess gave orders...]
And that's another thing!
E c'è anche questo!
[And there is also this!]
Has it dawned on you that your princess may be conspiring
Non avete pensato che la principessa potrebbe cospirare...
[You did not think that the princess could conspire...]
with a wicked sorceress
con quella strega...
[with that witch...]
to destroy us all?
per distruggerci tutti?
[to destroy us all?]
Do not question the princess.
Non dubitate della principessa.
[Do not doubt the princess.]
She left me in charge
Mi ha lasciato in carica...
[He left me in charge...]
and I will not hesitate
E io proteggerò
[And I will protect]
to protect Arendelle from treason.
Arendelle dal tradimento.
[Arendelle betrayal.]
Treason?
Tradimento?
[Treason?]
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Oh, buono!
[Oh, good!]
Easy.
Buono.
[Good.]
It's Princess Anna's horse.
È il cavallo della principessa Anna.
[It is the horse of Princess Anne.]
So, where is the princess?
Dove sarà la Principessa?
[Where is the Princess?]
Where could she be? - Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
La Principessa Anna è in pericolo.
[Princess Anne is in danger.]
I need volunteers to go with me to find her.
Mi servono dei volontari per trovarla.
[They need volunteers to find it.]
I'll go. I volunteer.
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Io offro due uomini, Milord.
[I offer two men, Milord.]
Be prepared for anything.
Siate pronti a tutto.
[Be ready for anything.]
And should you encounter the queen,
E se ??? la Regina...
[And if ??? the Queen...]
you are to put an end to this winter.
ponete fine a questo inverno.
[Place an end to this winter.]
Do you understand?
Mi sono spiegato?
[I make myself clear?]
So, how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
E come pensi di far cambiare questo tempaccio?
[And how do you plan to change this weather?]
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
Ehh... intendo parlerò con mia sorella.
[Ehh... I intend to speak with my sister.]
That's your plan?
È questo tuo piano?
[Is that your plan?]
My ice business is riding on you talking to your sister?
Il mio commercio di ghiaccio dipende dall'incontro con tua sorella?
[My trade of ice depends on the encounter with your sister?]
Yep.
Sì.
[Yes.]
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
Così, non hai paura di lei?
[So, are not you afraid of her?]
Why would I be?
Perché dovrei?
[Why should I?]
Yeah. I bet she's the nicest, gentlest, warmest person ever.
Sì, ??? la persona più carina e ??? del mondo.
[Yes, ??? the nicest person and ??? of the world.]
Oh. Look at that.
Oh, guarda.
[Oh, look.]
I've been impaled.
Mi sono stalactitato. (???)
I've been stalactited. (???)
What now?
E ora?
[And now?]
Mmm...
It's too steep.
È troppo ripido.
[It's too steep.]
I've only got one rope and you don't know how to climb mountains.
Ho solo una fune, e tu non sai scalare le montagne.
[I only have a rope, and you do not know mountain climbing.]
Says who?
E chi lo dice?
[Says who?]
Hmm?
What are you doing?
Che cosa fai?
[What do you do?]
I'm going to see my sister.
??? mia sorella.
[??? my sister.]
You're gonna kill yourself.
Ti ucciderai, cosi.
[You'll kill yourself, so.]
I wouldn't put my foot there.
Non metterei il piede lì.
[I do not put your foot there.]
You're distracting me. - Or there.
Mi distrai. - Neanche lì.
[I get distracted. - Not there.]
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
Come sai che Elsa vorrà vederti?
[How do you know Elsa wants to see you?]
All right. I'm just blocking you out
Bene. ??? ignorerò basta
[All right. ??? just ignore]
because I gotta concentrate, here.
??? concentrare.
[??? concentrate.]
You know, most people who disappear
La major parta ??? montagna
[The major starts ??? mountain]
into the mountains want to be alone.
vuole stare solo.
[He wants to be alone.]
Nobody wants to be alone.
Nessuno vuole stare solo.
[Nobody wants to be alone.]
Except maybe you.
A parte forse te.
[Except maybe you.]
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
Io non sono solo. Ho amici, ricordi?
[I am not alone. I have friends, remember?]
You mean, the love experts?
Ah, gli esperti in amore?
[Ah, the experts in love?]
Yes, the love experts.
Sì, esperti in amore.
[Yes, experts in love.]
Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Ti prego dimmi che ci sono quasi.
[Please tell me that there are almost.]
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
L'aria non sembra più rarefatta quassù?
[The air does not seem thinner up here?]
Hang on.
Resisti.
[Hold on.]
Hey, Sven?
Not sure if this is gonna solve the problem,
Non so se risolve il problema...
[I do not know if it solves the problem...]
but I found a staircase that leads exactly
Ma ho trovato una scala che porta...
[But I found a staircase leading...]
where you wanted to go.
Dove vogliamo andare.
[Where we want to go.]
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
Grazie al cielo. Prendimi!
[Thank goodness. Take me!]
Thanks. That was like a crazy trust exercise.
Grazie. È stata una folle prova di fiducia.
[Thank you. It was a crazy proof of confidence.]
Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
Questo è ghiaccio.
[This is ice.]
I might cry.
Voglio piangere.
[I want to cry.]
Go ahead. I won't judge.
???. Non ti giudicherò.
[???. I do not judge.]
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
I got you.
Ci penso io.
[I got it.]
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
Tu resta qui, Sven.
[You stay here, Sven.]
Flawless.
È perfetta.
[It's perfect.]
Knock.
Bussa.
[Knocks.]
Just knock.
??? bussa.
[??? knocks.]
Why isn't she knocking?
Perché non bussa?
[Why do not you knock?]
Do you think she knows how to knock?
Credi che sappia bussare?
[You think he knows knock?]
Huh. It opened.
È aperto.
[It's open.]
That's a first.
Mai successo.
[Never happened.]
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
Tu aspetti fuori.
[You wait outside.]
What? - The last time I introduced her to a guy,
Che cosa? - Quando gli ho presentato un ragazzo
[What? - When I presented him with a boy]
she froze everything.
ha congelato tutto.
[It froze everything.]
But, but... Oh, come on!
Ma...
[But...]
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
È un palazzo di ghiaccio. Il ghiaccio è la mia vita.
[It's an ice palace. Ice is my life.]
Bye, Sven.
Addio, Sven.
[Farewell, Sven.]
You, too, Olaf.
Anche tu, Olaf.
[You too, Olaf.]
Me? - Just give us a minute.
Anche io? - ??? solo minuto.
[Me too? - ??? minute.]
Okay.
Va bene.
[All right.]
One, two, three...
Uno, due, tre...
[One two three...]
Four...
Quattro...
[Four...]
Whoa.
Elsa?
It's me, Anna.
Sono io, Anna.
[It's me, Anna.]
Anna.
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
Elsa, sei cambiata.
[Elsa, you've changed.]
It's a good different.
In meglio, davvero.
[For the better, really.]
And this place...
E questo posto...
[And this place...]
It's amazing.
È meraviglioso!
[It's wonderful!]
Thank you.
Grazie.
[Thank you.]
I never knew what I was capable of.
Non sapevo di cosa fossi capace.
[I did not know what I was capable.]
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd have known...
Mi dispiace tanto per quanto è accaduto.
[I'm so sorry for what happened.]
No, no, no. It's okay.
No, no, va tutto bene.
[No, no, everything's fine.]
You don't have to apologize, but you should probably go.
Non devi scusarti, ma dovresti andare.
[You do not apologize, but you should go.]
Please.
Ti prego.
[Please.]
But I just got here.
Sono arrivata ora.
[I came now.]
You belong down in Arendelle.
Il tuo posto è ad Arendelle.
[It belongs to Arendelle.]
So do you.
Anche il tuo.
[Even your.]
No, Anna, I belong here.
No, Anna. Il mio posto è qui.
[No, Anna. My place is here.]
Alone.
Da sola.
[Alone.]
Where I can be who I am without hurting anybody.
Dove posso essere come sono senza far male a nessuno.
[Where I can be as I am not hurting anyone.]
Actually, about that...
Veramente, a proposito di questo...
[Really, about this...]
Sixty! - Wait. What is that?
??? - Aspetta, ???
[??? - Wait, ???]
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
Ciao, io sono Olaf e amo i caldi abbracci!
[Hello, I'm Olaf and I love the warm hug!]
Olaf?
You built me.
Sì, mi hai fatto tu.
[Yes, you've done you.]
Remember that?
Te lo ricordi?
[Do you remember?]
And you're alive?
E sei vivo?
[And you're alive?]
Um... I think so.
Credo di sì.
[I think so.]
He's just like the one we built as kids.
Sempre quello che abbiamo fatto da piccole.
[Always what we did small.]
Yeah.
Sì.
[Yes.]
Elsa, we were so close.
Elsa, eravamo così unite.
[Elsa, we were so united.]
We can be like that again.
Potremmo esserlo ancora.
[We may be still.]
Catch me! Slow down!
Prendimi! ???
[Take me! ???]
Anna!
No.
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
Non possiamo. Addio, Anna.
[We can not. Goodbye, Anna.]
Elsa, wait.
Elsa, aspetta.
[Elsa, wait.]
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
Voglio solo proteggerti.
[I just want to protect you.]
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
Non devi proteggermi, io non ho paura.
You don't have to protect me, I'm not afraid.
Please don't shut me out again.
Non escludermi di nuovo dalla tua vita.
Don't cut me off from your life again.
Please don't slam the door
Dai, non dirmi no
Come on, don't tell me no
You don't have to keep your distance anymore
Non dovrai scappare adesso che lo so
You won't have to run away now that I know
'Cause for the first time in forever
Posso aiutarti per davvero
I can really help you
I finally understand
Tu fidati di me
Just trust me
For the first time in forever
Tutto quello che volevo
All I wanted
We can fix this hand in hand
Era stare accanto a te
Was to stay by you
We can head down this mountain together.
Insieme risolveremo tutto
We'll settle everything together
You don't have to live in fear
E vedrai, sarà così
And you'll see, that's how it's going to be
'Cause for the first time in forever
Tutto è diverso perché adesso
Everything is different because now
I will be right here
Hai un'amica qui.
You've got a friend here.
Anna.
Anna...
Please go back home
Mi domandi troppo,
You're asking too much of me,
Your life awaits
dai retta a me
listen to me
Go enjoy the sun, and open up the gates
Non c'è nulla qua per una coma te
There's nothing here for someone like you
Yeah, but...
Sì, ma...
Yes, but...
I know.
Lo so
I know
You mean well, but leave me be
Tu pensi che mi aiuterai
You think you're going to help me
Yes, I'm alone
Ma senza me...
But without me...
But I'm alone and free
... problemi non ne avrai
... you'll have no problems
Just stay away and you'll be safe from me
E non dovrai più preoccuparti ormai
And you won't need to worry any more
Actually, we're not
Sai, non è così
Well, this isn't the way it is
What do you mean, you're not?
Come non è così?
What do you mean, this isn't the way it is?
I get the feeling you don't know
Non puoi saperlo neanche tu
Not even you can know it
What do I not know?
Parla, forza, su!
Speak out, come on!
Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep
Lì la neve è sempre, sempre, sempre, sempre
The snow is getting always, always, always, always...
deep snow
... di più
... more
What?
Cosa?
You kind of set off an eternal winter everywhere.
Hai portato un inverno perenne... ovunque
You've brought a perpetual winter... everywhere
Everywhere?
Ovunque?
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
Ma non fa niente, puoi sciogliere tutto
But it doesn't matter, you can thaw everything out
No, I can't. I don't know how.
No, non posso. Non so come fare!
No, I can't. I don't know how!
Sure you can. I know you can.
Certo che puoi. Io so che puoi.
'Cause for the first time in forever
Avrò la forza per restare
I'll have the strength to stay
Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free!
Non avrò mai la libertà!
I'll never have my freedom!
You don't have to be afraid
Non dovrai scappare, sai
You won't have to run away, you know
No escape from the storm inside of me
Sono in trappola e nulla cambierà
I'm trapped and nothing will change
We can work this out together
Sul mio aiuto puoi contare
You can rely on my help
I can't control the curse!
Che faccio d'ora io poi?
What shall I do from now on?
We'll reverse the storm you've made
Non sei più da sola ormai
You're no longer alone
Anna, please you'll only make it worse!
Anna, vuoi salvarmi ma non puoi!
Anna, you want to save me but you can't!
Don't panic!
Tranquilla
Don't worry
There's so much fear!
È colpa mia!
It's my fault!
We'll make the sun shine bright
Vedrai, funzionerà
You'll see, it's going to work
You're not safe here!
Non c'è altra via!
There's no other way!
We can face this thing together
Se le forze uniremo
If we join our forces
No!
We can change this winter weather
So che noi ci riusciremo
I know we can make it
And everything will be all right
E la bufera passerà
And the storm will blow over
I can't!
Vai via!
Begone!
Anna!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Sto bene.
[I'm fine.]
I'm fine.
Sto bene.
[I'm fine.]
Who's this?
Chi è lui?
[Who is he?]
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
Aspetta, non importa. Solo...
[Wait, never mind. Only...]
You have to go.
Andate via.
[Go away.]
No, I know we can figure this out together.
No, so che insieme lo risolveremo.
[No, I know that together we will solve it.]
How?
Come?
[How?]
What power do you have to stop this winter?
Che potere hai per fermare questo inverno?
[What power you have to stop this winter?]
To stop me?
Per fermare me?
[To stop me?]
Anna, I think we should go.
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Non vado via senza di te, Elsa.
[I do not go away without you, Elsa.]
Yes, you are.
Sì, invece ???.
[Yes but ???.]
Stop! Put us down!
Fermo! Mettici giù!
[Stop! Put us down!]
Go away.
Andate via.
[Go away.]
Heads up!
Occhio!
[Eye!]
Watch out for my butt!
Chiappette arriva!
[My behind's coming in!]
It is not nice to throw people!
Non è carino lanciare la gente!
[Not nice throw people!]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants. Okay, relax.
Ehi, furia scatenata.
[Hey, fury.]
Just calm down! Calm down! - Okay! All right!
Calmati! - Va bene!
[Calm down! - All right!]
I'm okay. - Just let the snowman be.
Sto bene. - Lascia stare il pupazzo di neve.
[I'm fine. - Leave the snowman.]
I'm calm.
Sono calma.
[I am calm.]
Oh! Come on!
Oh. Look, see? Now you made him mad.
Visto? L'hai fatto arrabbiare!
[See? You've angered!]
I'll distract him. You guys go.
Io lo distraggo. Voi andate.
[I get distracted. You go.]
No, no! Not you guys!
No, no! Non voi due!
[No no! Not you two!]
This just got a whole lot harder.
Look out!
Attenzione!
[Attention!]
What are you doing?
Che cosa fai?
[What do you do?]
I got him!
Whoa! Stop!
Ferma!
[Stop!]
It's a hundred-foot drop.
È un salto di trenta metri.
[It is a leap of thirty meters.]
It's two hundred.
??? sessanta.
[??? sixty.]
Ow!
What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
Che fai? - Un ancoraggio.
[What are you doing? - An anchor.]
Okay. What if we fall?
Certo. E se cadiamo?
[Sure. And if we fall?]
There's 20 feet of fresh powder down there.
Ci sono cinque metri di neve fresca.
[There are five meters of fresh snow.]
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
Sarà come atterrare su un cuscino.
[It will be like landing on a pillow.]
Hopefully.
Almeno spero.
[I hope.]
Okay, Anna. On three.
Anna. Al tre.
[Anna. On three.]
One...
Uno...
[One...]
Okay. You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
Dammi il via. Sono pronta.
[Give me off. I'm ready.]
Two... - I was born ready! Yes!
Due... Sono nata pronta.
[Two... I was born ready.]
Calm down.
Calmati.
[Calm down.]
Tree!
Via!
[Via!]
What the... Whoa!
Ma che?
[But who?]
That happened.
È andata.
[It's gone.]
Man, am I out of shape.
Mammina. Sono fuori forma.
[Mommy. I'm out of shape.]
There we go. Hey, Anna!
Ecco fatto. Anna!
[Done. Anna!]
Sven! Where did you guys go?
Sven! Dove siete?
[Sven! Where are you?]
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
???
[???]
Hey! We were just talking about you.
All good things, all good things.
Solo cose belle, solo cose belle.
[Only good things, only good things.]
No!
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
Non fa differenza per te, vero?
[It makes no difference to you, right?]
Olaf!
Hang in there, guys!
Tenete duro!
[Hold on!]
Go. Go faster!
Più veloce!
[Faster!]
Wait, what?
Aspetta, che?
[Wait, what?]
Ow!
Kristoff!
Don't come back!
Non tornate più!
[Do not go back more!]
We won't.
???
[???]
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
Avevi ragione. Come su un cuscino.
[You were right. How about a pillow.]
Olaf!
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
Non mi sento più le gambe!
[I do not feel my legs!]
Those are my legs.
Quelle sono le mie gambe.
[Those are my legs.]
Oooh. Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
Mi acchiappi le chiappe?
[I catch me your ass?]
Oh. That feels better.
Va meglio!
[It goes better!]
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Sven! Ci ha trovati!
[Sven! He found us!]
Who's my cute little reindeer?
La mia rennetta dolce!
[My rennetta sweet!]
Don't talk to him like that.
Non parlargli così!
[Do not talk like that!]
You're tickling me.
Che solletico!
[That tickles!]
Here.
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Tutto bene?
[All right?]
Thank you.
Grazie.
[Thank you.]
How's your head? - Ah! Ooh!
Come va la testa?
[How's your head?]
It's fine. Uh...
Va bene.
[All right.]
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
Tranquillo. Ho il cranio tosto.
[Quiet. I have the skull soon.]
I don't have a skull.
Io non ho il cranio.
[I do not have the skull.]
Or bones.
Né le ossa.
[Neither the bones.]
So, uh... So, now what?
E ora... che si fa?
[And now... what?]
Now what?
Che si fa?
[What do you do?]
Now what?
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
Che faccio io?
[What do I do?]
She threw me out.
Mi ha cacciata via.
[He was thrown out.]
I can't go back to Arendelle with the weather like this.
Non torno ad Arendelle con questo tempaccio.
[I get back to Arendelle in this weather.]
And then there's your ice business.
E c'è il tuo commercio di ghiaccio.
[And there's your trade ice.]
Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
???
[???]
Worry about your hair!
Pensa ai tuoi capelli.
[Think about your hair.]
What? I just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
Che? Sono caduta da una rupe. Dovresti vedere i tuoi.
[What? I fell off a cliff. You should see your.]
No, yours is turning white.
No, i tuoi diventano bianchi.
[No, you become white.]
White? It's... What?
Bianchi? È... Che?
[Bianchi? Is That?]
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
È perché ti ha colpita, vero?
[It's because he struck you, right?]
Does it look bad?
Mi invecchiano?
[I get older?]
No. - You hesitated.
No. - Hai esitato.
[No. - You hesitated.]
No, I didn't.
Non è vero.
[It's not true.]
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
Anna, ti serve aiuto. Andiamo.
[Anna, you need help. Come on.]
Okay! Where are we going?
Dove andiamo?
[Where are we going?]
To see my friends.
Dai miei amici.
[From my friends.]
The love experts?
Gli esperti in amore?
[Experts in love?]
Love experts?
Esperti in amore?
[Experts in love?]
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
E tranquilla. ???
[And quiet. ???]
How do you know?
Come lo sai?
[How do you know that?]
Because I've seen them do it before.
Gliel'ho già visto fare volta.
[I've already seen it done once.]
I like to consider myself a love expert.
Amo considerarmi un esperto in amore.
[I love to consider myself an expert in love.]
Get it together.
Cerca di dominarti.
[Tries to dominate you.]
Control it.
Controllati.
[Controlled.]
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Niente ???
[Nothing???]
Don't feel.
Don't feel!
Look, Sven, the sky's awake.
Sven, il cielo è sveglio.
[Sven, the sky is awake.]
Are you cold? - A little.
Hai freddo? - Un pochino.
[Are you cold? - A little.]
Uh... Wait. Come here.
Aspetta. Vieni qui.
[Wait. Come here.]
Huh?
Ooh.
So, uh, about my friends. Well...
I miei amici...
[My friends...]
I say "friends"...
Dico "amici"...
[I say "friends"...]
They're more like family.
ma sono la mia famiglia.
[but they are my family.]
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven.
Da piccolo eravamo soli, Sven e io.
[As a child we were alone, Sven and me.]
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
Finché non ci hanno presi con loro.
[Until they have taken with them.]
They did?
Davvero?
[Really?]
Yeah. I don't want to scare you.
Sì! Non voglio spaventarti.
[Yes! I do not want to scare you.]
They can be a little inappropriate and loud.
A volte sono sfacciati e chiassosi.
[Sometimes they are brash and boisterous.]
Very loud.
Molto chiassosi.
[Very noisy.]
They are also stubborn at times,
Sono anche testardi, talvolta.
[They are also stubborn, sometimes.]
and a little overbearing.
E prepotenti.
[And bullies.]
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
E pesanti. Molto, molto pesanti.
[And heavy. Very, very heavy.]
But you'll get it. They mean well.
Ma li capirai. Sono buoni.
[But you will understand. They are good.]
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Okay, then.
Bene, allora.
[Well then.]
Meet my family.
Ti presento i miei.
[Meet the Parents.]
Hey, guys.
Ciao, ragazzi.
[Hello guys.]
They're rocks.
Sono rocce.
[They are rocks.]
You are a sight for sore eyes.
Siete una gioia per gli occhi.
[You are a joy to behold.]
He's crazy. - Hey look, ???'s back from vacation!
È completamente pazzo.
[It's completely crazy.]
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Rocko, elegante, come sempre.
[Rocko, elegant, as always.]
Clay, whoa... I don't even recognize you.
Clay, non ti riconoscevo.
[Clay, did not recognize you.]
You lost so much weight.
Hai perso peso.
[You lost weight.]
I'll distract him while you run.
Io lo distraggo tu scappa.
[I distracted you run.]
Hi, Sven's family!
Ciao famiglia di Sven!
[Hello family of Sven!]
It's nice to meet you.
Piacere!
[Pleasure!]
Because I love you, Anna, I insist you run.
Per il tuo bene Anna, insisto: scappa!
[For your sake Anna, I insist: run!]
I understand you're love experts. Ooh!
Si vede che siete esperti in amore.
[You see that you are experienced in love.]
Why aren't you running?
Perché non scappi?
[Why do not you run away?]
Uh...
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
Certo. Io andrei...
[Sure. I would go...]
No, no, no. Anna, wait.
No, Anna, aspetta.
[No, Anna, waiting.]
Kristoff!
Whoa!
Hey!
Ciao!
[Hello!]
Kristoff's home!
Kristoff è tornato!
[Kristoff is back!]
Kristoff's here! Kristoff's home!
Wait, "Kristoff"?
Aspetta. Kristoff?
[Wait. Kristoff?]
Ah, let me look at you.
Fatti vedere.
[Show yourself.]
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
Togli i vestiti, te li lavo.
[Take off your clothes, you wash them.]
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
No, i vestiti me li tengo.
[No, the clothes I keep them.]
Look, it's great to see you all,
È bello vedervi,
[It's nice to see you,]
but where's Granpabbie?
ma dov'è Granpapà?
[but where Granpapà?]
He's napping.
But look, I grew a mushroom.
Mi è cresciuto un fungo.
[I grew a fungus.]
I earned my fire crystal.
Ho avuto il cristallo di fuoco.
[I had a glass of fire.]
I passed a kidney stone.
Ho espulso un calcolo.
[I expelled a calculation.]
Kristoff, pick me up.
Prendimi Kristoff.
[Take Kristoff.]
You're getting big.
-Sei cresciuto!
[-You Are grown!]
Good for you.
Bravo!
[Good Boy!]
Trolls. They're trolls!
Troll! Sono troll!
[Troll! Are trolls!]
He's brought a girl!
Ha portato una donna!
[He brought a woman!]
A girl!
Una donna!
[A woman!]
Is that a real girl?
She's like a little cupcake.
Sembra un cupcake!
[It looks like a cupcake!]
What's going on?
Che succede?
[What happens?]
I've learned to just roll with it.
Io li lascio fare.
[I let them do.]
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
Occhi brillanti, naso libero...
[Shining eyes, nose free...]
strong teeth!
dentatura forte.
[teeth strong.]
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
Sì. Andrà bene per il nostro Kristoff.
[Yes. Will it fit our Kristoff.]
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
Aspetta. No.
[Wait. No.]
You've got the wrong idea.
No. That's not why I brought her here.
Right. We're not... I'm not...
Sì. Noi non siamo... non sono...
[Yes. We are not... we are not...]
What's the issue, dear?
Qual è il problema, tesoro?
[What's the matter, honey?]
Why are you holding back from such a man?
Perché respingi un uomo simile?
[Why reject such a man?]
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
Saltella sempre come un troll?
[Always jumps like a troll?]
What? - Or the grumpy way he talks?
Che cosa? - Non gli piace il rock'n roll?
[What? - He does not like rock'n' roll?]
Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
Ha dei piedi grossi
[He has big feet]
Weirdness of his feet?
quasi quanto me?
[almost as much as me?]
Hey!
Ehi!
[Hey!]
And though we know he washes well
Magari trovi disarmante
[Maybe you can find disarming]
He always ends up sort of smelly
quell’odore un po' ruspante
[smell a little' free-range]
But you'll never meet a fella
Ma un ragazzo più stupendo e
[But a boy more beautiful and]
Who's as sensitive and sweet
dolce, credici, non c'è!
[sweet, believe us, there is!]
That's nice, but...
Perfetto, ma...
[Perfect, but...]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
C'è qualche aspetto da sistemare,
[Is there anything to be fixed,]
So, he's got a few flaws
ma ciascuno ne ha!
[but each one has!]
Like his peculiar brain, dear
La fissazione perenne
[The perennial fixation]
His thing with the reindeer
Che ha per le renne
[Who for reindeer]
That's a little outside of nature's laws
Con un po' di pazienza passerà.
[With a little' patience will.]
This is not about me!
Non parlano di me!
[Do not talk about me!]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
C'è qualche aspetto da sistemare,
[Is there anything to be fixed,]
But this we're certain of
ma fidati di noi
[but trust us]
You can fix this fixer-upper up
Ogni ostacolo si supera,
[Each obstacle is overcome,]
With a little bit of love
Con l’amore tra di voi.
[With the love between you.]
Can we please just stop talking about this?
Possiamo smettere di parlare di questo?
[Can we stop talking about this?]
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
Abbiamo un problema più grave.
[We have a bigger problem.]
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Direi. Allora, cara...
[I would say. So, dear...]
Is it the way that he runs scared?
Sai che si caccia in mezzo ai guai?
[You know that you hunt in trouble?]
Or that he's socially impaired?
O è perché non parla mai?
[Or is it because no one ever talks about?]
Or that he only likes to tinkle in the woods?
La fa nel bosco quando non la tiene più.
[Ago in the woods when it holds more.]
I did not need to know that.
Preferivo non saperlo.
[I preferred not to know.]
Are you holding back your fondness
Forse non vuoi dargli un bacio,
[Maybe you do not want to kiss him,]
Due to his unmanly blondness?
perché biondo è poco macho?
[because blonde is little macho?]
Or the way he covers up that he's the honest goods?
O perché lui non si vanta delle sue virtù?
[Or because he does not boast of his virtues?]
He's just a bit of a fixer-upper
C'è qualcosina da sistemare,
[There's a little something to fix,]
He's got a couple of bugs
qualche difetto lo ha
[some fault him]
(No, I don't!) - His isolation is confirmation
(No, per niente!) - È rattristato, l'ha confermato,
[(No, not at all!) - It's sad, he confirmed,]
Of his desperation for healing hugs
cerca disperato un po' di umanità.
[looking a bit desperate' of humanity.]
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
È molto meglio di quel che sembra,
[It is much better than it sounds,]
But we know what to do
Lui ha una marcia in più!
[He has a plus!]
The way to fix up this fixer-upper
Se pure qualcosa va cambiato,
[Even if something is changed,]
Is to fix him up with you
Lo potrai cambiare tu!
[It can change you!]
Whoa!
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
Fermi, fermi. Basta ora!
[Still, still. Enough now!]
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
È fidanzata con un altro, chiaro?
[It is engaged to another, right?]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
A quanto pare c'è un altro tipo
[Apparently there is another kind]
That's a minor thing
Sembra sia così.
[It seems so.]
Her quote "engagement" is a flex arrangement
Ho visto bene o non sono insieme?
[I saw well or are not together?]
And by the way, I don't see no ring
E poi non ha nessun anello qui!
[He then has no ring here!]
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
Il fidanzato va eliminato!
[The boyfriend must be eliminated!]
Her brain's a bit betwixt
È semplice, perché,
[It's simple, because,]
Get the fiance out of the way
se, con cortesia, lo cacci via,
[if, with courtesy, send him away,]
And the whole thing will be fixed
il suo cuore è per te!
[his heart is for you!]
We're not saying you can change him
Ma non credere che cambi,
[But do not think that changes,]
'Cause people don't really change
vedrai che non accadrà.
[you'll see that it will not happen.]
We're only saying that love's a force
Ma puoi scoprire che anche lui
[But you will find out that he]
That's powerful and strange
ha molte qualita!
[It has many qualities!]
People make bad choices
Spesso i nostri errori
[Often our mistakes]
If they're mad or scared or stressed
ci procurano dei guai,
[cause us trouble,]
But throw a little love their way
Ma chi ascolta il cuore sa
[But who listens to the heart knows]
Throw a little love their way
Ma chi ascolta il cuore sa
[But who listens to the heart knows]
And you'll bring out their best
Non si sbaglia mai
[Never wrong]
True love brings out the best
Che non si sbaglia mai.
[That is never wrong.]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
Qui non c'è nessuno che sia perfetto,
[Here no one is perfect,]
That's what it's all about
Ecco la verità.
[That's the truth.]
Father! Sister! Brother!
Padre! Figlia! Fratello!
[Father! Daughter! Brother!]
We need each other to raise us up
È questo il bello!
[This is the beauty!]
And round us out
L'amore ci completerà.
[Love will be completed.]
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
Qualche problemino lo trovi sempre,
[I always find some problems,]
But when push comes to shove
Succede a tutti noi
[It happens to all of us]
The only fixer-upper fixer
Con l'amore più profondo
[With the deepest love]
That can fix a fixer-upper is...
puoi cambiare tutto il mondo se
[you can change the world if]
True, true
Tu, tu
[You, you]
True
Tu
[you]
Love!
Vuoi!
[Do you want!]
Love, love, love
Love! True love
Solamente se...
[Only if...]
True
Tu...
[You...]
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
Vuoi tu Anna prendere Kristoff come tuo trollegittimo...
[Will you take Anna Kristoff as your troll-legitimate...]
Wait, what? - You're getting married.
Aspetta, che? - Vi state sposando.
[Wait, what? - You're married.]
Love!
... puoi!
[... You can!]
Anna?
She's as cold as ice.
È fredda come il ghiaccio.
[It's cold as ice.]
There is strange magic here.
C'è una strana magia, qui.
[There is a strange magic, here.]
Granpabbie. - Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Granpapà! - Presto, presto. Portala qui da me.
[Granpapà! - Hurry, hurry. Take it from me here.]
Anna, your life is in danger.
Anna, la tua vita è in pericolo.
[Anna, your life is in danger.]
There is ice in your heart put there by your sister.
Tua sorella ha messo ghiaccio nel tuo cuore.
[Your sister put ice in your heart.]
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
Se non viene tolto, il ghiaccio ti congelerà. Per sempre.
[If not removed, the ice will freeze. Forever.]
What? No.
Cosa? No.
[What? No.]
But you can remove it, right?
Ma tu puoi toglierlo, vero?
[But you can take it off, right?]
I cannot
Non posso.
[I can not.]
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
Mi dispiace, Kristoff.
[Sorry, Kristoff.]
If it was her head, that would be easy.
Se fosse nella testa, sarebbe facile.
[If it was in my head, it would be easy.]
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
Ma solo un atto di vero amore scioglie un cuore di ghiaccio.
[But only an act of true love melt a heart of ice.]
An act of true love?
Un atto di vero amore?
[An act of true love?]
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
Il bacio del vero amore, magari?
[The kiss of true love, maybe?]
(Something's wrong. Are you all right?)
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Anna, dobbiamo riportarti da Hans.
[Anna, we have to bring you back to Hans.]
Hans.
Pull us out, Sven.
Tiraci fuori, Sven.
[Get us out, Sven.]
Olaf, come on!
Olaf, andiamo!
[Olaf, come on!]
I'm coming!
Ecco mi!
[That's me!]
Let's go kiss Hans!
Andiamo a baciare Hans!
[We're going to kiss Hans!]
Who is this Hans?
A chi è questo Hans?
[Who is this Hans?]
We are here to find Princess Anna.
Siamo qui per la principessa Anna.
[We are here to Princess Anne.]
Be on guard, but no harm is to come to the queen.
State in guardia, ma nessuno tocchi la regina.
[Be on guard, but nobody touches the queen.]
Do you understand?
Sono stato è chiaro?
[I was clear?]
Yes, Your Grace.
The queen.
La regina.
[Queen.]
Go, go! Come on!
Via, via! Andiamo!
[Away! Come on!]
There!
Up there!
Lassù!
[Up there!]
Come on!
Andiamo!
[Come on!]
We got her.
Eccola!
[Here it is!]
No. Please.
No, vi prego.
[No, please.]
Go around. Toss it.
Dall'altra parte. Prendi.
[On the other side. Get.]
Stay away!
State lontani!
[Stay away!]
Look out!
Attenzione!
[Attention!]
Fire! Fire!
Fuoco! Fuoco!
[Fire! Fire!]
Get her!
Ah!
Come on!
Andiamo!
[Come on!]
Grab his arm.
Aim...
This way, this way!
Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Regina Elsa!
[Queen Elsa!]
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
Non siate il mostro che tutti temono.
[Do not be the monster that everyone fears.]
Oh, no. What have... What have I done?
Oh, no. Che cosa ho fatto?
[Oh no. What have I done?]
Why did you bring me here?
Perché mi hai portata qui?
[Why did you bring me here?]
I couldn't just let them kill you.
Non potevo farvi uccidere.
[I could not kill you.]
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
Ma io sono un pericolo per Arendelle. Va' da Anna.
[But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Goes' from Anna.]
Anna has not returned.
Anna non è tornata.
[Anna has not returned.]
If you would just stop the winter.
Maestà, ??? l'inverno.
[Majesty,??? winter.]
Bring back summer, please.
Riportate l'estate. Vi prego.
[Given the summer. Please.]
Don't you see?
Non vedi?
[Do not you see?]
I can't.
Non posso.
[I can not.]
You have to tell them to let me go.
Digli di lasciarmi andare.
[Tell him to let me go.]
I will do what I can.
Farò il possibile.
[I will do my best.]
Just hang in there.
Resisti.
[Hold on.]
Come on, buddy, faster!
Forza, Sven, più veloce!
[Strength, Sven, faster!]
Oh, boy!
Oh, mammina.
[Oh, Mommy.]
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
Ci vediamo al castello!
[See you at the castle!]
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
Sta' nascosto, Olaf.
[Is' hidden, Olaf.]
I will!
Sarà fatto!
[It will be done!]
Hello! - It's alive!
It's Princess Anna!
È la principessa Anna.
[Is Princess Anne.]
Are you gonna be okay?
Tu, starai bene?
[You, you'll be fine?]
Don't worry about me.
Non pensare a me.
[Do not think about me.]
Anna!
You had us worried sick. My Lady.
Get her warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.
Tenete al caldo. E trovate il principe Hans, subito.
[Keep warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.]
We will. Thank you.
Lo faremo. Grazie.
[We will do it. Thank you.]
Make sure she's safe.
Oh, you poor girl, you're freezing.
Povera piccola, siete gelata.
[Poor child, you are frozen.]
Oh, let's get you inside now and get you warm.
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
You cannot risk going out there again.
Non potete rischiare.
[You can not risk it.]
If anything happens to her...
Se le accadesse qualcosa...
[If something happened...]
If anything happens to the princess,
Se accade qualcosa alla Principessa...
[If something happens to the Princess...]
you are all Arendelle has left.
ad Arendelle non rimarrete che voi.
[to Arendelle that you will not be.]
He's in here.
Principe è qui.
[Prince is here.]
Prince Hans.
Principe Hans.
[Prince Hans.]
Anna.
You're so cold.
Sei ghiacciata.
[Six iced.]
Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
Hans devi baciarmi. - Che cosa?
[Hans have to kiss me. - What?]
Now! Now! - Slow down.
Subito, subito!
[Immediately, immediately!]
We'll give you two some privacy.
Vi lasciamo soli un momento.
[We leave you just a moment.]
What happened out there?
Cosa è successo?
[What happened?]
Elsa struck me with her powers.
Elsa mi ha colpita con i suoi poteri.
[Elsa hit me with his powers.]
You said she'd never hurt you.
Dicevi che non ti avrebbe fatto nulla.
[You said you would not have done anything.]
I was wrong.
Anna.
She froze my heart,
Mi ha gelato il cuore.
[I froze my heart.]
and only an act of true love can save me.
Solo un atto di vero amore può salvarmi.
[Only an act of true love can save me.]
A true love's kiss.
Il bacio del vero amore!
[The kiss of true love!]
Oh, Anna.
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
What?
You said you did.
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
I didn't stand a chance.
I knew I would have to marry into the throne somewhere.
What... What are you talking about?
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
But you...
You were so desperate for love,
you were willing to marry me just like that.
I figured after we married,
I would have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
Hans! No. Stop.
But then, she doomed herself,
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
Please.
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
and bring back summer.
You're no match for Elsa.
No, you're no match for Elsa.
I, on the other hand,
am the hero who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
You won't get away with this.
Oh...
I already have.
Please, somebody, help.
Please. Please.
It's getting colder by the minute.
If we don't do something soon, we'll all freeze to death.
Prince Hans.
Princess Anna is...
Dead.
What?
What happened to her?
She was killed...
... by Queen Elsa.
No!
Her own sister.
At least we got to say our marriage vows
before she died in my arms.
There can be no doubt now.
Queen Elsa is a monster,
and we are all in grave danger.
Prince Hans,
Arendelle looks to you.
With a heavy heart,
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason.
And sentence her to death.
Hurry up!
She's dangerous.
Move quickly. Careful!
It won't open! It's frozen shut.
Put your back into it!
Come on! Push!
What is it, buddy?
Hey, watch it.
What's wrong with you?
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
Stop it! Put me down!
No, Sven!
We're not going back.
She's with her true love.
What the...
Anna!
Come on! Come on, boy.
Help.
Anna!
Oh, no.
Olaf?
Olaf. Get away from there.
Wow!
So, this is heat.
I love it.
Ooh! But don't touch it.
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
But we ran all the way here.
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here. You'll melt.
I am not leaving here until
we find some other act of true love to save you.
Do you happen to have any ideas?
I don't even know what love is.
That's okay, I do.
Love is
putting someone else's needs before yours.
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans and left you forever.
Kristoff loves me?
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
Olaf, you're melting.
Some people are worth melting for.
Just maybe not right this second.
Don't worry, I've got it.
We're gonna get through... Oh, wait.
Hang on, I'm getting something.
It's Kristoff and Sven!
They're coming back this way.
They... They are?
Wow! He's really moving fast.
I guess I was wrong.
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
No, no, no! You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
I need to get to Kristoff.
Why?
Oh, I know why!
There's your act of true love right there!
Riding across the fjords like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
Come on!
Look out!
Oh!
Uh... Back this way.
We're trapped.
Oh...
Whoa!
Slide, Anna!
We made it!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, buddy, faster.
Kristoff!
Keep going!
Come on!
No.
Whoa!
Sven!
Good boy.
Kristoff.
Kristoff...
Anna!
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Just take care of my sister.
Your sister?
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
She said that you froze her heart.
No.
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
Your sister is dead.
Because of you.
No.
Kristoff.
Anna!
Elsa?
No!
Anna!
Oh. Anna!
No, no!
Please, no.
Anna?
Oh, Elsa.
You sacrificed yourself for me?
I love you.
"An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart."
"Love will thaw."
Love. Of course.
Elsa?
Love!
I knew you could do it.
Hands down, this is the best day of my life.
And, quite possibly, the last.
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Oh, Oh, Oh!
My own personal flurry!
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
But she froze your heart.
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
Wonderful!
Setting course, sir.
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
We shall see what his twelve big brothers think of his behavior.
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
This is unacceptable.
I am a victim of fear. I've been traumatized.
Ah! My neck hurts.
Is there a doctor that I could see?
And I demand to see the queen!
Oh. I have a message from the queen.
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever
"no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown."
"Weselton."
It's Weselton!
Come on, come on, come on!
Okay, okay, here I come.
Pole! - Whoops! Sorry.
Okay, Okay.
Here we are. Oh!
I owe you a sled.
Are you serious? - Yes!
And it's the latest model.
No, I can't accept this.
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
She's named you the Official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
What? That's not a thing. - Oh, sure it is.
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
Like it? I love it!
Whoa.
I could kiss you!
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd...
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
Wait, what?
We may.
Summer!
Ooh...
Hello.
Are you ready?
Ice!
Swing me.
Ooh...
I like the open gates.
We are never closing them again.
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful, but you know I don't skate.
Come on! You can do it!
Look out. Reindeer coming through.
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
Hey, guys!
That's it, Olaf.
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.