Frozen
O Reino De Gelo
[The Kingdom Of Ice]
Born of cold and winter air
O Inverno gela o ar
Winter freezes the air
And mountain rain combining
E a chuva na montanha.
and the rain in the mountain
This icy force both foul and fair
Nasceu uma força de arrasar
A blowing force was born
Has a frozen heart worth mining
Que no coração se entranha.
that burrows into the heart
So cut through the heart
E os corações
And the hearts
Cold and clear
vai cortar.
it will cut.
Strike for love and strike for fear
Trabalhamos sem parar,
We work, non-stop
See the beauty sharp and sheer
A beleza vai mostrar
The beauty it will show
Split the ice apart
Gelo dividir
Split the ice
And break the frozen heart
E o coração partir.
And break the heart
Watch your step! Let it go!
Tem cuidado! Deixa ir!
Be careful! Let it go!
Hup, ho
Watch your step! Let it go!
Tem cuidado! Deixa ir!
Be careful! Let it go!
Beautiful! Powerful!
Fabuloso! Poderoso!
Fabulous! Powerful!
Dangerous! Cold!
Perigoso! Frio!
Ice has a magic can't be controlled
E a magia que há no gelo
And the magic that is in the ice
Stronger than one
Mata um homem,
Kills a man
Stronger than ten
E bate dez,
Knocks back ten,
Stronger than a hundred men!
É mais forte do que cem.
it's stronger than a hundred!
Oh!
Born of cold and winter air
O Inverno gela o ar
Winter freezes the air
And mountain rain combining
E a chuva na montanha.
and the rain in the mountain
This icy force both foul and fair
Nasceu uma força de arrasar
A blowing force was born
Has a frozen heart worth mining
Que no coração se entranha.
that burrows into the heart
Cut through the heart
E os corações
And the hearts
Cold and clear
vai cortar.
it will cut
Strike for love and strike for fear
Trabalhamos sem parar
We work, non-stop
There's beauty and there's danger here
Perigos e beleza em par
Equal danger and beauty
Split the ice apart
Gelo dividir
Split the ice
Beware the frozen heart
E o coração partir.
And break the heart
Come on, Sven.
Anda, Sven!
[Come on, Sven!]
Elsa. Psst!
Elsa!
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
Acorda! Acorda!
[Wake up! Wake up!]
Anna, go back to sleep.
Anna, volta para a cama!
[Anna, back to bed!]
I just can't.
Não posso.
[I can not.]
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
O céu está acordado, por isso, estou acordada.
[The sky is awake, so I agreed.]
So, we have to play.
Temos de ir brincar.
[We have to go play.]
Go play by yourself.
Vai brincar sozinha.
[Will play alone.]
Do you want to build a snowman?
Queres fazer bonecos de neve?
[You want to make snowmen?]
Come on, come on, come on!
Vamos, vamos. Vamos!
[Come on. Come on!]
Do the magic! Do the magic!
Faz magia! Faz magia!
[Does Magic! Does Magic!]
Oh...
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
Preparada?
[Ready?]
This is amazing!
Isto é fantástico!
[This is fantastic!]
Watch this!
Vê isto!
[Watch this!]
Hi, I'm Olaf, and I like warm hugs.
Anna, sou o Olaf, e adoro abraços calorosos.
[Anna, I'm Olaf, and I love warm hugs.]
I love you, Olaf!
Adoro-te, Olaf!
[I love you, Olaf!]
Olaf...
Tickle bumps!
Faz cócegas.
[It tickles.]
Oh!
Hang on!
Segura-te!
[Hold on!]
Catch me!
Apanha-me!
[Catch me!]
Gotcha!
Again!
Outra vez!
[Another time!]
Wait!
Espera!
[Wait!]
- Whoo-hoo! - Slow down!
Mais devagar!
[Slower!]
Whoo!
Anna!
Mama! Papa!
Mamã! Papá!
[Mom! Papa!]
No, no...
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
Está tudo bem, Anna. Eu cuido de ti.
[It's okay, Anna. I care for you.]
Elsa, what have you done?
Elsa, o que fizeste?
[Elsa, what did you do?]
This is getting out of hand.
Isto está a ficar descontrolado!
[This is getting out of control!]
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
Foi um acidente. Desculpa, Anna.
[It was an accident. Sorry, Anna.]
Oh. She's ice cold.
Ela está gelada.
[It is cold.]
I know where we have to go.
Sei onde temos de ir.
[I know where we need to go.]
Ice?
Gelo?
[Ice?]
Faster, Sven.
Mais depressa, Sven!
[Faster, Sven!]
Sven!
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
Por favor, ajudem-nos! A minha filha!
[Please help us! My daughter!]
It's the king.
É Sua Majestade, o Rei!
[It is His Majesty the King!]
Trolls?
Shush! I'm trying to listen.
Calado! Estou a tentar ouvir.
[Silent! I'm trying to listen.]
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Que fofinhos. Vou ficar convosco.
[So cute. I'll stay with you.]
Your Majesty.
Vossa Majestade!
[Your Majesty!]
Born with the powers, or cursed?
Nascida com poderes ou amaldiçoada?
[Born with powers or cursed?]
Born. And they're getting stronger.
Nascida. E estão a ficar mais fortes.
[Born. And they are getting stronger.]
Here, here.
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
Teve sorte por não ser o coração.
[We were lucky not to be the heart.]
The heart is not so easily changed.
O coração não muda assim tão facilmente,
[The heart does not change so easily,]
But the head can be persuaded.
mas a cabeça pode ser persuadida.
[but the head can be persuaded.]
Do what you must.
Faça o que tem de fazer!
[Do what you have to do!]
I recommend we remove all magic.
Recomendo remover toda a magia,
[I recommend removing all the magic,]
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
até mesmo a recordação da magia, por segurança.
[even the memory of the magic for safety.]
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
Mas não se preocupem, vou deixar a diversão.
[But do not worry, I'll leave the fun.]
She will be okay.
Ela ficará bem.
[She'll be fine.]
But she won't remember I have powers?
Mas não se vai lembrar de que eu tenho poderes?
[But if you will not remember that I have powers?]
It's for the best.
É pelo melhor.
[It's for the best.]
Listen to me, Elsa. Your power will only grow.
Escuta-me, Elsa, O teu poder vai crescer.
[Listen to me, Elsa, Your power will grow.]
There is beauty in it...
Existe beleza nele.
[There is beauty in it.]
But also great danger.
Mas também um grande perigo.
[But also a great danger.]
You must learn to control it.
Tens de aprender a controlá-lo.
[You must learn to control it.]
Fear will be your enemy.
O medo será o teu inimigo.
[Fear is your enemy.]
No!
Não!
[No!]
We'll protect her.
Nós vamos protegê-la.
[We will protect her.]
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
Ela aprenderá a controlá-lo.
[She will learn to control it.]
Until then...
Até então,
[Until then,]
We'll lock the gates.
selamos os portões,
[We sealed the gates,]
We'll reduce the staff.
reduzimos os empregados.
[reduced employees.]
We will limit her contact with people,
Limitamos o contacto com as pessoas.
[Limit contact with people.]
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
Manteremos os poderes dela escondidos de todos,
[We keep the powers hidden it all,]
Including Anna.
incluindo da Anna.
[including Anna.]
Elsa?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Vem fazer bonecos de neve
Come and make snowmen
Come on, let's go and play
Há um que é só teu
There is one who is just yours
I never see you any more
Eu tenho tanto para contar,
I have so much to tell,
Come out the door
Deixa-me entrar
Let me in
It's like you've gone away
O que é que aconteceu?
What has happened?
We used to be best buddies, and now we're not
Nós éramos amigas, mas já não somos
We were friends, but we're not any more
I wish you would tell me why
Tu diz-me qual a razão!
Tell me the reason!
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Vem fazer bonecos de neve
Come and make snowmen
It doesn't have to be a snowman
Podem nem ser bonecos de neve.
They don't have to be snowmen
Go away, Anna.
Vai embora, Anna.
Leave, Anna.
Okay, bye
Vou então
I will then
The gloves will help.
As luvas vão ajudar-te.
The gloves will help you.
See? Conceal it.
Vês? Esconder...
See? Conceal...
Don't feel it.
Conter.
Contain.
Don't let it show.
E eles não saberão.
And they won't know.
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Vem fazer bonecos de neve
Come and make snowmen
Or ride our bike around the halls?
Na bicicleta passear
Take a bicycle trip
I think some company is overdue
A tua companhia quero ter
I want your company
I've started talking to the pictures on the walls
Até com quadros na parede ando a falar!
I have even been talking with wall paintings!
Hang in there, Joan.
Aguenta, Joan.
Hang on, Joan.
It gets a little lonely, all these empty rooms
Eu sinto-me sozinha, salas sem ninguém
I feel so lonely, those empty rooms
Just watching the hours tick by
As horas vejo a passar.
I see the hours pass.
I'm scared.
Isto assusta-me
This scares me
It's getting stronger!
Está a ficar mais forte.
It's getting stronger.
Getting upset only makes it worse. Calm down.
Enervares-te só vai piorar as coisas. Acalma-te.
Getting nervous will only make things worse. Calm down.
No! Don't touch me!
Não, não me toques!
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
Peço-te, ainda te magoar.
Please! I could hurt you.
See you in two weeks!
Vemo-nos daqui a duas semanas!
Do you have to go?
Tens que ir mesmo?
Do you really have to go?
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Não te vai acontecer nada, Elsa.
Nothing will happen to you, Elsa.
Your Highness.
Elsa?
Please, I know you're in there
Vá, sei que estás aí
C'mon, I know you're there
People are asking where you've been
"Onde estarás", estão a falar
"Where could you be", people are saying
They say "Have courage", and I'm trying to
Dizem coragem, e eu bem tento ter
They say be brave, and I try to be
I'm right out here for you
Vou-te proteger,
I will protect you,
Just let me in
Deixa-me entrar!
let me in!
We only have each other; it's just you and me
Nós estamos sós no mundo; só te tenho a ti
We're alone in the world; all I have is you
What are we gonna do?
Não quero estar tão só
I don't want to be so lonely
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Vem fazer bonecos de neve...
Come and make snowmen...
All ashore!
Welcome to Arendelle!
Bem-vindos a Arendelle!
[Welcome to Arendelle!]
Ahh, merci, monsieur.
Obrigado, senhor!
[Thank you sir!]
Watch your step, please.
Atenção onde pisa.
[Warning your step.]
The gates will be opening soon.
Os portões abrem em breve.
[The gates open soon.]
Why do I have to wear this?
Porque tenho de usar isto?
[Why should I use it?]
Because the queen has come of age.
Porque a Rainha atingiu a maioridade.
[Because the Queen has come of age.]
It's Coronation Day!
É o dia da coroação!
[It is the day of the coronation!]
That's not my fault.
Não tenho culpa disso.
[I can not help it.]
What do you want, Sven?
Que queres, Sven?
[What do you, Sven?]
"Give me a snack."
Dá-me um petisco!
[Give me a snack!]
What's the magic word?
Qual é a palavra mágica?
[What's the magic word?]
"Please."
Por favor!
[Please!]
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
Partilha!
[Share!]
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
Não acredito que vão finalmente abrir os portões!
[I do not think that will finally open the gates!]
And for a whole day! Faster, Percy!
Por um dia inteiro! Mais depressa, Persi!
[For a whole day! Faster, Persi!]
Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
Arendelle, o nosso parceiro comercial mais misterioso.
[Arendelle, our most mysterious business partner.]
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets and exploit your riches.
Abram esses portões para poder descobrir os vossos segredos e explorar as vossas riquezas.
[Open these gates in order to discover your secrets and explore riches.]
Did I say that out loud?
Disse isto em voz alta?
[He said that out loud?]
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait to see the queen and the princess.
Os meus olhos mal podem esperar para ver a Rainha e a Princesa.
[My eyes can not wait to see the Queen and the Princess.]
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
Ouvi dizer que são absolutamente encantadoras.
[I hear you are absolutely charming.]
I bet they are beautiful.
Aposto que são lindas!
[I bet you are beautiful!]
Princess Anna?
Princesa Anna?
[Princess Anna?]
Huh? Yeah?
Sim?
[Yup?]
Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
Desculpe acordá-la.
[Sorry to wake her.]
No, no, no, you didn't.
Não, não me...
[No, not me...]
I've been up for hours.
Estou acordada há horas.
[I'm awake for hours.]
Who is it?
Quem está aí?
[Who's there?]
Still me, ma'am.
Continuo a ser eu.
[I continue to be me.]
The gates will open soon. Time to get ready.
Os portões abrem em breve. É hora de se preparar.
[The gates open soon. It's time to prepare.]
Of course.
Claro!
[Of course!]
Ready for what?
Preparar-me para quê?
[Prepare me for what?]
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
Para a coroação da sua irmã.
[For the coronation of her sister.]
My sister's corneration.
A coroação da minha irmã.
[The coronation of my sister.]
It's Coronation Day!
É o dia da coroação!
The window is open!
Vou ver se a porta
I will go see if the door
So's that door!
já se abriu!
has already been opened!
I didn't know they did that any more
Um dia como este não se viu
A day like this hasn't been seen
Who knew we owned 8,000 salad plates?
Que grande o serviço de jantar
What a great dinner service!
For years I've roamed these empty halls
Tão só andei entre paredes
So lonely I walked between walls
Why have a ballroom with no balls?
Para quê o salão se não há bailes?
Why the parlour if there are no balls?
Finally, they're opening up the gates!
Os portões irão deixar entrar
The gates will allow to enter...
There'll be actual, real, live people
Tanta gente que não conheço
... so many people that I do not know
It'll be totally strange
Será tão estranho e excitante
It will be so odd and exciting
But wow! Am I so ready for this change!
Mas eu estou pronta, para seguir em frente.
But I am ready to keep moving forward
'Cause for the first time in forever
Pois pela primeira vez para sempre
Because for the first time in forever
There'll be music, there'll be light
Ouço a música que há no ar
I hear the music that is in the air
For the first time in forever
Pela primeira vez para sempre
I'll be dancing through the night
Há uma noite para dançar
There is a night to dance
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
Não sei se é emoção ou se são gases
I don't know if it's emotion or gases
But I'm somewhere in that zone
Mas tem algo bem melhor
But it has something much better
'Cause for the first time in forever
Pois pela primeira vez para sempre
Because for the first time in forever
I won't be alone
A vida é a maior.
Life is bigger.
I can't wait to meet everyone!
Mal posso esperar para conhecer toda a gente.
What if I meet The One?
E se eu conhecer "o tal"?
And what if I meet "the one"?
Tonight, imagine me gown and all
À noite um vestido vou usar
I will wear the dress at night
Fetchingly draped against the wall
Com ornamentos de encantar
With enchanting ornaments
The picture of sophisticated grace
Sou toda sofisticação e graça
I am all sophistication and grace
I suddenly see him standing there
Então vejo que ele está ali
Then I see that he is there
A beautiful stranger, tall and fair
É alto e belo, como eu vi
He is tall and beautiful, like I saw
I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face!
Não vai ficar comida nesta taça
There won't be any food left in this bowl
But then we laugh and talk all evening
Nós vamos rir e falar muito
We will laugh and talk a lot
Which is totally bizarre
Sei que soa um pouco estranho
I know it sounds a bit odd
Nothing like the life I've led so far
Toda a minha vida vai mudar!
All my life is going to change!
For the first time in forever
Pela primeira vez para sempre
There'll be magic, there'll be fun
Há magia e diversão
There is magic and fun
For the first time in forever
Pela primeira vez para sempre
I could be noticed by someone
Não viverei da ilusão
I will not live in illusion
And I know it is totally crazy
Sei que não é bem o mais sensato
I know it's not quite the wisest
To dream I'd find romance
Sonhar com o amor
To dream with love
But for the first time in forever
Mas pela primeira vez para sempre
At least I've got a chance!
Está tudo a meu favor.
Everything is in my favor
Don't let them in
Não vão entrar,
They will not enter,
Don't let them see
Não podem ver
They cannot see
Be the good girl you always have to be
Sê a menina que tu tens de ser
Be the girl you have to be
Conceal, don't feel
Esconder, conter
Hide, contain
Put on a show
Ouve a razão
Listen to the reason
Make one wrong move and everyone will know
Um passo errado e todos saberão
A wrong step and everyone will know
But it's only for today
Hoje tenho de aguentar
Today I have to endure
It's only for today
Eu tenho de aguentar!
I have to endure!
It's agony to wait
Tenho que esperar
I have to wait
It's agony to wait
Tenho que esperar
Have to wait
Tell the guards to open up
Abram os portões
Open the gates...
The gate
de par em par!
... wide!
The gate
Em par!
Wide!
For the first time in forever
Pela primeira vez para sempre
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Não vão entrar, não podem ver
They will not enter, they cannot see
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of
Eu tenho tudo o que eu sonhei
I have everything I've dreamed
Be the good girl you always have to be
A menina que esperam tu vais ser
You will be the girl they expect you to be
A chance to change my lonely world
Num mundo novo viverei
I will live in a new world
Conceal
Esconder
Hide
A chance to find true love
O amor encontrarei
I will find love
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Tens de esconder, ou saberão
You have to hide, or they will know
I know it all ends tomorrow
E amanhã tudo acaba
And tomorrow everything ends
So it has to be today!
Hoje, eu vou aproveitar
Today, I will enjoy [it]
'Cause for the first time in forever
Pois pela primeira vez para sempre
Because for the first time in forever
For the first time in forever
Pela primeira vez para sempre
Nothing's in my way!
Não me vão parar!
They won't stop me!
Hey!
Então!
[So!]
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Peço desculpa. Estás ferida?
[I apologize. Are you hurt?]
Hey.
Uh... No, no, I'm okay.
Não, não, estou bem.
[No, no, I'm fine.]
Are you sure?
Tens a certeza?
[Are you sure?]
Yeah. I just wasn't looking where I was going.
Sim, não vi onde pus os pés, mas estou óptima.
[Yes, I saw where I stepped, but I'm fine.]
But I'm great, actually.
A sério.
[Seriously.]
Oh... Thank goodness.
Ainda bem.
[Well yet.]
Oh! Uh...
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Príncipe Hans das Ilhas do Sul.
[Prince Hans of South Islands.]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Princesa Anna de Arendelle.
[Princess Anna of Arendelle.]
"Princess"? My Lady.
"Princesa"?
["Princess"?]
Oh!
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Um... Whew.
Hi. Again.
Olá, outra vez.
[Hello again.]
Oh, boy!
Caneco!
[Caneco!]
This is awkward.
Foi desastrado.
[It was awkward.]
Not "You're awkward", but just because we're...
Não és tu. Mas nós, eu...
[It is not you. But we, I...]
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous. Wait, what?
Foi desastrado. Tu és lindo. Espera, o quê?
[It was awkward. You are beautiful. Wait, what?]
I'd like to formally apologize
As minhas desculpas formais
[My formal apology]
for hitting the princess of Arendelle with my horse.
por bater na Princesa de Arendelle com o meu cavalo.
[By hitting the Arendelle princess with my horse.]
And for every moment after.
E pelo que aconteceu a seguir.
[And what happened next.]
No! No, no. It's fine.
Não, não há problema.
[No, no problem.]
I'm not that princess.
Não sou essa princesa.
[I'm not this princess.]
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
Se batesse na minha irmã Elsa,
[If knocked on my sister Elsa,]
it would be... Yeesh!
seria...
[It would be...]
Because, you know...
Porque sabes...
[Because you know...]
Hello.
Olá.
[Hello.]
But, lucky you,
Mas estás com sorte,
[But you're in luck,]
It's just me.
sou apenas eu.
[just me.]
"Just" you?
Apenas tu?
[You alone?]
The bells. The coronation.
Os sinos. A coroação.
[The bells. The crowning.]
I better go.
É melhor ir embora.
[I gotta go.]
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Tenho de ir. É melhor ir.
[I have to go. You'd better go.]
Bye!
Adeus!
[Bye!]
Oh, no. Oh!
Oh, não.
[Oh no.]
Your Majesty, the gloves.
Sua Majestade, as luvas.
[His Majesty the gloves.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
Rainha Elsa de Arendelle.
[Queen Elsa Arendelle.]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
Rainha Elsa de Arendelle!
[Queen Elsa Arendelle!]
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
A Rainha Elsa de Arendelle!
[The Queen Elsa Arendelle!]
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
A Princesa Anna de Arendelle!
[Princess Anna of Arendelle!]
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Para ali? Tem a certeza?
[For there? Are you sure?]
Because I don't think I'm supposed to...
Acho que não é suposto...
[I think it's not supposed to...]
Oh. Okay.
Está bem.
[Okay.]
Hi.
Olá.
[Hello.]
"Hi" me? Oh...
Olá para mim?
[Hello to me?]
Um... Hi.
Olá.
[Hello.]
You look beautiful.
Estás linda.
[You look beautiful.]
Thank you. You look beautiful-ler.
Obrigada. Tu estás maior.
[Thanks. You're bigger.]
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
Não é maior, percebes. Não pareces maior,
[Is not greater, you know. No bigger seem,]
But more beautiful.
mas sim mais bonita.
[but more beautiful.]
Thank you.
Obrigada.
[Thanks.]
So...
Então...
[So...]
This is what a party looks like.
uma festa é assim?
[a party like this?]
It's warmer than I thought.
É mais acolhedor do que pensava.
[It is more welcoming than I thought.]
What is that amazing smell?
Que cheiro maravilhoso é este?
[That wonderful smell?]
Chocolate.
Your Majesty.
Vossa Majestade,
[Your Majesty,]
The Duke of Weaseltown.
o Duque de Weaseltown.
[the Duke of Weaseltown.]
"Weselton"! Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
Weselton. Duque de Weselton, Vossa Majestade.
[Weselton. Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.]
As your closest partner in trade it seems only fitting
Como seu parceiro comercial mais próximo, parece-me adequado
[Like its closest trading partner, it seems appropriate]
that I offer you your first dance as queen.
oferecer-lhe a sua primeira dança como Rainha.
[offer you your first dance as Queen.]
One-two, and jump.
Uh...
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
Obrigada, mas não danço.
[Thanks, but no dance.]
Oh...
But my sister does.
Mas a minha irmã dança.
[But my sister dance.]
What? - Oh! Lucky you.
Sorte a tua.
[Lucky for you.]
Oh, I don't think...
Acho que não...
[I think not...]
If you swoon, let me know. I'll catch you.
Se desmaiares, avisa-me que eu apanho-te.
[If desmaiares, let me know I'll get you.]
Sorry.
Desculpa.
[Excuse.]
Like an agile peacock.
Ágil como um pavão.
[Agile as a peacock.]
Ow! Ow.
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
Por falar nisso, é óptimo os portões estarem abertos.
[By the way, it's great gates are opened.]
Why did they shut them in the first place?
Afinal, por que os fecharam?
[After all, why they shut them?]
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
Sabes a razão?
[You know why?]
No.
Não.
[Do not.]
All right. Hang on!
Está bem, segura-te.
[All right, hold up.]
They don't call me the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
Não é sem razão que me chamam o pequeno mergulhador.
[No wonder they call me the little diver.]
Oh-ho!
Like a chicken with the face of a monkey, I fly.
Como uma galinha com cara de macaco... eu voo.
[Like a chicken with monkey face... I fly.]
Let me know when you're ready
Avisa-me quando estiveres
[Let me know when you are]
for another round, Milady.
pronta para outra, Senhora.
[ready for another Lady.]
Well, he was sprightly.
Ele estava enérgico.
[He was energetic.]
Especially for a man in heels.
Especialmente para um homem de saltos.
[Especially for a man jumps.]
Are you okay?
Estás bem?
[You are fine?]
I've never been better. This is so nice.
Nunca estive melhor. Isto é tão agradável.
[Never better. This is so nice.]
I wish it could be like this all the time.
Gostava que fosse sempre assim.
[I wish it were always so.]
Me, too.
Eu também.
[Me either.]
But it can't.
Mas não pode ser.
[But it can not be.]
Why not? - It just can't.
Porque não? - Simplesmente não pode!
[Why not? - It just can not!]
Excuse me for a minute.
Dá-me licença.
[Excuse me.]
I'd be honored.
Glad I caught you.
Ainda bem que te apanhei.
[Glad I caught you.]
Hans.
I often had a whole parlor to myself to slide!
Geralmente tenho o salão todo só para mim...
[I usually have all the room to myself...]
Oops!
Sorry.
Desculpa.
[Excuse.]
Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
Ter o teu aspecto também ajuda.
[Have your aspect also helps.]
Ah.
What's this?
O que é isto?
[What is this?]
Uh, I was born with it.
Nasci com isso,
[I was born with it,]
Although, I dreamed I was kissed by a troll.
embora tenha sonhado ter sido beijada por um troll.
[although it has dreamed of being kissed by a troll.]
I like it.
Gosto dela.
[I like her.]
Yeah, the whole thing.
Sim, tudo!
[Yes everything!]
You got it.
Isso mesmo.
[That's it.]
Okay, wait, wait. So, you have how many brothers?
Espera lá. Tens quantos irmãos?
[Wait. You have how many brothers?]
Twelve older brothers.
Doze irmãos mais velhos.
[Twelve older brothers.]
Three of them pretended I was invisible, literally, for two years.
Três deles fingiram que eu era invisível. Literalmente, durante dois anos.
[Three of them pretended I was invisible. Literally, for two years.]
That's horrible.
Isso é horrível.
[This is horrible.]
It's what brothers do.
É o que os irmãos fazem.
[It's what brothers do.]
And sisters.
E as irmãs também.
[And the sisters as well.]
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
A Elsa e eu éramos muito chegadas quando éramos pequenas,
[Elsa and I were very arrivals when we were little,]
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
mas depois, um dia ela afastou-me e,
[but then one day she pushed me and,]
and I never knew why.
nunca soube a razão.
[I never knew the reason.]
I would never shut you out.
Eu nunca te iria afastar.
[I would never go away from you.]
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
Deixas-me dizer uma parvoíce?
[Will you let me tell you silly?]
I love crazy.
Eu adoro parvoíces.
[I love nonsense.]
All my life has been a series of doors in my face
Toda vida tive portas fechadas na cara
[All life had closed doors in the face]
And then suddenly I bump into you
E então de repente apareces tu.
[And then suddenly you show up.]
I was thinking the same thing, because, like...
Estava a pensar a mesma coisa porque...
[I was thinking the same thing because...]
I've been searching my whole life to find my own place
Eu procuro um lugar onde o mundo pare
[I look for a place where the world stops]
And maybe it's the party talking, or the chocolate fondue
Será o efeito dessa festa, ou será o fondue?
[It will be the effect of this party, or will the fondue?]
But with you
Mas és tu
[But thou,]
But with you I found my place
Mas és tu que o mundo paras
[But it is you that the world paras]
I see your face
Que o mundo paras
[The world paras]
And it's nothing like I've ever known before
Nunca senti algo assim, isto é maior
[I've never felt something like that, this is bigger]
Love is an open door!
A porta é o amor
[The door is love]
Love is an open door!
A porta é o amor
[The door is love]
Love is an open door
A porta é o amor
[The door is love]
With you
És tu!
[That's you!]
Love is an open door
A porta é o amor.
[The door is love.]
I mean, it's crazy
É muito estranho.
[It's very weird.]
What?
O quê?
[What?]
We finish each other's
Gostamos das mesmas...
[We like the same...]
Sandwiches
Sanduíches.
[Sandwiches.]
That's what I was gonna say!
Era o que eu ia dizer!
[That's what I was going to say!]
I've never met someone
Eu nunca conheci alguém igual a mim.
[I've never met anyone like me.]
Who thinks so much like me
Jinx! Jinx again!
Figas! Outra vez!
[Fingers crossed! Another time!]
Our mental synchronization
As mentes sincronizadas,
[The synchronized minds,]
Can have but one explanation
Só podem ser explicadas
[It can only be explained]
You and I were just meant to be
Tu e eu nós somos um só.
[You and I we are one.]
Say goodbye
Diz adeus
[says goodbye]
To the pain of the past
Ao teu triste passado
[When your sad past]
We don't have to feel it anymore
Não mais sentiremos esta dor.
[No longer feel this pain.]
Love is an open door
A porta é o amor
[The door is love]
Love is an open door!
A porta é o amor
[The door is love]
Life can be so much more
A vida tem esplendor
[Life has splendor]
With you
És tu!
[That's you!]
Love is an open
A porta é o
[The door is]
Door
Amor.
[Love.]
Can I say something crazy?
Posso dizer algo estúpido?
[Can I say something stupid?]
Will you marry me?
Casas comigo?
[Marry me?]
Can I say something even crazier?
Posso dizer algo ainda mais estúpido?
[I can say something even more stupid?]
Yes!
Sim!
[Yes!]
Coming through. Excuse me. Oh...
Com licença.
[Excuse.]
Pardon. Sorry. Oh!
Desculpe.
[Excuse me.]
Can we just get around you there?
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Obrigada. Ali está ela.
[Thanks. There she is.]
Elsa!
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
Quero dizer, Rainha. Sou eu novamente.
[I mean, Queen. I'm me again.]
May I present Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Queria apresentar-lhe o Príncipe Hans, das Ilhas do Sul.
[I wanted to introduce you to the Prince Hans, the South Sea Islanders.]
Your Majesty.
Vossa Majestade.
[Your Majesty.]
We would like...
Gostaríamos de pedir...
[We would like to ask...]
Uh, your blessing...
A sua bênção...
[Your blessing...]
Of our marriage.
Para o nosso casamento!
[For our wedding!]
Marriage? - Yes!
Casamento? - Sim!
[Marriage? - Yes!]
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Desculpa, estou confusa.
[Sorry, I'm confused.]
Well, we haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
Ainda não acertámos todos os detalhes.
[We agreed not still all the details.]
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
Vamos precisar de alguns dias para preparar a cerimónia.
[We will need a few days to prepare the ceremony.]
Of course, we'll have soup, roast, and ice cream. And then...
Como é claro, teremos que ter sopa, guisados, gelados e...
[Of course, we have to have soup, stews, ice cream and...]
Wait. Would we live here?
Espera. Podemos viver aqui?
[Wait. Can we live here?]
Here? - Absolutely!
Aqui? - Claro que sim!
[Here? - Of course I do!]
Anna!
Oh! We can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us.
Podíamos convidar os teus doze irmãos para virem viver connosco.
[We could invite your twelve brothers to come and live with us.]
What? No, no, no.
Espera. Não, não, não.
[Wait. No no no.]
Of course we have the room......
Penso que temos quartos para todos, não sei. Alguns vão...
[I think we have rooms for all do not know. Some will...]
Wait, slow down. No one's brothers are staying here.
Espera. Acalma-te.
[Wait. Calm down.]
No one is getting married.
Ninguém se vai casar.
[No one is getting married.]
Wait, what?
Espera, o quê?
[Wait, what?]
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
Posso falar contigo, por favor? A sós.
[Can I talk to you, please? Alone.]
No. Whatever you have to say, you can say to both of us.
Não. O que quer que me queiras dizer, podes dizê-lo aos dois.
[No. Whatever you want to tell me, you can say it to two.]
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
Não te podes casar com alguém que conheceste há minutos.
[You can not marry someone you met a few minutes ago.]
You can if it's true love.
Podes se for amor verdadeiro.
[You can if it is true love.]
Anna, what do you know about true love?
Anna, e o que percebes tu disso?
[Anna, and what you perceive it?]
More than you.
Mais que tu.
[More than you.]
All you know is how to shut people out.
Só sabes afastar as pessoas de ti.
[Only you know drive people away from you.]
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
Querias a minha bênção, mas a minha resposta é não.
[I wanted my blessing, but my answer is no.]
Now, excuse me.
Agora, se me dás licença.
[Now if you'll excuse me.]
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
Majestade, se me permite...
[Majesty, if I may...]
No, you may not. And I think you should go.
Não permito. Creio que deve sair.
[I do not allow. I think you should leave.]
The party is over. Close the gates.
A festa acabou. Fechem os portões.
[The party is over. Close the gates.]
Yes, Your Majesty.
Sim, Vossa Majestade.
[Yes, Your Majesty.]
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
Elsa, não. Espera.
[Elsa, no. Wait.]
Give me my glove!
Dá-me a minha luva!
[Give me my glove!]
Elsa, please, please.
Elsa, por favor.
[Elsa, please.]
I can't live like this anymore!
Já não consigo viver assim.
[I just can not live like this.]
Then leave.
Então vai-te embora.
[Then go away.]
What did I ever do to you?
Porque me tratas assim?
[Why treat me like that?]
Enough, Anna.
Basta, Anna.
[Simply, Anna.]
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
Não. Porquê? Por que é que te afastaste de mim?
[No, Why? Why put c off from me?]
Why do you shut the world out?
Por que é que afastas todos?
[Why stray from everyone?]
What are you so afraid of?
Do que tens medo?
[What are you afraid?]
I said, enough!
Eu disse, basta!
[I said, enough!]
Sorcery.
Feitiçaria!
[Witchcraft!]
I knew there was something dubious going on here.
O meu sexto sentido bem que me avisou que algo não estava bem.
[My sixth sense and who warned me that something was not right.]
Elsa.
There she is!
Ali está ela!
[There she is!]
Yes! It is her!
Sim, é mesmo ela.
[Yes, it is she.]
Queen Elsa.
Rainha Elsa!
[Queen Elsa!]
Our beautiful queen!
A nossa linda Rainha.
[Our beautiful Queen.]
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
Majestade, sente-se bem?
[Majesty feels good?]
No.
There she is! Stop her!
Ali está ela! Parem-na!
[There she is! Stop it!]
Please, just stay away from me. Stay away.
Por favor, afastem-se de mim! Afastem-se!
[Please move away from me! Get away!]
Monster. Monster!
Monstro... Monstro!
[Monster... Monster!]
Elsa!
Wait, please!
Espera, por favor!
[Wait please!]
Elsa, stop!
Elsa, pára!
[Elsa, stop!]
Anna!
No.
Não...
[Do Not...]
The fjord.
O Fiorde...
[The Fjord...]
Snow! Snow?
Neve! Neve?
[Snow! Snow?]
Yes, snow.
Sim, neve!
[Yes, snow!]
Are you all right? - No.
Estás bem? - Não.
[You are fine? - No.]
Did you know?
Sabias disto?
[Did you know that?]
No.
Não.
[Do not.]
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
Reparem, está a nevar. Está a nevar!
[Look, it's snowing. It is snowing!]
The queen has cursed this land!
A Rainha amaldiçoou esta terra!
[The Queen cursed this land!]
She must be stopped! You have to go after her.
Alguém tem que a parar! Tem que ir atrás dela!
[Someone has to stop! You have to go after her!]
Wait, no!
Espere, não!
[Wait, no!]
You! ls there sorcery in you, too?
Tu! Também és uma feiticeira?
[You! You're also a witch?]
Are you a monster, too?
Também és um monstro?
[Too are a monster?]
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
Não, não. Sou vulgar.
[No no. I am ordinary.]
That's right, she is.
Pois é vulgar.
[It is ordinary.]
In the best way.
No bom sentido.
[In the good sense.]
And my sister is not a monster.
E a minha irmã não é um monstro.
[And my sister is not a monster.]
She nearly killed me!
Quase que me matou!
[Almost killed me!]
You slipped on ice. - Her ice.
Escorregou no gelo. - No gelo dela!
[He slipped on the ice. - On ice it!]
It was an accident. She was scared.
Foi um acidente. Ela estava assustada.
[It was an accident. She was scared.]
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this.
Não foi de propósito.
[I did not mean it.]
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
A culpa foi minha. Pressionei-a.
[It was my fault. I pressed it.]
So, I'm the one
Por isso sou eu
[So am I]
that needs to go after her.
quem tem que ir à sua procura.
[who have to go looking for her.]
Bring me my horse, please.
Tragam o meu cavalo, por favor.
[Bring my horse, please.]
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
Anna, não. É muito perigoso.
[Anna, no. It's very dangerous.]
Elsa's not dangerous.
A Elsa não é perigosa.
[Elsa is not dangerous.]
I'll bring her back, and I'll make this right.
Vou buscá-la, vai tudo voltar ao que era.
[I'll get it, everything will go back to what it was.]
I'm coming with you.
Vou contigo.
[I'm going with you.]
No, I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
Não. Preciso que fiques aqui, a tomar conta de Arendelle.
[No. I need you to stay here, to take Arendelle account.]
On my honor.
Dou-te a minha palavra.
[I give you my word.]
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Príncipe Hans tomará conta do Reino.
[Prince Hans will take care of the Kingdom.]
Are you sure you can trust her?
Estás certa que podes confiar nela?
[Are you sure you can trust her?]
I don't want you getting hurt.
Não quero que te magoes.
[I do not want to get hurt.]
She's my sister.
É minha irmã.
[It is my sister.]
She would never hurt me.
Jamais me magoaria.
[I never hurt me.]
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
A neve cobre a montanha esta noite,
The snow covers the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
Mas os passos são só meus.
But the only footsteps are mine.
A kingdom of isolation,
Comigo só há solidão,
There is only the loneliness with me,
and it looks like I'm the queen
Sou rainha destes céus.
I'm the queen of these heavens.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Cá dentro a tempestade que estou a sentir
This storm that I am feeling inside
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Não a controlei, deixei-a sair.
I didn't control it, I let it out.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Não vão entrar, não podem ver!
They won't come in, they cannot see!
Be the good girl you always had to be
Sê a menina que tu tens de ser!
Be the girl you have to be!
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Esconder, conter, ou saberão.
Conceal, contain, or they will know.
Well, now they know!
Mas foi em vão!
But it was in vain!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
Can't hold it back any more!
Não vivo mais com temor.
I don't live in fear any more.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
Turn away and slam the door!
Fecha a porta, por favor!
Please close the door!
I don't care what they're going to say
Tanto faz o que vão dizer
Let the storm rage on
Venha a tempestade...
A storm comes...
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio nunca me fará estremecer.
The cold will never make me shiver.
It's funny how some distance
Eu vejo que a distância
I can see some distance
Makes everything seem small
vai tudo suavizar.
will make everything seem softer.
And the fears that once controlled me
E os medos de outros tempos
And that my old fears
Can't get to me at all!
não me vão apanhar!
won't be able to get to me!
It's time to see what I can do
Ser livre assim é mesmo bom!
Being free like this is really good!
To test the limits and break through
Ver os limites deste dom.
To test the limits of this gift.
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Sem regras sou feliz enfim!
Without rules I'm happy at last!
I'm free!
Sou sim!
Yes I am!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
I am one with the wind and sky
Este é mesmo o meu lugar.
This is where I belong.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
You'll never see me cry
Não irei mais chorar.
I won't cry any more.
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Estou aqui e vou ficar,
Here I am, and here I'll stay,
Let the storm rage on...
Venha a tempestade...
A storm comes...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
O meu poder agita o ar que entra no chão
My power stirs the air that enters the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
A minha alma brilha em espirais até mais não
My soul shines in infinite spirals
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Um pensamento tudo irá cristalizar
A thought will crystallize everything
I'm never going back
O que passou, passou.
What has passed, has passed.
The past is in the past!
Para trás não vou olhar!
I'm not looking back!
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Com o amanhã me vou erguer.
I will rise with tomorrow.
Let it go, let it go!
Já passou, já passou!
It's OK now, it's OK now!
That perfect girl is gone
Menina não vou ser.
I won't be a little girl any more.
Here I stand in the light of day
Este dia está a nascer
The dawn is coming
Let the storm rage on!
Venha a tempestade!
A storm comes!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
O frio nunca me fará estremecer.
The cold will never make me shiver.
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
Elsa, sou eu, a Anna.
[Elsa, it's me, Anna.]
your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
Uma irmã que não queria que congelasse o Verão.
[A sister who did not want to freeze the summer.]
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
Desculpa. A culpa foi minha.
[Excuse. It was my fault.]
Of course, none of it would have happened
Nada disto acontecia,
[None of this happened,]
if she had just told me her secret.
se ela me tivesse contado o seu segredo.
[if she had told me his secret.]
She's a stinker.
É má parva.
[It is bad silly.]
Whoa!
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
Não, não, não. Volta.
[No no no. Back.]
No, no, no!
Não, não!
[No no!]
Okay.
Muito bem.
[Very good.]
Snow. It had to be snow.
Gelo. Tinha que ser gelo.
[Ice. It had to be ice.]
She couldn't have had tropical magic
Não podia ter poderes tropicais,
[I could not have tropical powers,]
that covered the fjords in white sand and warm...
que cobrisse o Fiorde com uma reconfortante...
[covering the fjord with a soothing...]
Fire!
Fogo!
[Fire!]
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
Frio, frio, frio, frio!
[Cold, cold, cold, cold!]
"Wandering Oaken's Trading Post".
Loja de passagem do Oaken.
[Shop for passage of Oaken.]
Ooh. "And sauna"!
Ena, com sauna.
[Ena, with sauna.]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
O Verão chegou em força!
[Summer's here in force!]
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
Temos descontos nos fatos-de-banho, nas socas...
[We have discounted - facts - bath, the clogs...]
and a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
E os protectores solares são fabricados por nós, ya?
[And sunscreens are manufactured by us, will ya?]
Oh. Great. For now, um, how about boots?
Excelente. Por agora, que tal umas botas.
[Excellent. For now, how about some boots.]
Winter boots? And dresses?
Botas de Inverno, e vestidos?
[Winter boots and dresses?]
That would be in our winter department.
Isso estará na secção de Inverno.
[This section will be in winter.]
Oh. Um...
I was just wondering.
Pensava para mim,
[I thought to myself,]
Has another young woman...
se uma jovem,
[A young,]
The queen perhaps, I don't know,
uma Rainha talvez, não sei bem,
[one queen maybe, I do not know,]
passed through here?
passou por aqui?
[He came by?]
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm
A única maluca que anda na floresta com esta tempestade
[The only crazy walking in the woods with this storm]
is you, dear.
é a menina.
[is the girl.]
You and this fellow.
A menina e este...
[The girl and this...]
Hoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
O Verão chegou em força!
[Summer's here in force!]
Carrots.
Cenouras.
[Carrots.]
Huh?
Behind you.
Atrás de ti.
[Behind you.]
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Sim, claro. Desculpe.
[Yes of course. Excuse me.]
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
Uma estupidez no Verão, não acha?
[Stupid in the summer, right?]
Wherever could it be coming from?
De onde poderia vir?
[Where could come?]
The North Mountain.
Da Montanha do Norte.
[North Mountain.]
North Mountain.
Montanha do Norte...
[North Mountain...]
That will be forty.
Assim sendo, são quarenta.
[Thus, they are forty.]
Forty? No, ten.
Quarenta? Não, dez.
[Forty? There, mar.]
Oh, dear, that's no good.
Ai, chiça. Isso não é bom.
[Oh Sheesh. This is not good.]
See, this is from our winter stock,
Isto pertence à nossa Secção de Inverno,
[This belongs to our Winter Section,]
where supply and demand have a big problem.
onde a Lei da Oferta e da Procura, são um problema.
[where the Law of Supply and Demand, is a problem.]
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
Quer mesmo falar disso?
[You really want to talk about it?]
I sell ice for a living.
Vendo gelo para viver.
[Seeing ice to live.]
Ooh. That's a rough business to be in right now.
Nos tempos que correm, parece-me ser um negócio complicado.
[These days, it seems to me to be a tricky business.]
I mean, that is really...
Quero dizer, é o que...
[I mean, that's what...]
That's unfortunate.
Que infelicidade.
[That unhappiness.]
Still forty.
É quarenta à mesma.
[It is forty to it.]
But I will throw in a visit to Oaken's sauna.
Mas posso convidá-lo a visitar a Sauna do Oaken!
[But I invite you to visit the Sauna Oaken!]
Hoo-hoo. Hi, family.
Olá, família!
[Hello family!]
Hoo-hoo!
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
Só tenho dez.
[Just I got in December]
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
Com dez só dá para isto, nada mais.
[With ten only gives for it, nothing more.]
Okay, just tell me one thing.
Diga-me uma coisa,
[Tell me something,]
What was happening on the North Mountain?
o que aconteceu na Montanha do Norte?
[what happened in the North Mountain?]
Did it seem magical?
Parecia magia?
[It seemed magic?]
Yes!
Sim!
[Yup!]
Now, back up while I deal with this crook, here.
Agora, afasta-te, enquanto lido com este charlatão.
[Now, get away while I deal with this charlatan.]
What did you call me?
O que me chamou?
[What struck me?]
Okay, okay. I'm out.
Certo, certo. Já estou cá fora.
[Right, right. I'm already outside.]
Whoa!
Bye-bye.
Adeusinho.
[Bye.]
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
Não, Sven, não trouxe as tuas cenouras.
[No, Sven, did not bring your carrots.]
But I did find us a place to sleep.
Mas encontrei um lugar para dormirmos.
[But I found a place to we sleep.]
And it's free.
E é gratuito.
[And it's free.]
I'm sorry about this violence.
Lamento pela violência.
[I'm sorry violence.]
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
Vou adicionar um quarto de lutefisk,
[I will add a lutefisk room,]
so we have good feelings.
para que atrai energias positivas.
[for attracting positive energies.]
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
Será então só as botas e o fato, ya?
[It will then only boots and the fact ya?]
Uh...
Reindeers are better than people
As renas são melhores que as pessoas
[The reindeer are better than people]
Sven, don't you think that's true?
Sven, não concordas comigo?
[Sven did not agree with me?]
"Yeah, people will beat you and curse you and cheat you"
"Porque as pessoas, vão-te bater, enganar, amaldiçoar"
["Because people, will you beat, cheat, curse"]
"Every one of them's bad, except you!"
"São todos mau, excepto tu."
[" They're all bad, except you."]
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
Obrigado, rapaz.
[Thank you, young man.]
But people smell better than reindeers
Mas as pessoas cheiram melhor que as renas
[But people smell better than the reindeer]
Sven, don't you think I'm right?
Sven, não achas que estou certo?
[Sven, do not you think I'm right?]
"That's once again true, for all except you!"
"Estás novamente certo, todos, excepto tu"
["You are right again, everyone, except you"]
You got me! Let's call it a night.
Apanhaste-me! Vamos encerrar a noite.
[You got me! Let's call it a night.]
"Good night"
"Boa noite."
["Good night."]
Don't let the frostbite
Não deixes que o gelo
[Do not let the ice]
Bite
Morda.
[Bite.]
Nice duet.
Foi um bom dueto.
[It was a good duet.]
It's just you. What do you want?
Que queres?
[What do you want?]
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
Quero que me leves à Montanha do Norte.
[I want you to take me to the North Mountain.]
I don't take people places.
Não levo pessoas a lugares.
[I do not take people to places.]
Let me rephrase that.
Deixa-me reformular.
[Let me rephrase.]
Hey.
Take me up the North Mountain.
Leva-me à Montanha do Norte.
[It brings me to the North Mountain.]
Please.
Por favor.
[Please.]
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
Ouve, sei como parar este Inverno.
[Look, I know how to stop this winter.]
We leave at dawn.
Partimos ao amanhecer,
[We set off at dawn,]
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
e esqueceste-te das cenouras do Sven.
[and forgot Carrots Sven.]
Oops, sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
Desculpa, desculpa. Não queria...
[Sorry Sorry. I did not want...]
We leave now. Right now.
Partimos agora. Já.
[We start now. Already.]
Whew!
Hang on! We like to go fast.
Agarra-te bem. Gostamos de velocidade.
[Grab yourself well. Like speed.]
I like fast. - Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Eu gosto da velocidade.
[I like the speed.]
Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
Pés para baixos. Acabei de o envernizar.
[Feet low. Just the varnish.]
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
Sinceramente, cresceste numa quinta?
[Honestly, grew up on a farm?]
Ugh!
No, I was raised in a castle.
Não, cresci num castelo.
[No, I grew up in a castle.]
So, uh, tell me,
Conta-me, porque razão
[Tell me, why]
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
a Rainha congelou tudo?
[Queen froze all?]
Oh. Well...
It was all my fault.
A culpa foi minha.
[It was my fault.]
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
Fiquei noiva, mas o problema foi
[I got engaged, but the problem was]
because I'd only just met him you know, that day.
porque o tinha acabado... de o conhecer.
[because had just... to know him.]
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage, and...
E ela não me quis dar a sua bênção...
[And she would not give me his blessing...]
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
Espera. Ficaste noiva de um tipo que acabaste de conhecer?
[Wait. You were engaged to a guy who just met?]
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
Sim. Adiante, enervei-me, ela enervou-se,
[Yes. Go ahead, I enervei me, it unnerved,]
and then she tried to walk away, and I grabbed her glove...
depois ela tentou sair, então eu puxei-lhe a luva.
[after she tried to leave, so I pulled her glove.]
Hang on!
Espera lá.
[Wait.]
You mean to tell me you got engaged
Acabaste de me dizer que ficaste noiva
[Just tell me that you stayed bride]
to someone you just met that day?
de um tipo que tinhas conhecido há horas?!
[of a kind you had known for hours?!]
Yes. Pay attention.
Sim, mas presta atenção.
[Yes, but watch.]
But the thing is, she wore the gloves all the time,
O problema foi, ela usava sempre luvas,
[The problem was, she always wore gloves,]
so I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
e eu pensei: "Talvez não goste de pó."
[and I thought, "Maybe not like dust."]
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
Os teus pais nunca te avisaram para não falares com estranhos?
[Your parents never warned you not to talk to strangers?]
Yyyyyes, they did.
Sim, disseram.
[Yes, they said.]
But Hans is not a stranger.
Mas o Hans não é um estranho.
[But Hans is not a stranger.]
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
Ai não? Qual é o seu último nome?
[Is not? What's your last name?]
"Of the Southern Isles."
"Das Ilhas do Sul."
["Of the South Islands."]
What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
Qual é o seu prato favorito? - Sanduíches.
[What is your favorite dish? - Sandwiches.]
Best friend's name? - Probably John.
Qual é o nome do seu melhor amigo? - John, provavelmente.
[What is the name of your best friend? - John, probably.]
Eye color? - Dreamy.
Cor dos olhos? - De morrer.
[Eye color? - To die for.]
Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
Número que calça? - Isso não interessa.
[Number pants? - It does not matter.]
Have you had a meal with him yet? What if you hate the way he eats?
Já comeram alguma refeição juntos? E se não gostares da forma de comer dele?
[Have you eaten a meal together? And if you do not like the way we eat it?]
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
E se não gostares da forma que ele tira macacos?
[And if you do not like the way he takes monkeys?]
Picks his nose?
Tirar macacos?
[Take monkeys?]
And eats it.
E come-los.
[And eat them.]
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
Desculpe, Senhor. Mas ele é um Príncipe.
[Sorry Sir. But he's a prince.]
All men do it.
Todos os homens fazem isso.
[All men do.]
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
Nada mais importa, se for amor verdadeiro.
[Nothing else matters if it is true love.]
It doesn't sound like true love.
Não me parece que seja o caso.
[I do not think is the case.]
Are you some sort of love expert?
E tu és algum experiente no assunto?
[And you're experienced in any subject?]
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
Não. Mas tenho amigos que são.
[No. But I have friends who are.]
You have friends
Tens amigos
[Do you have friends]
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
que percebem de amor verdadeiro? Não acredito.
[who realize the true love? I can not believe.]
Stop talking. - No, no, no. No, no.
Pára de falar. - Não, não, não.
[Stop talking. - No no no.]
I'd like to meet these... - No, I mean it.
Gostava de conhecer esses... - Não, estou a falar a sério.
[I liked to know these... - No, I'm serious.]
Sven, go.
Sven, vai.
[Sven will.]
Go!
Vai!
[Go!]
What are they? - Wolves.
O que é? - Lobos.
[What is it? - Lobos.]
Wolves?
Lobos?
[Wolves?]
What do we do? - I got this.
E agora? - Eu trato disto.
[And now? - I got this.]
You just... Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
Tu... não caias e não deixes que te comam.
[You... do not fall and do not let them eat you.]
But I want to help!
Mas quero ajudar.
[But I want to help.]
No. - Why not?
Não. - Porque não?
[No. - Why not?]
Because I don't trust your judgment.
Porque não confio em ti.
[Why not trust you.]
Excuse me?
Desculpa?
[Excuse?]
Who marries a man she just met?
Quem se casa com uma pessoa que se acabou de conhecer?
[Who marries a person who just met?]
It's true love!
É amor verdadeiro!
[It is true love!]
Whoa!
Whoa. Whoa!
Christopher!
It's "Kristoff"!
É Kristoff!
[Is Kristoff!]
Ow!
Duck!
Abaixa-te!
[Bow down!]
You almost set me on fire!
Quase que me incendiados!
[Almost burned me!]
But I didn't.
Mas não o fiz.
[But I did not.]
Get ready to jump, Sven!
Prepara-te para saltar, Sven!
[Get ready to jump, Sven!]
You don't tell him what to do.
Não lhe digas o que fazer.
[Do not tell him what to do.]
I do!
Eu é que digo.
[I is what I say.]
Jump, Sven!
Salto, Sven!
[Heels, Sven!]
Phew!
But I just paid it off.
Tinha acabado de o pagar.
[I had just the pay.]
Uh-oh. No. No.
No!
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Não, não, não!
[No no no!]
Grab on!
Agarra!
[Grabs!]
Pull, Sven. Pull!
Puxe, Sven! Puxe!
[Pull, Sven! Pull!]
Whoa.
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
Eu ofereço-te um trenó novo, igual ao que tinhas.
[I offer you a new sled, like the one you had.]
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
Caso não me queiras ajudar mais, vou compreender perfeitamente.
[If you do not wanna help me more, I understand perfectly.]
Of course I don't want to help her anymore. In fact,
Claro que não a quero ajudar mais. Aliás,
[Of course not want to help more. incidentally,]
this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
depois do que se passou, dificilmente volto a ajudar alguém.
[after what happened, hardly back to help someone.]
It's this way?
"She'll die on her own."
"Se não a ajudares, ela morre."
["If not you help, she dies."]
I can live with that. - Here we go.
Posso viver com isso.
[I can live with that.]
"But you won't get your new sled if she's dead."
"Mas se ela morrer não receberás um novo trenó."
["But if she dies you will not receive a new sled."]
I think, actually, it's up.
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
Por vezes odeio-te.
[Sometimes I hate you.]
Hold up! We're coming.
Espera! Estamos a ir.
[Wait! We are going.]
You are?
A sério?
[Seriously?]
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
Quero dizer, claro. Deixo-te que venhas comigo.
[I mean, sure. I leave you to come with me.]
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
Está completamente congelada.
[It is completely frozen.]
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
Mas vai ficar tudo bem. A Elsa vai corrigir tudo.
[But it will be all right. Elsa will fix everything.]
Will she?
Vai?
[Go?]
Yeah. Now, come on.
Sim. Agora, anda.
[Yes. Now, come on.]
This way to the North Mountain?
É este o caminho para a Montanha do Norte?
[Is this the way to North Mountain?]
More like this way.
É mais por ali.
[It's there.]
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
Nunca pensei que o Inverno fosse tão lindo.
[I never thought that winter was so beautiful.]
Yeah.
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
But it's so white.
You know, how about a little color?
I'm thinking maybe some crimson, chartreuse.
How about yellow?
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
No go.
Am I right?
You're creepy.
I don't want it.
Back at you. - Please don't drop me.
Come on, it's just a head.
All right. We got off to a bad start.
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
All right, wait one second.
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Now, I'm perfect.
Well, almost.
It was like my whole life got turned upside down.
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
Head rush! - I was just... Are you okay?
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
I've always wanted a nose.
So cute.
It's like a little baby unicorn.
But... Hey! Whoa!
Oh.
I love it even more.
All right, let's start this thing over.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Olaf.
And I like warm hugs.
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
And you are?
Oh. Um...
I'm Anna.
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
That's Sven.
And who's the reindeer?
Sven.
Oh, they're... Oh. Okay. That makes things easier for me.
Aw, look at him trying to kiss my nose.
I like you, too.
Olaf. Did Elsa build you? - Yeah. Why?
Do you know where she is? - Yeah. Why?
Fascinating.
Do you think you could show us the way? - Yeah. Why?
How does this work? Ow!
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus, here.
Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
Summer?
Oh. I don't know why,
but I've always loved the idea of summer
and sun, and all things hot.
Really?
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
Nope.
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
and imagine what it would be like when summer does come.
Bees will buzz, kids will blow dandelion fuzz
And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer
A drink in my hand
My snow up against the burning sand
Probably getting gorgeously tanned
In summer.
I'll finally see a summer breeze
Blow away a winter storm
And find out what happens to solid water
When it gets warm
And I can't wait to see
What my buddies all think of me
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be
In summer!
The hot and the cold are both so intense
Put them together It just makes sense
Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle
But put me in summer and I'll be a...
(puddle?)
Happy snowman!
When life gets rough
I like to hold on to my dream
Of relaxing in the summer sun, just letting off steam
Oh, the sky will be blue
And you guys will be there, too
When I finally do
What frozen things do in summer!
I'm gonna tell him.
Don't you dare.
In summer!
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Let's go bring back summer!
I'm coming!
Somebody's gotta tell him.
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
The bark needs to be face-up.
Bark down is drier. - Bark up!
Bark down! - Papa!
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
The castle is open.
There is soup and hot gløgg in the Great Hall.
Here, pass these out.
Prince Hans!
Are we expected to just sit here and freeze
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
Princess Anna has given her orders.
And that's another thing!
Has it dawned on you that your princess may be conspiring
with a wicked sorceress
to destroy us all?
Do not question the princess.
She left me in charge
and I will not hesitate
to protect Arendelle from treason.
Treason?
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Easy.
It's Princess Anna's horse.
So, where is the princess?
Where could she be? - Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
I need volunteers to go with me to find her.
I'll go. I volunteer.
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Be prepared for anything.
And should you encounter the queen,
you are to put an end to this winter.
Do you understand?
So, how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
That's your plan?
My ice business is riding on you talking to your sister?
Yep.
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
Why would I be?
Yeah. I bet she's the nicest, gentlest, warmest person ever.
Oh. Look at that.
I've been impaled.
What now?
Mmm...
It's too steep.
I've only got one rope and you don't know how to climb mountains.
Says who?
Hmm?
What are you doing?
I'm going to see my sister.
You're gonna kill yourself.
I wouldn't put my foot there.
You're distracting me. - Or there.
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
All right. I'm just blocking you out
because I gotta concentrate, here.
You know, most people who disappear
into the mountains want to be alone.
Nobody wants to be alone.
Except maybe you.
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
You mean, the love experts?
Yes, the love experts.
Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
Hang on.
Hey, Sven?
Not sure if this is gonna solve the problem,
but I found a staircase that leads exactly
where you wanted to go.
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
Thanks. That was like a crazy trust exercise.
Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
I might cry.
Go ahead. I won't judge.
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
I got you.
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
Flawless.
Knock.
Just knock.
Why isn't she knocking?
Do you think she knows how to knock?
Huh. It opened.
That's a first.
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
What? - The last time I introduced her to a guy,
she froze everything.
But, but... Oh, come on!
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
Bye, Sven.
You, too, Olaf.
Me? - Just give us a minute.
Okay.
One, two, three...
Four...
Whoa.
Elsa?
It's me, Anna.
Anna.
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
It's a good different.
And this place...
It's amazing.
Thank you.
I never knew what I was capable of.
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd have known...
No, no, no. It's okay.
You don't have to apologize, but you should probably go.
Please.
But I just got here.
You belong down in Arendelle.
So do you.
No, Anna, I belong here.
Alone.
Where I can be who I am without hurting anybody.
Actually, about that...
Sixty! - Wait. What is that?
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
Olaf?
You built me.
Remember that?
And you're alive?
Um... I think so.
He's just like the one we built as kids.
Yeah.
Elsa, we were so close.
We can be like that again.
Catch me! Slow down!
Anna!
No.
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
Elsa, wait.
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
Please don't shut me out again.
Please don't slam the door
You don't have to keep your distance anymore
'Cause for the first time in forever
I finally understand
For the first time in forever
We can fix this hand in hand
We can head down this mountain together.
You don't have to live in fear
'Cause for the first time in forever
I will be right here
Anna.
Please go back home
Your life awaits
Go enjoy the sun, and open up the gates
Yeah, but...
I know.
You mean well, but leave me be
Yes, I'm alone
But I'm alone and free
Just stay away and you'll be safe from me
Actually, we're not
What do you mean, you're not?
I get the feeling you don't know
What do I not know?
Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep
deep snow
What?
You kind of set off an eternal winter everywhere.
Everywhere?
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
No, I can't. I don't know how.
Sure you can. I know you can.
'Cause for the first time in forever
Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free!
You don't have to be afraid
No escape from the storm inside of me
We can work this out together
I can't control the curse!
We'll reverse the storm you've made
Anna, please you'll only make it worse!
Don't panic!
There's so much fear!
We'll make the sun shine bright
You're not safe here!
We can face this thing together
No!
We can change this winter weather
And everything will be all right
I can't!
Anna!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'm fine.
Who's this?
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
You have to go.
No, I know we can figure this out together.
How?
What power do you have to stop this winter?
To stop me?
Anna, I think we should go.
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Yes, you are.
Stop! Put us down!
Go away.
Heads up!
Watch out for my butt!
It is not nice to throw people!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants. Okay, relax.
Just calm down! Calm down! - Okay! All right!
I'm okay. - Just let the snowman be.
I'm calm.
Oh! Come on!
Oh. Look, see? Now you made him mad.
I'll distract him. You guys go.
No, no! Not you guys!
This just got a whole lot harder.
Look out!
What are you doing?
I got him!
Whoa! Stop!
It's a hundred-foot drop.
It's two hundred.
Ow!
What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
Okay. What if we fall?
There's 20 feet of fresh powder down there.
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
Hopefully.
Okay, Anna. On three.
One...
Okay. You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
Two... - I was born ready! Yes!
Calm down.
Tree!
What the... Whoa!
That happened.
Man, am I out of shape.
There we go. Hey, Anna!
Sven! Where did you guys go?
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
Hey! We were just talking about you.
All good things, all good things.
No!
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
Olaf!
Hang in there, guys!
Go. Go faster!
Wait, what?
Ow!
Kristoff!
Don't come back!
We won't.
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
Olaf!
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
Those are my legs.
Oooh. Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
Oh. That feels better.
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Who's my cute little reindeer?
Don't talk to him like that.
You're tickling me.
Here.
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Thank you.
How's your head? - Ah! Ooh!
It's fine. Uh...
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
I don't have a skull.
Or bones.
So, uh... So, now what?
Now what?
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
She threw me out.
I can't go back to Arendelle with the weather like this.
And then there's your ice business.
Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
Worry about your hair!
What? I just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
No, yours is turning white.
White? It's... What?
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
Does it look bad?
No. - You hesitated.
No, I didn't.
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
Okay! Where are we going?
To see my friends.
The love experts?
Love experts?
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
How do you know?
Because I've seen them do it before.
I like to consider myself a love expert.
Get it together.
Control it.
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Don't feel.
Don't feel!
Look, Sven, the sky's awake.
Are you cold? - A little.
Uh... Wait. Come here.
Huh?
Ooh.
So, uh, about my friends. Well...
I say "friends"...
They're more like family.
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven.
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
They did?
Yeah. I don't want to scare you.
They can be a little inappropriate and loud.
Very loud.
They are also stubborn at times,
and a little overbearing.
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
But you'll get it. They mean well.
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Okay, then.
Meet my family.
Hey, guys.
They're rocks.
You are a sight for sore eyes.
He's crazy. - Hey look, ???'s back from vacation!
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Clay, whoa... I don't even recognize you.
You lost so much weight.
I'll distract him while you run.
Hi, Sven's family!
It's nice to meet you.
Because I love you, Anna, I insist you run.
I understand you're love experts. Ooh!
Why aren't you running?
Uh...
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
No, no, no. Anna, wait.
Kristoff!
Whoa!
Hey!
Kristoff's home!
Kristoff's here! Kristoff's home!
Wait, "Kristoff"?
Ah, let me look at you.
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
Look, it's great to see you all,
but where's Granpabbie?
He's napping.
But look, I grew a mushroom.
I earned my fire crystal.
I passed a kidney stone.
Kristoff, pick me up.
You're getting big.
Good for you.
Trolls. They're trolls!
He's brought a girl!
A girl!
Is that a real girl?
She's like a little cupcake.
What's going on?
I've learned to just roll with it.
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
strong teeth!
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
You've got the wrong idea.
No. That's not why I brought her here.
Right. We're not... I'm not...
What's the issue, dear?
Why are you holding back from such a man?
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
What? - Or the grumpy way he talks?
Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
Weirdness of his feet?
Hey!
And though we know he washes well
He always ends up sort of smelly
But you'll never meet a fella
Who's as sensitive and sweet
That's nice, but...
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
So, he's got a few flaws
Like his peculiar brain, dear
His thing with the reindeer
That's a little outside of nature's laws
This is not about me!
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
But this we're certain of
You can fix this fixer-upper up
With a little bit of love
Can we please just stop talking about this?
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Is it the way that he runs scared?
Or that he's socially impaired?
Or that he only likes to tinkle in the woods?
I did not need to know that.
Are you holding back your fondness
Due to his unmanly blondness?
Or the way he covers up that he's the honest goods?
He's just a bit of a fixer-upper
He's got a couple of bugs
(No, I don't!) - His isolation is confirmation
Of his desperation for healing hugs
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
But we know what to do
The way to fix up this fixer-upper
Is to fix him up with you
Whoa!
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
That's a minor thing
Her quote "engagement" is a flex arrangement
And by the way, I don't see no ring
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
Her brain's a bit betwixt
Get the fiance out of the way
And the whole thing will be fixed
We're not saying you can change him
'Cause people don't really change
We're only saying that love's a force
That's powerful and strange
People make bad choices
If they're mad or scared or stressed
But throw a little love their way
Throw a little love their way
And you'll bring out their best
True love brings out the best
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
That's what it's all about
Father! Sister! Brother!
We need each other to raise us up
And round us out
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
But when push comes to shove
The only fixer-upper fixer
That can fix a fixer-upper is...
True, true
True
Love!
Love, love, love
Love! True love
True
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
Wait, what? - You're getting married.
Love!
Anna?
She's as cold as ice.
There is strange magic here.
Granpabbie. - Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Anna, your life is in danger.
There is ice in your heart put there by your sister.
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
What? No.
But you can remove it, right?
I cannot
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
If it was her head, that would be easy.
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
An act of true love?
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
(Something's wrong. Are you all right?)
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Hans.
Pull us out, Sven.
Olaf, come on!
I'm coming!
Let's go kiss Hans!
Who is this Hans?
We are here to find Princess Anna.
Be on guard, but no harm is to come to the queen.
Do you understand?
Yes, Your Grace.
The queen.
Go, go! Come on!
There!
Up there!
Come on!
We got her.
No. Please.
Go around. Toss it.
Stay away!
Look out!
Fire! Fire!
Get her!
Ah!
Come on!
Grab his arm.
Aim...
This way, this way!
Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
Oh, no. What have... What have I done?
Why did you bring me here?
I couldn't just let them kill you.
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
Anna has not returned.
If you would just stop the winter.
Bring back summer, please.
Don't you see?
I can't.
You have to tell them to let me go.
I will do what I can.
Just hang in there.
Come on, buddy, faster!
Oh, boy!
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
I will!
Hello! - It's alive!
It's Princess Anna!
Are you gonna be okay?
Don't worry about me.
Anna!
You had us worried sick. My Lady.
Get her warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.
We will. Thank you.
Make sure she's safe.
Oh, you poor girl, you're freezing.
Oh, let's get you inside now and get you warm.
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
You cannot risk going out there again.
If anything happens to her...
If anything happens to the princess,
you are all Arendelle has left.
He's in here.
Prince Hans.
Anna.
You're so cold.
Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
Now! Now! - Slow down.
We'll give you two some privacy.
What happened out there?
Elsa struck me with her powers.
You said she'd never hurt you.
I was wrong.
Anna.
She froze my heart,
and only an act of true love can save me.
A true love's kiss.
Oh, Anna.
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
What?
You said you did.
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
I didn't stand a chance.
I knew I would have to marry into the throne somewhere.
What... What are you talking about?
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
But you...
You were so desperate for love,
you were willing to marry me just like that.
I figured after we married,
I would have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
Hans! No. Stop.
But then, she doomed herself,
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
Please.
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
and bring back summer.
You're no match for Elsa.
No, you're no match for Elsa.
I, on the other hand,
am the hero who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
You won't get away with this.
Oh...
I already have.
Please, somebody, help.
Please. Please.
It's getting colder by the minute.
If we don't do something soon, we'll all freeze to death.
Prince Hans.
Princess Anna is...
Dead.
What?
What happened to her?
She was killed...
... by Queen Elsa.
No!
Her own sister.
At least we got to say our marriage vows
before she died in my arms.
There can be no doubt now.
Queen Elsa is a monster,
and we are all in grave danger.
Prince Hans,
Arendelle looks to you.
With a heavy heart,
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason.
And sentence her to death.
Hurry up!
She's dangerous.
Move quickly. Careful!
It won't open! It's frozen shut.
Put your back into it!
Come on! Push!
What is it, buddy?
Hey, watch it.
What's wrong with you?
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
Stop it! Put me down!
No, Sven!
We're not going back.
She's with her true love.
What the...
Anna!
Come on! Come on, boy.
Help.
Anna!
Oh, no.
Olaf?
Olaf. Get away from there.
Wow!
So, this is heat.
I love it.
Ooh! But don't touch it.
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
But we ran all the way here.
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here. You'll melt.
I am not leaving here until
we find some other act of true love to save you.
Do you happen to have any ideas?
I don't even know what love is.
That's okay, I do.
Love is
putting someone else's needs before yours.
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans and left you forever.
Kristoff loves me?
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
Olaf, you're melting.
Some people are worth melting for.
Just maybe not right this second.
Don't worry, I've got it.
We're gonna get through... Oh, wait.
Hang on, I'm getting something.
It's Kristoff and Sven!
They're coming back this way.
They... They are?
Wow! He's really moving fast.
I guess I was wrong.
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
No, no, no! You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
I need to get to Kristoff.
Why?
Oh, I know why!
There's your act of true love right there!
Riding across the fjords like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
Come on!
Look out!
Oh!
Uh... Back this way.
We're trapped.
Oh...
Whoa!
Slide, Anna!
We made it!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, buddy, faster.
Kristoff!
Keep going!
Come on!
No.
Whoa!
Sven!
Good boy.
Kristoff.
Kristoff...
Anna!
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Just take care of my sister.
Your sister?
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
She said that you froze her heart.
No.
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
Your sister is dead.
Because of you.
No.
Kristoff.
Anna!
Elsa?
No!
Anna!
Oh. Anna!
No, no!
Please, no.
Anna?
Oh, Elsa.
You sacrificed yourself for me?
I love you.
"An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart."
"Love will thaw."
Love. Of course.
Elsa?
Love!
I knew you could do it.
Hands down, this is the best day of my life.
And, quite possibly, the last.
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Oh, Oh, Oh!
My own personal flurry!
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
But she froze your heart.
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
Wonderful!
Setting course, sir.
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
We shall see what his twelve big brothers think of his behavior.
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
This is unacceptable.
I am a victim of fear. I've been traumatized.
Ah! My neck hurts.
Is there a doctor that I could see?
And I demand to see the queen!
Oh. I have a message from the queen.
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever
"no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown."
"Weselton."
It's Weselton!
Come on, come on, come on!
Okay, okay, here I come.
Pole! - Whoops! Sorry.
Okay, Okay.
Here we are. Oh!
I owe you a sled.
Are you serious? - Yes!
And it's the latest model.
No, I can't accept this.
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
She's named you the Official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
What? That's not a thing. - Oh, sure it is.
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
Like it? I love it!
Whoa.
I could kiss you!
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd...
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
Wait, what?
We may.
Summer!
Ooh...
Hello.
Are you ready?
Ice!
Swing me.
Ooh...
I like the open gates.
We are never closing them again.
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful, but you know I don't skate.
Come on! You can do it!
Look out. Reindeer coming through.
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
Hey, guys!
That's it, Olaf.
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.